<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version='2.0'>
<channel>
<generator>
clj-rss
</generator>
<link>
https://news.ycombinator.com
</link>
<title>
myread
</title>
<description>
myread
</description>
<item>
<link>
http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/index.php
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;section id=&quot;content&quot;&gt;



		


&lt;p id=&quot;date&quot;&gt;Jan 22th, 2014&lt;/p&gt;

			
&lt;p id=&quot;paperbox&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/index.php&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;shadowed&quot; src=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/icon_plane.png&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;I love you Hoi-En.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/index.php&quot;&gt;    
&lt;/a&gt; 
    
    

Back in the early 90s, one company was on the bleeding edge of PC gaming: 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Origin_Systems&quot;&gt;Origin Systems&lt;/a&gt;.
Their motto was &quot;We Create Worlds&quot; and boy did they deliver: With the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ultima_(series)&quot;&gt;Ultima&lt;/a&gt; series, Crusader series and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wing_Commander_(franchise)&quot;&gt;Wing Commander&lt;/a&gt; series, they consistently took gamer's breath away.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
One of them took four years and more than a million man hours to complete: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strike_Commander&quot;&gt;
Strike Commander&lt;/a&gt;. The famous flight simulator
had its own 3D engine called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wcnews.com/wcpedia/RealSpace&quot;&gt;RealSpace&lt;/a&gt; which pioneered many of what we take 
for granted today: Texture Mapping, Gouraud Shading, Level of Details and Dithered colors.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

My old dream was to play the game with a Virtual Reality device. With 
the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oculusvr.com/&quot;&gt;Oculus Rift&lt;/a&gt; that fantasy came one step closer to reality.
But when it turned out the source code had been lost and would never be released, I decided to reverse engineer it.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
As of the publication of this article, the project is not yet completed  but I want to share the techniques that have so far allowed this :&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;shadowed&quot; src=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/sc_before.png&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
to become that :&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;shadowed&quot; src=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/sc_after.png&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
... and maybe inspire some people to join the adventure.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;b&gt;TABLE OF CONTENT :&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/index.php&quot;&gt;Part 1:  Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/strike_commander_architecture.php&quot;&gt;Part 2: Game Architecture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/strike_commander_assets.php&quot;&gt;Part 3: Reverse Engineer Assets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/strike_commander_game.php&quot;&gt;Part 4: Play the game again&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/strike_commander_oculus_rift.php&quot;&gt;Part 5: Oculus Rift&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Before Strike Commander
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Early 90s flight simulators were good but like &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Falcon_(video_game_series)#Falcon_3.0&quot;&gt;Falcon 3.0&lt;/a&gt; 
  or &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_Microsoft_Flight_Simulator#Flight_Simulator_4.0&quot;&gt;Flight simulator 4.0&lt;/a&gt; they focused mostly on accurate flying models than beautiful rendition :&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;shadowed&quot; src=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/falcon3_small.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;shadowed&quot; src=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/flight_simulator_4_small.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
 There were many fight simulator on the market and few people noticed the 1990 Origin Systems announcement for a new game. But things
 changed after Chicago CES 1991 where a demo could be seen in action : 
  Nobody could believe the game could feature things only seen in military flight simulator so far: Texture Mapping, Gouraud Shading, Haze and more. 
  Screenshots demonstrated a technology far ahead any competitors :&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;shadowed&quot; src=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/sick_game_small.png&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;shadowed&quot; src=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/sick_game_cockpit_small.png&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;shadowed&quot; src=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/sc_story_small.png&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;shadowed&quot; src=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/sc_story2_small.png&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  After 1991 the game became highly anticipated. Not only the engine was gorgeous and the story captivating, RealSpace also supported exceptional hardware out of the box: The very expensive 
  and fragile accessories that every flight simulator 
  enthusiast wanted were the THRUSTMASTER WEAPON CONTROL SYSTEM and the THRUSTMASTER FLIGHT CONTROL SYSTEM:&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/tm_TQS-web.jpg&quot; class=&quot;shadowed&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/tm_FCS-web.jpg&quot; class=&quot;shadowed&quot;&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  And you could even connect the THRUSTMASTER RUDDER:&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/tm_rcs-web.jpg&quot; class=&quot;shadowed&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  Still, there was more: The game also supported a Virtual Cockpit. The
  4-way 'hat switch' on the ThrustMaster allowing to move the pilot's head and follow ground objects/enemy jets without the need for a Virtual Reality HeadSet :&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/sick_game_v_cockpit_small.png&quot; class=&quot;shadowed&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/sick_game_v_cockpit2_small.png&quot; class=&quot;shadowed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;1993: First Contact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The game and its 3D engine were mind blowing but required an impossibly powerful machine :
  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;IBM PC 486-DX2 66Mhz&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;4MB RAM&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;38MB mandatory installation&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Game comes on 11 x 1.44MB floppy disks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Adjusted to today technological inflation the recommended configuration would be : 
  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;8 Cores CPU with 16 GB of RAM.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Dual Nvidia Titan GPUs.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mandatory install of 1000 GB.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Game comes on five BluRays.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
  And purchasing the game was not enough, you also had to survive the installation ! Upon opening the box you would be faced with 8 floppy disks (
  +3 for the Speech Pack):&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;shadowed&quot; src=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/Strike-Poster_small.png&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;shadowed&quot; src=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/sc_disks_small.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &lt;u&gt;&lt;b&gt;Trivia :&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/u&gt; Notice the poster announcing a Christmas 1991 release. The game would not be completed until 1993 after a long process that Chris Robert labeled &quot;The Apocalypse Now of computer games&quot;.&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
   Decompressing the game from floppies to hard-drive and swapping the 13 flopping disk took a good 30 minutes. And when you thought you were done,
   the game proceeded to generate all the maps. The size of the game would blow up from 24MB to 38MB: Four times the size of any game back them.&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/sc_mapgenerator.png&quot; class=&quot;shadowed&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;u&gt;&lt;b&gt;Trivia :&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/u&gt; A map was generated from a single &quot;seed&quot; (an integer number) that was injected in a pseudo-random numbers generation algorithm.
  This was a clever technique that avoided shipping data by generating the map after installation. If you are curious about this technique, go read &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/The-Backroom-Boys-Secret-British/dp/0571214975&quot;&gt;The Backroom Boys&lt;/a&gt; and the chapter about Frontier Elite game.&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
   The maps generation step took ONE hour on a 386 PC. But Origin Systems had the good idea to ship with &lt;a href=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/docs/sudden_death.JPG&quot;&gt;the box&lt;/a&gt; a superb 100 pages magazine set in the dystopian 2012 world of the game. &lt;a href=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/docs/StrikeCommanderManual.pdf&quot;&gt;Sudden Death&lt;/a&gt;  made the entire process less painful ( notice the fake advertisement on page 38 promising the release of Strike Commander for Christmas 2013).
        
   &lt;br&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;h2&gt;Strike Commander !&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Finally after all those steps, players were able to enjoy the game....in April 1993 ! Despite being 2 years late, the game was everything Origin promised and it sold very well. Many spent nights after nights dogfighting even if for most what was supposed to look like this :&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
   &lt;img src=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/sc_ingame.png&quot; class=&quot;shadowed&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
   &lt;br&gt;
   ...ended up looking like that on minimum settings :&lt;br&gt;
   &lt;br&gt;
   &lt;img src=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/sc_ingame_low.png&quot; class=&quot;shadowed&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
   Overall the game was enough to captivate pilots and generate fond memories.
&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h2&gt;The Lost Source Code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  With the Oculus Rift release, my interest in Strike Commander peaked again: The hardware was ready. Since
  it was a 20 years old game, I expected the source code to have been released but I quickly found out the sad story of Origin Systems 
  decline.&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  Origin Systems was acquired by Electronic Arts in September 1992 and all projects were canceled circa 1999 following poor sales of
  Ultima 9. The company was to refocus on an other field they pioneered: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ultima_Online&quot;&gt;MMORPG Ultima Online&lt;/a&gt;.
  Most people assume the source codes and gold versions of all finished games were stored in a Vault somewhere at EA. 
  But after getting in touch with people at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wcnews.com/chatzone/threads/wing-commander-source-code.24840/&quot;&gt;Wing Commander CIC&lt;/a&gt;, 
  it appeared that all the source code was lost when the company closed.&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  It is something hard to believe today but back then developers and companies were more focused on the next title
  instead of preserving &quot;old things&quot;, there was not nostalgia factor, no huge fan base and no market like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gog.com/&quot;&gt;Good Old Games&lt;/a&gt; today. Many stories could illustrate how &quot;primitive&quot; source control was but the best 
  is probably the &quot;ZAP SC&quot; story at 15m14s :&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
     &lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/K8gj2YyB0Hg#start=922&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  On his first day one developer managed to delete the full 900MB of Strike Commander source tree. The IT team spent 72 hours recovering everything from developers machines. The interview also mention that Wing Commander 1 and 2 code was exchanged via floppy disks: They did not have a network until SC !
  &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;u&gt;&lt;b&gt;Trivia :&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/u&gt; In a surprising turn of event, some of the source code re-emerged recently via ex-Origin developers: Wing Commander CIC 
  maintains an off-line archive which features the source codes of &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.wcnews.com/newestshots/full/squadronsourcecode.png&quot;&gt;Wing Commander I&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.wcnews.com/newestshots/full/wc3sourcecode.PNG&quot;&gt;Wing Commander  III&lt;/a&gt; and people working on Ultima 8 were offered (but turned down) 
  the source code of &quot;Ultima 8: Pagan&quot; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://exult.sourceforge.net/forum/read.php?f=1&amp;amp;i=13863&amp;amp;t=13863&quot;&gt;an anonymous source&lt;/a&gt;. As for Strike Commander, I have never heard of someone having it.



&lt;h2&gt;Reverse Engineering: Can it be done ?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Over the years many teams had done work on Origin Systems game and reached great results:
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   How long and how hard would it be ? After chatting with Gregory Montoir who did most of the reverse engineer on &lt;a href=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/anotherWorld_code_review/index.php&quot;&gt;Another World&lt;/a&gt;
  I learned that working one hour per evening allowed to reverse 10KB of assembly to C each month. There are many executable in Strike Commander and the initial discouraging time estimate was :&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;long&quot;&gt;


  INSTALL.EXE       7,793 bytes :  2 weeks
  MKTERR.EXE      203,744 bytes :  1.5 years
  SC.EXE           20,000 bytes :  1 month
  MKGAME.EXE      131,696 bytes :  1 year
  OPTTEST.EXE     870,528 bytes :  7 years
  STRIKE.EXE      746,304 bytes :  6 years
  =============================================

                                  15 years, 7 months and 2 weeks. Ouch.

&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  That was upsetting: If someone had started back in 1993 then he would have finished six years ago and I would just have had to &lt;code&gt;git clone &lt;/code&gt; it :( ! But after starting up &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hex-rays.com/index.shtml&quot;&gt;IDA&lt;/a&gt; and taking a quick look
  it turned out that not all of it would have to be reverse engineered: The 3D engine is fully contained within STRIKE.EXE and a small team 
  could do it in a reasonable amount of time.

  &lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Road Map&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The road-map I initially drew in order to reverse engineer Strike Commander was as follow :
  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;Gather as much documentation as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;Understand the Global Architecture of Strike Commander.&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;Reverse-Engineer the Game Assets.&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;Document step 3 and extrapolate (Visual Surface Determination method, Level Of Detail, ...)&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;Re-implement the 3D engine and build &lt;code&gt;NEO_STRIKE.EXE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;Add support for VR device Oculus Rift.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    And then I got busy.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Next&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fabiensanglard.net/reverse_engineering_strike_commander/strike_commander_architecture.php&quot;&gt;Architecture and Documentation&lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/p&gt;

    
      
   

 &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Add a comment&lt;/h3&gt; 
    

    

&lt;h3&gt;Comments (0)&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;

    
    &lt;a name=&quot;c5t_comment&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      
 
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
        
    
    
    
    
    
  
    
    &amp;#13;    
    
    
    
    
    
    
   
 
    
  
    &amp;#13;&lt;h2&gt;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;@2014&lt;/p&gt;

		&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Reverse Engineering Strike Commander
</title>
</item>
<item>
<author>
Violet Blue, Pulp Tech
</author>
<link>
http://www.zdnet.com/google-outed-me-7000025416/
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;storyBody&quot;&gt;
		
		
		
		
					&lt;p&gt;If you haven't heard about it by now, last Wednesday, ESPN's Grantland website published an article called &lt;a href=&quot;http://grantland.com/features/a-mysterious-physicist-golf-club-dr-v/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dr. V&amp;#x2019;s Magical Putter&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#xA0;by Caleb Hannan. It was supposed to be a profile about a golf club, but instead its purpose - and dramatic climax - was to out the club's inventor as transgender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;alignRight&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;google-plus-icons&quot; alt=&quot;google-plus-icons&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/025416/google-plus-icons-200x156.jpg?hash=ZJR4MQH3Zm&amp;amp;upscale=1&quot; width=&quot;200&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The inventor&amp;#x2019;s name was Dr. Essay Anne Vanderbilt. She had agreed to be the subject of the story reluctantly, and only if Hannan wrote about &quot;the science, not the scientist.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Hannan investigated Vanderbilt, he found out that her academic background didn't add up, and he also learned that she was transgender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon learning this, Hannan told her he was going to break the agreement not to write about her personal life and reveal her transgender status without her consent. He then outed her as transgender to her investors and colleagues, and went forward with an article that was intended to out her online, and to the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After being outed to her colleagues, and before the article was published, Dr. Essay Anne Vanderbilt killed herself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It reminded me about another transgender woman who was recently outed without her consent - by Google Plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A woman was using her old (male) name at work, and when her Android phone updated to KitKat - with Google+ integrating chat and SMS into &quot;hangouts&quot; - this is what happened when she texted a coworker:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(ICYMI earlier: KitKat did indeed out me to a coworker. I am freaking out.)&lt;/p&gt;
&amp;#x2014; Erika Sorensen (@eiridescent) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/eiridescent/statuses/419198281546465280&quot;&gt;January 3, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow I didn't think through the potential consequences of Google+ embedding itself ever deeper into stock Android stuff&lt;/p&gt;
&amp;#x2014; Erika Sorensen (@eiridescent) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/eiridescent/statuses/418946496352878593&quot;&gt;January 3, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/jan/07/google-hangouts-faces-criticism-after-outing-trans-woman&quot;&gt;response&lt;/a&gt; was that her outing was &quot;user error&quot; - Google blamed her, the user for not understanding the new, confusing integration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ESPN Grantland editor Bill Simmons issued a 2,700-word statement where he &lt;a href=&quot;http://grantland.com/features/the-dr-v-story-a-letter-from-the-editor/&quot;&gt;lamented twice for failing his writer Hanna&lt;/a&gt;n, but never once expressed concern for failing Ms. Vanderbilt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One could argue that ESPN may not have caused Ms. Vanderbilt's suicide, but its actions in outing her have been acknowledged by ESPN itself and the general public as having played an active, key role in her death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Grantland founder Bill Simmons has since posted a letter to his readers apologizing for outing her saying, &quot;I don&amp;#x2019;t think [Hannan] understood the moral consequences of that decision, and frankly, neither did anyone working for Grantland.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vanderbilt did not want to be out. She wanted to blend in. And though some have been quick to point out that her world would have crumbled had she not been outed as trans, but simply found out as having made up her credentials - those people aren't familiar with the world of sports entrepreneurialism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vanderbilt would have merely joined the ranks of &lt;a href=&quot;http://bleacherreport.com/articles/1660198-how-athletes-lie-to-us&quot;&gt;sports entrepreneurs who got caught&lt;/a&gt; changing their background. Michael Vick, Kevin Hart, Tim Johnson, Nick Saban, Miguel Tijada, Manti Te'o, Rosie Ruiz and George O'Leary are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/9-people-who-were-publicly-shamed-for-lying-on-their-resumes-2012-5?op=1&quot;&gt;just a few&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And like the people in that list, Vanderbilt would have been busted but if her product or performance was great on its own merit, she would have recovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, she was outed as a transgender woman to someone she works with, and before she was to be outed to the world, rather than go through this hell all over again, she took her own life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really pissed right now. Fucking Google. I was NOT ready to tell any of my coworkers yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&amp;#x2014; Erika Sorensen (@eiridescent) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/eiridescent/statuses/419140278486712320&quot;&gt;January 3, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm just glad I live in a state where it'd be illegal to fire me.&lt;/p&gt;
&amp;#x2014; Erika Sorensen (@eiridescent) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/eiridescent/statuses/419142523940917248&quot;&gt;January 3, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the release of the latest mobile software Android 4.4, codenamed KitKat, the instant messaging app Hangouts has become the default text-messaging app on phones and tablets running with the newly installed operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Sorenson wasn't the only transgender person made unsafe by Google+ in Google's ruthless objective to use Android for reorganizing peoples' lives to suit Google's bottom line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four days later on January 7, transgender Android user Zoe &lt;a href=&quot;http://productforums.google.com/forum/#!search/transgender/hangouts/DCa_NkeLXaw/acKNJZ_qhXAJ&quot;&gt;posted to Google Product Forums &amp;gt; Hangouts&lt;/a&gt; that she now needed to change her name and gender display. She did not receive a response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same day (and While Ms. Sorensen was waiting fretfully for her employer's HR person to return to work) Android user Nora posted &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://productforums.google.com/forum/#!search/outed/chat/WCurXt3PQX8/sXJlSjDul80J&quot;&gt;Legal name instead of actual desired/registered name shows up in Hangout History&lt;/a&gt;&quot; to Google Product Forums &amp;gt; Google Chat:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm transgender... this account was registered using my preferred name, Nora, but when I look at hangout histories, certain locations on my android phone, and a few other places, I see my legal name popping up instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't remember actually giving this detail to Google, nor can I find anywhere within the settings where anything other than &quot;Nora&quot; is listed... I don't know how many other people can see me listed as such, but it's really kind of unpleasant and outing, and a bit triggering really...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There're trans ppl for whom this tech flaw would get them fired, w/cascading consequences. There're trans youth who'd be outed to parents.&lt;/p&gt;
&amp;#x2014; Erika Sorensen (@eiridescent) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/eiridescent/statuses/421383623648894976&quot;&gt;January 9, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many trans ppl lose everything or nearly so when they come out. This could've been utterly disastrous.&lt;/p&gt;
&amp;#x2014; Erika Sorensen (@eiridescent) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/eiridescent/statuses/421382479270780928&quot;&gt;January 9, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issue with identity and Google+ Hangouts overwriting people's Gmail and SMS contacts has been trans-unfriendly since its rollout. One woman &lt;a href=&quot;http://productforums.google.com/forum/#!search/transgender/gmail/Ydcnp5ukolQ/xoS51ixVIvkJ&quot;&gt;worried about the privacy of her transgender sister's identity&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#xA0;wrote in Google's Forums (Gmail),&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My sister is transgendered and has yet to legally switch to female, and because of this has yet to change her name on her Google+ since she has professional contacts on her page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(...) Now that I have used the video chat option on Hangouts, everything is reverting back to her old name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She did not receive a response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Google called Erika Sorensen's outing &quot;user error&quot; writer &lt;a href=&quot;http://lexiecannes.com/2014/01/08/google-says-user-error-caused-outing-of-transgender-googleandroid-user/&quot;&gt;Lexi Cannes commented on the matter&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#xA0;January 8, saying &quot;Google is facing increased complaints that they are dismissive of privacy errors triggered by upgrades and other changes. Transgender issues with Google began the day Google+ was launched.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my eyes, finding &lt;a href=&quot;http://productforums.google.com/forum/#!search/transgender/youtube/49Ffi0-6DPk/NXrGOtSF604J&quot;&gt;this distraught post from a Google+ user one month after Plus launched&lt;/a&gt; brought Cannes' comments and Ms. Vanderbilt's suicide full circle:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am FTM transgender, and outside of this channel (which is meant to be detached from my personal, real-life acquaintances) I have not come out yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[the way FTM people are treated when they come out] sickens me and has pushed me farther and farther into the closet to the point where I fear I will not be able to get out before I end up killing myself out of stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I opened up my youtube page today, I was greeted by my birth name, the one that people know and call me by in my outside life, attached to the google+ connection bar just under my profile picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(...) I frantically searched through the google+ page and the youtube settings and found no option to remove connections. Eventually, I was forced to delete my entire google+ account, hoping that would at least remove my legal name from my home page... But it DIDN'T.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My youtube home page still displays that information loud and clear, even though I DE-ACTIVATED MY ACCOUNT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This does not make me feel safe. I feel like my personal privacy as a human being has been stolen from me. So please, if anyone can tell me how to permanently remove google+ and facebook connections from the new page, it would mean so much to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I want to be a part of a safe community.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, Ms. Vanderbilt might have said. What he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still. Ever-shrinking privacy, &quot;real name&quot; policies, etc. aren't just abstract civil liberties issues. Trans ppl disproportionately harmed.&lt;/p&gt;
&amp;#x2014; Erika Sorensen (@eiridescent) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/eiridescent/statuses/418947527010836480&quot;&gt;January 3, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On some level, I want to imagine that Google will fix this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't want to think that controlling our own identities doesn't matter to Google; or it's as if to Google we are the faulty parts of its machine. Or we are Google Plus with a body vaguely attached. Or to Google, the problems are our own faults, and any calls for respect or privacy in a painful world are just annoying to Google, which has better things to do, like terrify us with the privacy nightmare of Google Glass and making bulk data consolidators' jobs of cataloging our personally identifying information easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commenting on Dr. V&amp;#x2019;s Magical Putter, writer &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.niemanstoryboard.org/2014/01/19/the-journalist-and-dr-v/&quot;&gt;Max Potter was quoted on Nieman Storyboard saying&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that piece is emblematic of so much of what I think is wrong with what&amp;#x2019;s happening in journalism today. We&amp;#x2019;ve got journalism and journalists struggling more than ever before to make a name and a living, and thereby more and more pressure on landing an amazing story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#x2019;ve got less and less staff and experience, fewer and fewer &amp;#x201C;adults&amp;#x201D; around, more and more talented kids desperate to make a name and very little mentoring. And, seems to me, we still have this (white) male dominated journalism elite, with their myopic, pseudo-macho ideas of what truth and the pursuit of it means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And &amp;#x2026; this is what we get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this is what we get, then Google's little Plus project is a loaded gun pointed right at anyone whose privacy is what keeps them alive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ZDNet has emailed Google for comment and will update this article if it responds.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		
	
	
&lt;/div&gt;
	

							&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Google outed me
</title>
</item>
<item>
<author>
Dan Colman
</author>
<link>
http://www.openculture.com/2010/07/tarkovksy.html
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot;&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.openculture.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/tarkovsky.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-25930&quot; title=&quot;tarkovsky&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.openculture.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/tarkovsky-e1327177995907.jpg&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Andrei Tarkovsky (1932-1986) firmly positioned himself as the finest Soviet director of the post-War period. But his influence extended well beyond the Soviet Union. &amp;#xA0;The &lt;em&gt;Cahiers du cin&amp;#xE9;ma&lt;/em&gt; consistently ranked his films on &lt;a href=&quot;http://alumnus.caltech.edu/~ejohnson/critics/cahiers.html&quot;&gt;their top ten annual lists&lt;/a&gt;. Ingmar Bergman went so far as to say, &amp;#x201C;Tarkovsky for me is the greatest [director], the one who invented a new language, true to the nature of film, as it captures life as a reflection, life as a dream.&amp;#x201D; And Akira Kurosawa&amp;#xA0;&lt;a href=&quot;http://people.ucalgary.ca/~tstronds/nostalghia.com/TheTopics/Kurosawa_on_AT_obit.html&quot;&gt;acknowledged his influence&lt;/a&gt; too, adding, &amp;#x201C;I love all of Tarkovsky&amp;#x2019;s films. I love his personality and all his works. Every cut from his films is a marvelous image in itself.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shot between 1962 and 1986,&amp;#xA0;Tarkovsky&amp;#x2019;s seven feature films often grapple with&amp;#xA0;metaphysical and spiritual themes, using a distinctive cinematic style. Long takes, slow pacing and metaphorical imagery &amp;#x2013; they all figure into the archetypical Tarkovsky film. (Watch the scene from &lt;em&gt;Stalker&lt;/em&gt; above.)&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;You can now watch Tarkovsky&amp;#x2019;s films online &amp;#x2013; for free. Each film is listed in our collection of&amp;#xA0;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openculture.com/freemoviesonline&quot;&gt;Free Online Movies&lt;/a&gt;, but here you can access each major film in the order in which they were made. Most all of the films below were placed online by Mosfilm, the largest and oldest studion in Russia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE: if you access the films via YouTube, be sure to click &amp;#x201C;CC&amp;#x201D; at the bottom of the videos to access the subtitles.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;#x2019;t forget to follow us on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/openculture&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/openculture&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and now &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/108579751001953501160/posts&quot;&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt;, and add a pinch of culture to your daily social media diet.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related Content:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openculture.com/2013/08/the-masterful-polaroid-pictures-taken-by-filmmaker-andrei-tarkovsky.html&quot;&gt;The Masterful Polaroid Pictures Taken by Filmmaker Andrei Tarkovsky&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openculture.com/2013/01/tarkovskys_advice_to_young_filmmakers.html&quot;&gt;Tarkovsky&amp;#x2019;s Advice to Young Filmmakers: Sacrifice Yourself for Cinema&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openculture.com/2013/08/a-poet-in-cinema-andrei-tarkovsky.html&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;A Poet in Cinema: Andrei Tarkovsky&lt;/i&gt; Reveals the Director&amp;#x2019;s Deep Thoughts on Filmmaking and Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

	

	&lt;/div&gt;

	
				&lt;div class=&quot;mr_social_sharing_wrapper&quot;&gt;
				&lt;span class=&quot;mr_social_sharing&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.openculture.com%2F2010%2F07%2Ftarkovksy.html&amp;amp;t=Tarkovsky+Films+Now+Free+Online&quot; class=&quot;mr_social_sharing_popup_link&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn5.openculture.com/wp-content/plugins/social-sharing-toolkit/images/icons_small/facebook.png&quot; class=&quot;nopin&quot; alt=&quot;Share on Facebook&quot; title=&quot;Share on Facebook&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mr_social_sharing&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/share?url=http%3A%2F%2Fcultr.me%2Fam2mpf&amp;amp;text=Tarkovsky+Films+Now+Free+Online&amp;amp;counturl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.openculture.com%2F2010%2F07%2Ftarkovksy.html&quot; class=&quot;mr_social_sharing_popup_link&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn5.openculture.com/wp-content/plugins/social-sharing-toolkit/images/icons_small/twitter.png&quot; class=&quot;nopin&quot; alt=&quot;Share on Twitter&quot; title=&quot;Share on Twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mr_social_sharing&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:?subject=Tarkovsky%20Films%20Now%20Free%20Online&amp;amp;body=http://www.openculture.com/2010/07/tarkovksy.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.openculture.com/wp-content/plugins/social-sharing-toolkit/images/icons_small/email.png&quot; class=&quot;nopin&quot; alt=&quot;Share via email&quot; title=&quot;Share via email&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mr_social_sharing&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linkedin.com/shareArticle?mini=true&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.openculture.com%2F2010%2F07%2Ftarkovksy.html&amp;amp;title=Tarkovsky+Films+Now+Free+Online&quot; class=&quot;mr_social_sharing_popup_link&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn4.openculture.com/wp-content/plugins/social-sharing-toolkit/images/icons_small/linkedin.png&quot; class=&quot;nopin&quot; alt=&quot;Share on LinkedIn&quot; title=&quot;Share on LinkedIn&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mr_social_sharing&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tumblr.com/share/link?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.openculture.com%2F2010%2F07%2Ftarkovksy.html&amp;amp;name=Tarkovsky+Films+Now+Free+Online&quot; class=&quot;mr_social_sharing_popup_link&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn4.openculture.com/wp-content/plugins/social-sharing-toolkit/images/icons_small/tumblr.png&quot; class=&quot;nopin&quot; alt=&quot;Share on Tumblr&quot; title=&quot;Share on Tumblr&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mr_social_sharing&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.openculture.com%2F2010%2F07%2Ftarkovksy.html&quot; class=&quot;mr_social_sharing_popup_link&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn3.openculture.com/wp-content/plugins/social-sharing-toolkit/images/icons_small/stumbleupon.png&quot; class=&quot;nopin&quot; alt=&quot;Submit to StumbleUpon&quot; title=&quot;Submit to StumbleUpon&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mr_social_sharing&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/submit?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.openculture.com%2F2010%2F07%2Ftarkovksy.html&quot; class=&quot;mr_social_sharing_popup_link&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn4.openculture.com/wp-content/plugins/social-sharing-toolkit/images/icons_small/reddit.png&quot; class=&quot;nopin&quot; alt=&quot;Submit to reddit&quot; title=&quot;Submit to reddit&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mr_social_sharing&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pinterest.com/pin/create/button/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.openculture.com%2F2010%2F07%2Ftarkovksy.html&amp;amp;media=&amp;amp;description=Tarkovsky+Films+Now+Free+Online&quot; class=&quot;pin-it-button&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://assets.pinterest.com/images/PinExt.png&quot; title=&quot;Pin It&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;	
 		
	
	&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Tarkovsky Films Free Online (2010)
</title>
</item>
<item>
<author>
NEIL GOUGH and DAVID GELLES
</author>
<link>
http://dealbook.nytimes.com/2014/01/23/lenovo-buys-ibm-server-business-for-2-3-billion/
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;w592&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphics8.nytimes.com/images/2014/01/23/business/dealbook/dbpix-lenovo/dbpix-lenovo-tmagArticle.jpg&quot; id=&quot;100000002666497&quot; width=&quot;592&quot; alt=&quot;A Lenovo outlet in Hefei, China. The company has agreed to acquire IBM's low-end server unit.&quot;&gt; &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text&quot;&gt;Lenovo said on Thursday that it would pay $2.3  billion for IBM&amp;#x2019;s low-end server business, successfully concluding a deal that had fizzled a year earlier after the two parties failed to agree on a price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text&quot;&gt;Lenovo said it would settle the transaction with $2 billion in cash and the balance in its own Hong Kong-listed shares. About 7,500 IBM employees in locations including Raleigh, N.C., Shanghai and Shenzhen in China, and Taipei, Taiwan, were expected to be offered employment by Lenovo, the Chinese company said in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text&quot;&gt;&amp;#x201C;With the right strategy, great execution, continued innovation and a clear commitment to the x86 industry, we are confident that we can grow this business successfully for the long-term, just  as we have done with our worldwide PC business,&amp;#x201D; Yang Yuanqing, Lenovo&amp;#x2019;s chairman and chief executive, said in a statement, referring to the server industry. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;entry entry-related&quot;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Related Links&lt;/h4&gt;	&lt;div class=&quot;entry-related&quot;&gt;
		&lt;ul&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dealbook.nytimes.com/2014/01/23/lenovo-sees-server-deal-as-part-of-pc-plus-strategy/&quot;&gt;Lenovo Sees Server Deal as Part of &amp;#x2018;PC Plus&amp;#x2019; Strategy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text&quot;&gt;Early last year, Lenovo and IBM were in negotiations about the unit, which includes IBM&amp;#x2019;s x86 server business. At  the time, Lenovo valued the unit at about $2.5 billion, while IBM wanted at least $4 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text&quot;&gt;IBM restarted talks with interested  parties recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text&quot;&gt;Dell and Fujitsu were among the other bidders. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text&quot;&gt;But because Lenovo had already taken a close look at the business last year, it was able to quickly make an offer that IBM was comfortable with. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text&quot;&gt;Lenovo bought IBM&amp;#x2019;s ThinkPad personal computer business in 2005 for $1.75 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text&quot;&gt;In the years since then, the Chinese company has overtaken HP and Dell to become the world&amp;#x2019;s biggest manufacturer of PCs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text&quot;&gt;The server unit being sold has estimated revenues of about $5 billion a year, but IBM does not break out sales for the division, which has lower margins than its software and services businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text&quot;&gt;With a sale of the division, IBM continues its transformation from primarily a hardware producer to a provider of services and software for businesses and governments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text&quot;&gt;&amp;#x201C;This divestiture allows IBM to focus on system and software innovations that bring new kinds of value to strategic areas of our business, such as cognitive computing, Big Data and cloud,&amp;#x201D; Steven A. Mills, senior vice president at IBM Software and Systems, said in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text&quot;&gt;For Lenovo, based in China, acquiring the server business is expected to help it weather the slow decline in its core personal computer business. Lenovo is also expanding into tablets and smartphones as it tries to tap into rising consumer demand for mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text&quot;&gt;In China, Lenovo is already the second-largest smartphone brand, after Samsung, and it has announced plans  for a push into the United States smartphone market this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Neil Gough reported from Hong Kong and David Gelles from New York.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Lenovo Agrees to Buy IBM Server Business for $2.3 Billion
</title>
</item>
<item>
<author>
Terence Eden
</author>
<link>
http://shkspr.mobi/blog/2014/01/another-google-privacy-flaw/
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-bodycopy cf&quot;&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&quot;http://mymisanthropicmusings.org.uk/&quot;&gt;wife&lt;/a&gt; likes to set reminders for herself in Google Calendar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://shkspr.mobi/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Email-Pay-Rise-fs8.png&quot; alt=&quot;Email Pay Rise-fs8&quot; width=&quot;512&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-9532&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Recently, she added a note to her &lt;em&gt;personal&lt;/em&gt; Google Calendar reading &quot;&lt;span&gt;Email &lt;a class=&quot;__cf_email__&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cloudflare.com/email-protection&quot;&gt;[email&amp;#xA0;protected]&lt;/a&gt; to discuss pay rise&lt;/span&gt;&quot; and set the date for a few months from now.  She'd had a discussion with her boss, Alice, and they'd agreed to talk about salary later in the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few moments later, Alice sent her a &quot;Meeting Accepted&quot; email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What... The...?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although pretty embarrassing, it could have been a lot worse.  It could have been &quot;&lt;span&gt;Email &lt;a class=&quot;__cf_email__&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cloudflare.com/email-protection&quot;&gt;[email&amp;#xA0;protected]&lt;/a&gt; with excuse why we can't see her&lt;/span&gt;&quot; or perhaps &quot;&lt;span&gt;Email &lt;a class=&quot;__cf_email__&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cloudflare.com/email-protection&quot;&gt;[email&amp;#xA0;protected]&lt;/a&gt; with divorce details&lt;/span&gt;&quot; or even &quot;&lt;span&gt;Email &lt;a class=&quot;__cf_email__&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cloudflare.com/email-protection&quot;&gt;[email&amp;#xA0;protected]&lt;/a&gt; to demand red stapler back&lt;/span&gt;&quot; or... well, you get the picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, my wife doesn't have a Google+ profile, so there was no information leak other than her email address (which wasn't &quot;huggle.wuggle.2012&quot; or anything daft like that!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've tried several times to recreate this behaviour.  Here's what we discovered:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you use Google Calendar on the web and put a Gmail address in the subject line, that user &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; have the event added to the calendar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They will &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; receive an email notification - although they will get a &quot;meeting reminder&quot; pop-up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating an event on an Android phone does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; trigger a meeting request.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some&lt;/em&gt; non-Gmail addresses will also see the meeting in their calendar - but others will not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you &lt;em&gt;delete&lt;/em&gt; a calendar item, the &quot;Cancellation&quot; notification is emailed &lt;strong&gt;regardless&lt;/strong&gt; of whether the user received the original invite.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://shkspr.mobi/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/Delete-fs8.png&quot; alt=&quot;Delete-fs8&quot; width=&quot;654&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-9611&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
We were unable to determine which &lt;strong&gt;non&lt;/strong&gt;-Gmail addresses would receive the item in their calendar. Some which were hosted with Google didn't receive the pseudo-invitation.  Some accounts hosted on Microsoft Exchange got the invite while others on seemingly similar systems didn't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a video showing it in action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embed-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/ZqjYb6eiMWE?version=3&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that when a user fills in the pop-up, Google Calendar asks for confirmation to send a meeting invite. When using the full interface, &lt;strong&gt;no warning whatsoever&lt;/strong&gt; is given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Impact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google has tried to be clever here.  It has failed.  Just because I am talking &lt;em&gt;about&lt;/em&gt; someone, it doesn't mean I am talking &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; someone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two main risks here - the user could expose her private Gmail account and associated Google+ data, and she could also reveal her private thoughts and feelings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google really needs to work harder at &lt;a href=&quot;http://storify.com/joliss/what-happens-when-our-software-has-broken-privacy&quot;&gt;protecting the privacy of its users&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Disclosure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This privacy issue was formally disclosed to Google on 6th January 2014.&lt;br&gt;
On 22nd January, they responded by saying they &lt;em&gt;didn't&lt;/em&gt; consider it a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We reviewed your report. After careful consideration by our security team, we feel that the issue has minimal impact on the security of our users. Let us know if you believe that this determination may be incorrect. If you'd submitted your report as part of our reward program, this means it doesn't qualify for reward or credit. Thanks for your help!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As much as I'm disappointed not to be getting a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.co.uk/about/appsecurity/reward-program/&quot;&gt;$10,000 bug bounty&lt;/a&gt;, I'm more upset that Google repeatedly finds itself &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zdnet.com/google-outed-me-7000025416/&quot;&gt;failing to keep its users' private information private&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;ins datetime=&quot;2014-01-23T13:54:42+00:00&quot;&gt;Update&lt;/ins&gt;: according to a comment on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=7107597&quot;&gt;HackerNews discussion&lt;/a&gt; - problems like this have been &lt;a href=&quot;http://lee-phillips.org/gcaldisaster/&quot;&gt;reported to Google as far back as 2010&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-10187660-9531-52e2047ab378f&quot;&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;likes-widget-placeholder post-likes-widget-placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;sd-link-color&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-flattr-button&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;FlattrButton&quot; href=&quot;http://shkspr.mobi/blog/2014/01/another-google-privacy-flaw/&quot; title=&quot; Another Google Privacy Flaw - Calendar Unexpectedly Leaks Private Information (Disclosed)&quot; rev=&quot;flattr;uid:edent42;language:en_GB;category:text;tags:bugs,gmail,google,privacy,blog;popout:0;button:compact;&quot;&gt;My wife likes to set reminders for herself in Google Calendar. Recently, she added a note to her personal Google Calendar reading &quot;Email &lt;span class=&quot;__cf_email__&quot;&gt;[email&amp;#xA0;protected]&lt;/span&gt; to discuss pay rise&quot; and set...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				
			&lt;/div&gt;

			
			


		&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Google Calendar Unexpectedly Leaks Private Information
</title>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
