<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version='2.0'>
<channel>
<generator>
clj-rss
</generator>
<link>
https://news.ycombinator.com
</link>
<title>
myread
</title>
<description>
myread
</description>
<item>
<author>
Ron Amadeo
</author>
<link>
http://arstechnica.com/security/2014/01/malware-vendors-buy-chrome-extensions-to-send-adware-filled-updates/?
</link>
<description>
&lt;div class=&quot;article-content clearfix&quot; score=&quot;10.0&quot;&gt;
    
&lt;figure class=&quot;intro-image image center full-width&quot;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/code-640x283.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;&gt;
  
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;One of the coolest things about Chrome is the silent, automatic updates that always ensure that users are always running the latest version. While Chrome itself is updated automatically by Google, that update process also includes Chrome's extensions, which are updated by the extension owners. This means that it's up to the user to decide if the owner of an extension is trustworthy or not, since you are basically giving them permission to push new code out to your browser whenever they feel like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make matters worse, ownership of a Chrome extension can be &lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;transferred to another party, and users are never informed when an ownership change happens. Malware and adware vendors have caught wind of this and have started showing up at the doors of extension authors, looking to buy their extensions. Once the deal is done and the ownership of the extension is transferred, the new owners can issue an ad-filled update over Chrome's update service, which sends the adware out to every user of that extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ought to clarify here that Google isn't explicitly responsible for such unwanted adware, but vendors are exploiting Google's extension system to create a subpar—and possibly dangerous—browsing experience. Ars has contacted Google for comment, but we haven't heard back yet. We'll update this article if we do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;image center full&quot; score=&quot;12.5&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/2014-01-17_14-20-38.png&quot; width=&quot;613&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot; score=&quot;20.0&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;User reviews for Add to Feedly complaining about the adware.&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.labnol.org/internet/sold-chrome-extension/28377/&quot;&gt;first-hand account&lt;/a&gt; of this, which was first spotted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.omgchrome.com/malware-buying-google-chrome-extensions/&quot;&gt;OMGChrome&lt;/a&gt;, was given by Amit Agarwal, developer of the &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/add-to-feedly/ejkjjleifeeaccajkekdcckflfpenoen?hl=en&quot;&gt;Add to Feedly&lt;/a&gt;&quot; extension. One morning, Agarwal got an e-mail offering &quot;4 figures&quot; for the sale of his Chrome extension. The extension was only about an hour's worth of work, so Agarwal agreed to the deal, the money was sent over PayPal, and he transferred ownership of the extension to another Google account. A month later, the new extension owners released their first (and so far only) update, which injected adware on all webpages and started redirecting links. Chrome's extension auto-update mechanism silently pushed out the update to all 30,000 Add to Feedly users, and the ad revenue likely started rolling in. While Agarwal had no idea what the buyer's intention was when the deal was made, he later learned that he ended up selling his users to the wolves. The buyer was not after the Chrome extension, they were just looking for an easy attack vector in the extension's user base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn't a one-time event, either. About a month ago, I had a very simple Chrome extension called &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/tweet-this-page/ppilhaolhbpfembaoedfdbkegfedfgip/reviews&quot;&gt;Tweet This Page&lt;/a&gt;&quot; suddenly transform into an ad-injecting machine and start hijacking Google searches. A quick search for the Chrome Web Store reveals several other extensions that reviewers say suddenly made a U-turn from useful extension to ad-injector. There is even an extension that purports to &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/stop-extensions-from-inje/bjdaconoeojhhkdjndlelgklkmalleon&quot;&gt;stop other extensions&lt;/a&gt; from injecting ads. Injected ads &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/chrome/web-store/program_policies&quot;&gt;are allowed&lt;/a&gt; in Chrome extensions, but Google's policy states that which app the ads are coming from must be clearly disclosed to the user, and they cannot interfere with any native ads or the functionality of the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;image center large full-width&quot; score=&quot;12.5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/2014-01-17_14-08-2114.png&quot; class=&quot;enlarge&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/2014-01-17_14-08-2114-640x203.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot; score=&quot;17.5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/2014-01-17_14-08-2114.png&quot; class=&quot;enlarge&quot;&gt;Enlarge&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sep&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; Code from Tweet This Page, which hijacks Google, Yahoo, and Bing results and redirects to searchgist.com.&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;When malicious apps don't follow Google's disclosure policy, diagnosing something like this is extremely difficult. When Tweet This Page started spewing ads and malware into my browser&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;, the only &lt;/span&gt;initial&lt;span&gt; sign was that ads on the Internet had suddenly become much more intrusive, and many auto-played sound. The extension only started injecting ads a few days after it was installed in an attempt to make it more difficult to detect. After a while, Google search became useless, because every link would redirect to some other webpage. My initial thought was to take an inventory of every program I had installed recently—I never suspected an &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;update&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt; would bring in malware. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;I ran a ton of malware/virus scanners, and they all found nothing. I was only clued into the fact that Chrome was the culprit because the same thing started happening on &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;my Chromebook—if I didn't notice that, the next step would have probably been a full wipe of my computer. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The difficult part of this for users is that normal removal techniques will not work. Virus scanners are unlikely to flag ad-injecting JavaScript as malicious. Extensions are synced to your Google account, which means that even wiping out a computer and reinstalling the OS will not remove the malware—signing-in to Chrome will just download it again. The only way to be rid of the malware is to find the extension in chrome://extensions and remove it—and to make sure the removal gets propagated to your account and down to all your other devices. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Even when you have it narrowed down to Chrome, since nothing detects a malicious Chrome extension, the best course of action is to meticulously check the latest reviews of every extension and hope that someone else has figured out where the ads are coming from.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can users do to protect themselves? It's very hard to keep yourself in the loop with Chrome extension updates. Extensions usually don't have changelogs, and there is currently no way to disable extension auto-updating. One way to stay a least slightly informed of what is going on is to install an extension that will &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/extensions-update-notifie/nlldbplhbaopldicmcoogopmkonpebjm?hl=en&quot;&gt;notify you&lt;/a&gt; when your other extensions get updated. Other than that, the only other option is to stop using extensions entirely, which is a little extreme. Just keep an eye on the simpler extensions from smaller extension makers—those are the ones &lt;span&gt;at most risk of being gobbled up by a malicious entity. Chrome will require your approval if an extension adds &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://developer.chrome.com/extensions/permission_warnings.html&quot;&gt;new permissions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, but the magic permission that allows ad-injecting is called &quot;access your data on all web pages,&quot; which many legitimate extensions already use. A malicious extension buyer could even look for an extension that already uses this permission so that their update will arouse the least suspicion among current users.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reality, though, is that while it's extremely easy for a novice user to install an extension, it's nearly impossible for them to diagnose and remove an extension that has turned sour, and Chrome Sync will make sure that extension hangs around on all their devices for a long time. The author of Add to Feedly stated that his extension had around 30,000 users before it was sold and packed full of ads. Today, despite the flood of unhappy user reviews, the Chrome Web Store shows 31,548 users. Auto-updating from a trusted source is one thing, but when that user trust can be bought and sold—and extension ownership can change hands without the users being informed—something needs to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
    		&lt;/div&gt;
    
</description>
<title>
Adware vendors buy Chrome Extensions to send ad- and malware-filled updates
</title>
</item>
<item>
<link>
http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=MTU3Mzc
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Today&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=19581&quot; title=&quot;Early Ubuntu 14.04 Tests Show Some Performance Changes&quot;&gt;Early Ubuntu 14.04 Tests Show Some Performance Changes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;01:27 AM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=category&amp;amp;item=Operating%20Systems&quot;&gt;Operating Systems&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91622&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;1 Comment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;If you have been wanting to take some time this holiday season to switch from Ubuntu 13.10 stable to the latest development packages for Ubuntu 14.04 LTS, here's some quick benchmarks I did last week showing some of the performance changes to be found right now from using the latest Ubuntu 14.04 development packages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;16 December&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=19557&quot; title=&quot;FreeBSD 10.0 Kernel Comes To Debian&quot;&gt;FreeBSD 10.0 Kernel Comes To Debian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;09:15 PM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=category&amp;amp;item=Operating%20Systems&quot;&gt;Operating Systems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;Advancing prudently but quietly within the Debian camp is the Debian GNU/kFreeBSD operating system that pairs Debian's GNU user-land with the FreeBSD kernel. For Debian 8.0 &quot;Jessie&quot; there are continued improvements on this spin that does away with the Linux kernel. Debian GNU/kFreeBSD Jessie/Sid currently defaults to the FreeBSD 9.2.0 kernel, but a FreeBSD 10.0 development kernel has already landed in Debian and is the focus of today's benchmarks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0NTQ&quot; title=&quot;BGFX Makes It Easy Targeting Multiple Rendering APIs&quot;&gt;BGFX Makes It Easy Targeting Multiple Rendering APIs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;04:39 PM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=Free%20Software&quot;&gt;Free Software&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91604&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;1 Comment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;BGFX is a cross-platform rendering library that makes it easy targeting multiple versions of OpenGL and Direct3D on platforms ranging from Apple iOS to Windows to Google Native Client.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0NTM&quot; title=&quot;OpenDocument ODF Support Coming To The Web&quot;&gt;OpenDocument ODF Support Coming To The Web&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;03:25 PM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=Free%20Software&quot;&gt;Free Software&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91602&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;2 Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;WebODF is a new open-source projet that allows ODF document files to be displayed within a web-browser. WebODF is used by the new OwnCloud release for its collaborative, web-based ODF file editing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=19632&quot; title=&quot;SteamOS vs. Windows 8.1 NVIDIA Performance&quot;&gt;SteamOS vs. Windows 8.1 NVIDIA Performance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;01:43 PM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=category&amp;amp;item=Linux%20Gaming&quot;&gt;Linux Gaming&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91595&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;23 Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;For those NVIDIA gaming customers running Microsoft Windows 8.1 that have been thinking about giving Valve's SteamOS Linux-based gaming platform a try, here are some early benchmarks of the SteamOS 1.0 beta that compare the performance to Microsoft Windows 8.1 Pro x64 on multiple NVIDIA GeForce graphics cards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0NTI&quot; title=&quot;FreeBSD 10.0 RC2 Brings Radeon KMS Fixes&quot;&gt;FreeBSD 10.0 RC2 Brings Radeon KMS Fixes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;The second release candidate to FreeBSD 10.0 is now available and with it comes Radeon KMS graphics driver bug-fixes and other cleaned-up and fixed code.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0NTE&quot; title=&quot;Linux Kernel Support For Intel Processor Trace (Intel PT)&quot;&gt;Linux Kernel Support For Intel Processor Trace (Intel PT)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;Patches were published last week that enable support for the Intel Processor Trace extension within the Linux kernel's perf sub-system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=19483&quot; title=&quot;Intel HD Graphics Linux 3.13 + Mesa 10.1 Update&quot;&gt;Intel HD Graphics Linux 3.13 + Mesa 10.1 Update&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;07:30 AM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=category&amp;amp;item=Display%20Drivers&quot;&gt;Display Drivers&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91572&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;1 Comment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;In continuing from yesterday's article that offered up fresh benchmarks of Intel Sandy Bridge &amp;amp; Ivy Bridge CPUs with the latest Linux code atop Ubuntu 13.10, out today are new graphics benchmarks using the very latest open-source Intel Linux graphics driver code and trying out CPUs with HD Graphics 2000, 2500, 3000. The open-source Intel graphics driver has certainly matured a lot since the debut of Sandy Bridge and Ivy Bridge CPUs!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0NTA&quot; title=&quot;Ubuntu Now Supports Cross-Compiling CMake Projects&quot;&gt;Ubuntu Now Supports Cross-Compiling CMake Projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;The latest developer package uploads into Ubuntu 14.04 &quot;Trusty Tahr&quot; allow for cross-compiling CMake-based projects, e.g. compiling Mir and Unity 8 for ARM from an x86 system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0NDk&quot; title=&quot;Gummiboot Gains Splash Screen Support&quot;&gt;Gummiboot Gains Splash Screen Support&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;05:05 AM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=Hardware&quot;&gt;Hardware&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91551&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;7 Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;Gummiboot, the simple and open-source UEFI boot manager, now has support for displaying a user-defined splash screen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0NDg&quot; title=&quot;Debian 7.3 Officially Released&quot;&gt;Debian 7.3 Officially Released&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;04:59 AM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=Distributions&quot;&gt;Distributions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;Coincidentally, Debian GNU/Linux 7.3 was released this weekend -- the same weekend as it being known that SteamOS is Debian-based.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;15 December&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=19623&quot; title=&quot;SteamOS vs. Ubuntu 13.10 - Intel HD Graphics Performance&quot;&gt;SteamOS vs. Ubuntu 13.10 - Intel HD Graphics Performance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;05:25 PM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=category&amp;amp;item=Linux%20Gaming&quot;&gt;Linux Gaming&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91518&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;25 Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;When Valve announced the public release of the beta for SteamOS 1.0 &quot;Alchemist&quot; on Friday they listed NVIDIA graphics as a hardware requirement, but I showed that AMD Radeon graphics with Catalyst would work and it's possible to get Intel graphics working (or the open-source graphics drivers in general) through a minor change to the Linux-based SteamOS kernel parameters. After that I ran some benchmarks and here are a few performance results comparing SteamOS 1.0 Beta to Ubuntu 13.10 with Intel HD Graphics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0NDc&quot; title=&quot;Linux 3.13-rc4 Kernel Released, But It's Too Big&quot;&gt;Linux 3.13-rc4 Kernel Released, But It's Too Big&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;04:12 PM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=Linux%20Kernel&quot;&gt;Linux Kernel&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91510&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;1 Comment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;Linux 3.13-rc4 was released today but Linus Torvalds isn't too happy as this latest test release is much bigger than the earlier development RCs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0NDY&quot; title=&quot;Lenovo X201 Support Comes To Coreboot&quot;&gt;Lenovo X201 Support Comes To Coreboot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;02:09 PM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=Hardware&quot;&gt;Hardware&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91505&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;2 Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;The Lenovo ThinkPad X201 laptop is now supported by mainline Coreboot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0NDU&quot; title=&quot;It's Easy Getting Intel Graphics To Work On SteamOS&quot;&gt;It's Easy Getting Intel Graphics To Work On SteamOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;12:12 PM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=Gaming&quot;&gt;Gaming&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91502&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;9 Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;While Valve only advertises NVIDIA graphics driver support in the SteamOS Beta released on Friday, I already found that AMD Radeon GPUs work with Catalyst on this Debian Linux derived OS. With a simple tweak, Intel HD Graphics can also run quite fine on SteamOS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0NDQ&quot; title=&quot;AMD Catalyst Graphics Do Work On SteamOS&quot;&gt;AMD Catalyst Graphics Do Work On SteamOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;09:52 AM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=Gaming&quot;&gt;Gaming&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91489&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;7 Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;The binary Catalyst graphics driver is pre-installed and does work on Valve's SteamOS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0NDM&quot; title=&quot;Linux Kernel Works To Make Better Random Reseeding&quot;&gt;Linux Kernel Works To Make Better Random Reseeding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;09:05 AM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=Hardware&quot;&gt;Hardware&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91482&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;1 Comment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;While /dev/random was made faster and more random in Linux 3.13, in light of the NSA controversies and that Intel/VIA hardware encryption and random generators may not even be trustworthy, there's been a rework in how reseeding happens for the Linux kernel's random component.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=19621&quot; title=&quot;The First NVIDIA GeForce Benchmarks On The SteamOS Beta&quot;&gt;The First NVIDIA GeForce Benchmarks On The SteamOS Beta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;12:35 AM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=category&amp;amp;item=Linux%20Gaming&quot;&gt;Linux Gaming&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91440&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;21 Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;A comprehensive performance comparison is underway at Phoronix that pits SteamOS against other desktop Linux distributions, but for those anxious to see some performance numbers, here are benchmarks done so far this weekend from seven NVIDIA GeForce graphics cards on the public SteamOS 1.0 Beta operating system. In this article are early benchmarks from seven NVIDIA GeForce graphics cards running Valve's Debian Linux based SteamOS on an Intel Haswell system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;14 December&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0NDI&quot; title='The Steam Controller Works &quot;Out Of The Box&quot; On Linux'&gt;The Steam Controller Works &quot;Out Of The Box&quot; On Linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;07:03 PM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=Gaming&quot;&gt;Gaming&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91435&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;12 Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;Valve's initial Steam Controller prototype for use with the Steam Machines Linux-based game console will also work &quot;out of the box&quot; on other Linux distributions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=19478&quot; title=&quot;Intel Core i3/i5 Linux Performance Update&quot;&gt;Intel Core i3/i5 Linux Performance Update&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;02:30 PM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=category&amp;amp;item=Processors&quot;&gt;Processors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;For those curious about the performance of Intel's Sandy Bridge and Ivy Bridge processors when upgrading to Ubuntu 13.10 and the experimental Linux 3.13 along with the latest stable GCC 4.8.2 compiler, here's some fresh benchmarks from several different Intel Core i3 and Core i5 CPUs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0NDE&quot; title=&quot;Mesa Support Comes For Adaptive Vsync&quot;&gt;Mesa Support Comes For Adaptive Vsync&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;11:37 AM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=Mesa&quot;&gt;Mesa&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91402&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;27 Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;Patches published for Mesa today are beginning to work on adaptive vsync support and eventually the GLX_EXT_swap_control_tear extension.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0NDA&quot; title=&quot;Running The SteamOS Kernel On Ubuntu Linux&quot;&gt;Running The SteamOS Kernel On Ubuntu Linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;10:07 AM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=Ubuntu&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91401&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;13 Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;It is possible to install Valve's SteamOS modified Linux kernel onto an Ubuntu Linux installation, but I would recommend against doing so, at least for now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0Mzk&quot; title=&quot;DRI3 Patches Published For Gallium3D Drivers&quot;&gt;DRI3 Patches Published For Gallium3D Drivers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;08:05 AM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=X.Org&quot;&gt;X.Org&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91382&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;1 Comment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;Besides clearing out 1,000+ X.Org Server warnings, Keith Packard at Intel recently has been working on a new patch-set so DRI3 can be used by Mesa's Gallium3D graphics drivers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0Mzg&quot; title=&quot;Android's ION Proposed For Mainline Linux&quot;&gt;Android's ION Proposed For Mainline Linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;07:49 AM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=Linux%20Kernel&quot;&gt;Linux Kernel&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91381&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;10 Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;Android's ION memory allocator has been proposed for mainlining into the Linux kernel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0MzE&quot; title=&quot;Linux 3.13 Kernel CPU Governor Benchmarks&quot;&gt;Linux 3.13 Kernel CPU Governor Benchmarks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;07:06 AM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=Linux%20Kernel&quot;&gt;Linux Kernel&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91375&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;1 Comment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;At the request of several Phoronix readers, here are some new CPU governor benchmarks from the Linux 3.13 development kernel as of Friday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=19470&quot; title=&quot;NVIDIA Linux Anti-Aliasing Performance Update&quot;&gt;NVIDIA Linux Anti-Aliasing Performance Update&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;06:38 AM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=category&amp;amp;item=Display%20Drivers&quot;&gt;Display Drivers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;After delivering Radeon Gallium3D MSAA benchmarks earlier in the week to share where the open-source AMD driver is at in its support for multi-sample anti-aliasing, here's some AA benchmarks from NVIDIA's high-class binary Linux graphics driver. The NVIDIA Linux driver offers some of the best anti-aliasing support among Linux graphics drivers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0Mzc&quot; title=&quot;Former NVIDIA, Microsoft Developers Doing Lots Of The SteamOS Work&quot;&gt;Former NVIDIA, Microsoft Developers Doing Lots Of The SteamOS Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;01:09 AM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=Gaming&quot;&gt;Gaming&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91348&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;28 Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;A former NVIDIA engineer joined Valve some months ago and is responsible for lots of the work on SteamOS and their Linux support. A long-time Microsoft employee is also involved in designing SteamOS. Here's also a few other bits of information in my SteamOS adventures this evening.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;13 December&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0MzY&quot; title=&quot;SteamOS Compositor Details, Kernel Patches, Screenshots&quot;&gt;SteamOS Compositor Details, Kernel Patches, Screenshots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;09:08 PM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=Gaming&quot;&gt;Gaming&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91336&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;36 Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;Here are more details on the innards of SteamOS along with some screenshots of the GNOME-based desktop environment outside of the Steam Big Picture Mode.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0MzU&quot; title=&quot;SteamOS Has Its Own Graphics Compositor&quot;&gt;SteamOS Has Its Own Graphics Compositor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;07:02 PM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=Gaming&quot;&gt;Gaming&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91327&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;51 Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;More details regarding the Debian-based SteamOS are emerging. There's also a SteamOS installer now available but the server is getting slaughtered at the moment by those trying to download SteamOS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0MzQ&quot; title=&quot;Enlightenment 0.18 Release Candidate 2 Released&quot;&gt;Enlightenment 0.18 Release Candidate 2 Released&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;06:45 PM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=Desktop&quot;&gt;Desktop&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91317&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;1 Comment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;As some additional exciting news on Friday night besides the SteamOS beta being out is that the second release candidate to Enlightenment 0.18 is now available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0MzM&quot; title=&quot;SteamOS 1.0 Is Based Upon Debian Wheezy&quot;&gt;SteamOS 1.0 Is Based Upon Debian Wheezy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;06:22 PM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=Gaming&quot;&gt;Gaming&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91316&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;42 Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;As expected, SteamOS is starting to surface today. Here's the first details!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0MzI&quot; title=&quot;X.Org Server: 1,047 Warnings Reduced To Zero&quot;&gt;X.Org Server: 1,047 Warnings Reduced To Zero&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;06:03 PM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=X.Org&quot;&gt;X.Org&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91315&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;36 Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;Keith Packard has been working on an X.Org Server clean-up of the aging code-base and he's managed to reduce the number of generated warnings down to zero.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0MzA&quot; title=&quot;More Ubuntu Benchmarks Of The Haswell Chromebook&quot;&gt;More Ubuntu Benchmarks Of The Haswell Chromebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;04:11 PM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=Hardware&quot;&gt;Hardware&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91302&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;10 Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;Yesterday I shared the first Phoronix tests of Ubuntu running on the Acer C720 Chromebook, a ChromeOS-focused device powered by an Intel Celeron &quot;Haswell&quot; processor. The performance was great -- as was the build quality and features -- for being a $199 USD device that can be loaded with other operating systems too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0Mjk&quot; title=&quot;KDE digiKam 4.0 Beta Released&quot;&gt;KDE digiKam 4.0 Beta Released&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;01:43 PM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=KDE&quot;&gt;KDE&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91294&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;2 Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;KDE's digiKam software for managing digital camera images is finally up to version 4.0, albeit in beta form. The digiKam 4.0 Beta brings new features and lands a lot of the GSoC 2013 changes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0Mjg&quot; title=&quot;NetworkManager Gets A New Text Interface&quot;&gt;NetworkManager Gets A New Text Interface&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;12:21 PM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=GNOME&quot;&gt;GNOME&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91276&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;16 Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;While NetworkManager already has great integration with the GNOME and KDE desktops and there are command-line interfaces to this open-source network management program, there's now a new curses-based interface.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=19564&quot; title=&quot;Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7 Beta 1 Looks Great, Performance Is Great&quot;&gt;Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7 Beta 1 Looks Great, Performance Is Great&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;04:00 AM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=category&amp;amp;item=Operating%20Systems&quot;&gt;Operating Systems&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91240&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;27 Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;Red Hat this week released the first beta to Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7. RHEL 7 is based upon improvements and other work that happened over the past few release cycles in Fedora and is riding on its new enterprise Linux 3.10 kernel. In this article is a first look at RHEL 7 Beta 1 along with our first benchmarks of Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7 comparing the results to Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6.5.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0MjY&quot; title=&quot;Valve Set To Debut SteamOS Linux Today&quot;&gt;Valve Set To Debut SteamOS Linux Today&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;01:56 AM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=Gaming&quot;&gt;Gaming&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91231&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;15 Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;If all goes according to plan, Valve will be making publicly available their Linux-based SteamOS platform in a matter of hours.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0MjU&quot; title=&quot;GNOME 3.12 To Plug Into Facebook In New Ways&quot;&gt;GNOME 3.12 To Plug Into Facebook In New Ways&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;01:10 AM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=GNOME&quot;&gt;GNOME&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91229&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;18 Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;GNOME applications are seeing greater integration support with Facebook in the GNOME 3.12 development cycle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0Mjc&quot; title=&quot;Xen PVH Support Brought Back Up For The Linux Kernel&quot;&gt;Xen PVH Support Brought Back Up For The Linux Kernel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;12:29 AM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=Virtualization&quot;&gt;Virtualization&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91228&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;1 Comment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;Konrad Rzeszutek Wilk at Oracle has re-posted the Xen PVH patches for the Linux kernel as he seeks to get support for para-virtualized hardware extensions into the Linux kernel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0MjQ&quot; title=&quot;ECMA Is Working On Standardizing Google's Dart&quot;&gt;ECMA Is Working On Standardizing Google's Dart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_home_page_sub&quot;&gt;12:15 AM EST - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_topic&amp;amp;q=Google&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/forums/showthread.php?t=91225&amp;amp;goto=newpost&quot;&gt;19 Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;phxcms_home_con&quot;&gt;ECMA International has formed a technical committee to work on a standard specification for the Dart web programming language that's developed by Google as an alternative to JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/rss.php&quot;&gt;RSS Feed&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=phoronix_articles&quot;&gt;Articles &amp;amp; Reviews&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=phoronix_news&quot;&gt;News Archives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;





&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_contentphx_right_bar&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_bar_align&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text-align: center; margin: 10px auto;&quot;&gt;In addition to supporting our site through our advertisers or by subscribing to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=phoronix_premium&quot;&gt;Phoronix Premium&lt;/a&gt;, another way you can support our Linux hardware and software efforts is by clicking the links below when shopping at your favorite Internet retailers, for which we generate a commission off whatever you purchase. It's that easy, thanks!&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2F&amp;amp;tag=phoronix-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&quot;&gt;Amazon.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;




&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_contentphx_right_bar&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_bar_align&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ4MDE&quot; title=&quot;AMD: AMD Intentionally Crippled Their HDMI Adapters&quot;&gt;AMD Intentionally Crippled Their HDMI Adapters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ3NDU&quot; title=&quot;AMD: AMD Posts A Horde Of New 3D GPU Documentation&quot;&gt;AMD Posts A Horde Of New 3D GPU Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ3MDU&quot; title=&quot;AMD: AMD's Mantle Graphics API For Linux?&quot;&gt;AMD's Mantle Graphics API For Linux?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ5NDA&quot; title=&quot;BSD: Arch BSD Is Still Around &amp;amp; Keeping It Simple&quot;&gt;Arch BSD Is Still Around &amp;amp; Keeping It Simple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUwODY&quot; title=&quot;BSD: The State Of FreeBSD's Bhyve Virtualization&quot;&gt;The State Of FreeBSD's Bhyve Virtualization&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ3MzU&quot; title=&quot;BSD: FreeBSD 9.2 Brings ZFS TRIM, ZFS LZ4, Updated DTrace&quot;&gt;FreeBSD 9.2 Brings ZFS TRIM, ZFS LZ4, Updated DTrace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ5NzQ&quot; title=&quot;Compiler: Debian To Switch To Systemd Or Upstart&quot;&gt;Debian To Switch To Systemd Or Upstart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ5NjM&quot; title=&quot;Compiler: GCC 4.9 Will Make Compilers More Exciting In 2014&quot;&gt;GCC 4.9 Will Make Compilers More Exciting In 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUxNzQ&quot; title=&quot;Compiler: GCC 4.9 Continues Piling On New Features&quot;&gt;GCC 4.9 Continues Piling On New Features&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ4ODc&quot; title=&quot;Desktop: Glx-Dock 3.3 Has A Big Core Rewrite&quot;&gt;Glx-Dock 3.3 Has A Big Core Rewrite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUzMDA&quot; title=&quot;Desktop: Enlightenment EFL 1.8 Coming Next Week, 1.9 In 2014&quot;&gt;Enlightenment EFL 1.8 Coming Next Week, 1.9 In 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUxNzM&quot; title=&quot;Desktop: New Lightworks Linux Beta Steps Up The Features&quot;&gt;New Lightworks Linux Beta Steps Up The Features&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUwNDE&quot; title=&quot;Distributions: Debian Trying Out Xfce Over GNOME By Default&quot;&gt;Debian Trying Out Xfce Over GNOME By Default&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ4NTA&quot; title=&quot;Distributions: Debian 8.0 To Be Frozen, Features Announced&quot;&gt;Debian 8.0 To Be Frozen, Features Announced&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUxNzY&quot; title=&quot;Distributions: Canonical Developer Criticizes Linux Mint's Security&quot;&gt;Canonical Developer Criticizes Linux Mint's Security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ5ODc&quot; title=&quot;Fedora: Fedora 20 Beta vs. Ubuntu 13.10 Benchmarks&quot;&gt;Fedora 20 Beta vs. Ubuntu 13.10 Benchmarks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ4MTc&quot; title=&quot;Fedora: Ubuntu 13.10 vs. Fedora Linux CPU Benchmarks&quot;&gt;Ubuntu 13.10 vs. Fedora Linux CPU Benchmarks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUzMDg&quot; title='Fedora: Exciting Features For Fedora 20 &quot;Heisenbug&quot;'&gt;Exciting Features For Fedora 20 &quot;Heisenbug&quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ4NDI&quot; title=&quot;Free Software: OpenRISC Emulator In JavaScript Can Run Wayland&quot;&gt;OpenRISC Emulator In JavaScript Can Run Wayland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ3MDM&quot; title=&quot;Free Software: IBM Releases FusedOS Operating System&quot;&gt;IBM Releases FusedOS Operating System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUxNjM&quot; title=&quot;Free Software: NVIDIA, Mentor Graphics May Harm GCC&quot;&gt;NVIDIA, Mentor Graphics May Harm GCC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0MzY&quot; title=&quot;Gaming: SteamOS Compositor Details, Kernel Patches, Screenshots&quot;&gt;SteamOS Compositor Details, Kernel Patches, Screenshots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0MzU&quot; title=&quot;Gaming: SteamOS Has Its Own Graphics Compositor&quot;&gt;SteamOS Has Its Own Graphics Compositor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTU0MTA&quot; title=&quot;Gaming: Activision Is Preventing A Game From Coming To Linux&quot;&gt;Activision Is Preventing A Game From Coming To Linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ2Nzg&quot; title=&quot;GNOME: What's Your Hopes From Valve's SteamOS?&quot;&gt;What's Your Hopes From Valve's SteamOS?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ3MjM&quot; title='GNOME: GNOME &quot;Flashback&quot; Released, GNOME Panel 3.8'&gt;GNOME &quot;Flashback&quot; Released, GNOME Panel 3.8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ4ODM&quot; title=&quot;GNOME: Wireshark Is Being Ported From GTK+ To Qt&quot;&gt;Wireshark Is Being Ported From GTK+ To Qt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ2ODY&quot; title=&quot;Google: GNOME 3.10 Has Been Officially Released&quot;&gt;GNOME 3.10 Has Been Officially Released&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ4NzE&quot; title=&quot;Google: Linux Won't Get Aura UI Stack Until Google Chrome 33&quot;&gt;Linux Won't Get Aura UI Stack Until Google Chrome 33&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUyMTM&quot; title=&quot;Google: Google Shows Off Nice Performance On SPDY&quot;&gt;Google Shows Off Nice Performance On SPDY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ5NzE&quot; title='Hardware: The ASUS &quot;Bay Trail&quot; T100 Is Not Linux Friendly'&gt;The ASUS &quot;Bay Trail&quot; T100 Is Not Linux Friendly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUxNTc&quot; title=&quot;Hardware: Is All Hope Lost For Non-Android Linux Tablets?&quot;&gt;Is All Hope Lost For Non-Android Linux Tablets?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ5Mjc&quot; title=&quot;Hardware: ARM Cortex-A15 big.LITTLE Pitted Against Intel, AMD&quot;&gt;ARM Cortex-A15 big.LITTLE Pitted Against Intel, AMD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUzODc&quot; title=&quot;Intel: Intel Developer Finds 50 Watt Power Regression In Linux&quot;&gt;Intel Developer Finds 50 Watt Power Regression In Linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUzMDc&quot; title=&quot;Intel: Choosing A 2013 Laptop/Ultrabook For Linux&quot;&gt;Choosing A 2013 Laptop/Ultrabook For Linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUyNzY&quot; title=&quot;Intel: Intel Makes Major Zlib Performance Improvements&quot;&gt;Intel Makes Major Zlib Performance Improvements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUyNDk&quot; title=&quot;KDE: KDE's Kdenlive Video Editor Has Gone Dark&quot;&gt;KDE's Kdenlive Video Editor Has Gone Dark&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUwMTQ&quot; title=&quot;KDE: KDE Developers Continue To Be Frustrated With Canonical&quot;&gt;KDE Developers Continue To Be Frustrated With Canonical&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ3NjE&quot; title=&quot;KDE: A Look At Some KDE 4.12 Features&quot;&gt;A Look At Some KDE 4.12 Features&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUxNTk&quot; title=&quot;Linux Kernel: 13 Reasons Linux 3.13 Is Going To Be Very Exciting&quot;&gt;13 Reasons Linux 3.13 Is Going To Be Very Exciting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ5MDU&quot; title=&quot;Linux Kernel: NFTables IPTables-Replacement Queued For Linux 3.13&quot;&gt;NFTables IPTables-Replacement Queued For Linux 3.13&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUwMzA&quot; title=&quot;Linux Kernel: Linux 3.12 Kernel Released; Linux 4.0 Planning Talked Up&quot;&gt;Linux 3.12 Kernel Released; Linux 4.0 Planning Talked Up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ5NjU&quot; title=&quot;Mesa: Hi10P Support Proposed For VDPAU&quot;&gt;Hi10P Support Proposed For VDPAU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ3MTc&quot; title=&quot;Mesa: The New Linux OpenGL ABI Is Nearing Reality&quot;&gt;The New Linux OpenGL ABI Is Nearing Reality&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ4MzI&quot; title=&quot;Mesa: Mesa 10.0 Is Declared: OpenGL 3.2 Comes For Intel Linux&quot;&gt;Mesa 10.0 Is Declared: OpenGL 3.2 Comes For Intel Linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ3NjY&quot; title='Mozilla: Mozilla Pushes &quot;Shumway&quot; Flash Into Firefox'&gt;Mozilla Pushes &quot;Shumway&quot; Flash Into Firefox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUzOTk&quot; title=&quot;Mozilla: Mozilla Firefox 26 Is Shipping Today With Fun Features&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox 26 Is Shipping Today With Fun Features&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ5Nzk&quot; title=&quot;Mozilla: Firefox 25 Now Shipping With Minor Enhancements&quot;&gt;Firefox 25 Now Shipping With Minor Enhancements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ2NDM&quot; title=&quot;Multimedia: VLC Media Player Adds Support For H.265 / HEVC&quot;&gt;VLC Media Player Adds Support For H.265 / HEVC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ4Njg&quot; title=&quot;Multimedia: FFmpeg Now Supports HEVC/H.265 Decoding&quot;&gt;FFmpeg Now Supports HEVC/H.265 Decoding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ5NzU&quot; title=&quot;Multimedia: FFmpeg 2.1 Supports VP9, HEVC, PulseAudio Output&quot;&gt;FFmpeg 2.1 Supports VP9, HEVC, PulseAudio Output&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUzODU&quot; title=&quot;Nouveau: NVIDIA Helping Nouveau With Video Decoding&quot;&gt;NVIDIA Helping Nouveau With Video Decoding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ3MTU&quot; title=&quot;Nouveau: Nouveau Keeps Pushing Forward With Improvements&quot;&gt;Nouveau Keeps Pushing Forward With Improvements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ3OTY&quot; title='Nouveau: Reverse-Engineering Could Yield A Linux NV &quot;PerfKit&quot;'&gt;Reverse-Engineering Could Yield A Linux NV &quot;PerfKit&quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ3NDE&quot; title=&quot;NVIDIA: NVIDIA Drops Linux Driver Feature Not Found On Windows&quot;&gt;NVIDIA Drops Linux Driver Feature Not Found On Windows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ2NzY&quot; title=&quot;NVIDIA: NVIDIA To Begin Publishing Open GPU Documentation&quot;&gt;NVIDIA To Begin Publishing Open GPU Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ3NzA&quot; title=&quot;NVIDIA: NVIDIA Releases Major Linux Driver With New Features, EGL&quot;&gt;NVIDIA Releases Major Linux Driver With New Features, EGL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUyMDE&quot; title=&quot;Operating Systems: UEFI Makes It Easy To Boot Rust Applications&quot;&gt;UEFI Makes It Easy To Boot Rust Applications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUyOTQ&quot; title=&quot;Operating Systems: Genode OS 13.11 Brings Many Fantastic Features&quot;&gt;Genode OS 13.11 Brings Many Fantastic Features&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUzMjg&quot; title=&quot;Oracle: Benchmarking Oracle's Unbreakable Enterprise Kernel&quot;&gt;Benchmarking Oracle's Unbreakable Enterprise Kernel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUzMTg&quot; title=&quot;Phoronix: December Should Be Very Exciting For Linux Users&quot;&gt;December Should Be Very Exciting For Linux Users&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUwMDI&quot; title=&quot;Phoronix: Linux 3.12, Ubuntu Spooked Users This Month&quot;&gt;Linux 3.12, Ubuntu Spooked Users This Month&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUzMTI&quot; title=&quot;Phoronix: Linux 3.13, NVIDIA GPUs Won Over November&quot;&gt;Linux 3.13, NVIDIA GPUs Won Over November&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ3MTY&quot; title=&quot;Red Hat: NVIDIA, Red Hat Partner Up For New Graphics Project&quot;&gt;NVIDIA, Red Hat Partner Up For New Graphics Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUxMzI&quot; title=&quot;Red Hat: Red Hat Puts Out Ceylon 1.0 Language, Compiler&quot;&gt;Red Hat Puts Out Ceylon 1.0 Language, Compiler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ5MTU&quot; title=&quot;Red Hat: QXL SPICE X.Org Driver Supports New Features&quot;&gt;QXL SPICE X.Org Driver Supports New Features&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUxODc&quot; title=&quot;Standards: Khronos Finalizes The OpenCL 2.0 Specification&quot;&gt;Khronos Finalizes The OpenCL 2.0 Specification&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUxODg&quot; title=&quot;Standards: OpenVX 1.0: A Computer Vision Acceleration API&quot;&gt;OpenVX 1.0: A Computer Vision Acceleration API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUyMDA&quot; title=&quot;Standards: Khronos Keeps Advancing, Pushing Its Standards&quot;&gt;Khronos Keeps Advancing, Pushing Its Standards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ2NTY&quot; title=&quot;SUSE: OpenSUSE Looks To Switch To Btrfs For Next Release&quot;&gt;OpenSUSE Looks To Switch To Btrfs For Next Release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ4ODE&quot; title=&quot;SUSE: Why SUSE Likes The Btrfs File-System&quot;&gt;Why SUSE Likes The Btrfs File-System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ2NTU&quot; title=&quot;SUSE: OpenSUSE 13.1 Goes Into Beta With Linux 3.11&quot;&gt;OpenSUSE 13.1 Goes Into Beta With Linux 3.11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ4OTM&quot; title=&quot;Ubuntu: Ubuntu 14.04 Codename Revealed, Mir Haters Attacked&quot;&gt;Ubuntu 14.04 Codename Revealed, Mir Haters Attacked&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUxOTQ&quot; title=&quot;Ubuntu: Ubuntu 14.04 LTS Won't Be Powered By Mir&quot;&gt;Ubuntu 14.04 LTS Won't Be Powered By Mir&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ5MDI&quot; title=&quot;Ubuntu: Shuttleworth Challenged Over Mir Comments&quot;&gt;Shuttleworth Challenged Over Mir Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ2NjM&quot; title=&quot;Virtualization: VirtualBox 4.3 Beta 3 Fixes 3D, Modern Kernels&quot;&gt;VirtualBox 4.3 Beta 3 Fixes 3D, Modern Kernels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUyNzQ&quot; title=&quot;Virtualization: QEMU 1.7 Is Bringing New Features For Linux Emulation&quot;&gt;QEMU 1.7 Is Bringing New Features For Linux Emulation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ4NjA&quot; title=&quot;Virtualization: VirtualBox 4.3 Supports Multi-Touch, New OSes&quot;&gt;VirtualBox 4.3 Supports Multi-Touch, New OSes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ2NDA&quot; title=&quot;Wayland: GNOME Shell 3.10 Is Ready To Shine On Wayland&quot;&gt;GNOME Shell 3.10 Is Ready To Shine On Wayland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ2NDU&quot; title=&quot;Wayland: Raspberry Pi Is Running Well On Wayland/Weston&quot;&gt;Raspberry Pi Is Running Well On Wayland/Weston&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ3MjE&quot; title=&quot;Wayland: The State Of Wayland, Weston (September 2013)&quot;&gt;The State Of Wayland, Weston (September 2013)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ3MTE&quot; title=&quot;WINE: Wine 1.7.3 Readies D3D Command Stream Improvements&quot;&gt;Wine 1.7.3 Readies D3D Command Stream Improvements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ5NTM&quot; title=&quot;WINE: Wine 1.7.5 Has... Font, Unicode Improvements&quot;&gt;Wine 1.7.5 Has... Font, Unicode Improvements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ4MzY&quot; title=&quot;WINE: Wine 1.7.4 Continues With The D3D Command Stream&quot;&gt;Wine 1.7.4 Continues With The D3D Command Stream&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ3Nzk&quot; title=&quot;X.Org: The Re-Opened X.Org Server 1.15 Pushes Ahead&quot;&gt;The Re-Opened X.Org Server 1.15 Pushes Ahead&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTQ3NjI&quot; title=&quot;X.Org: We Have Mir &amp;amp; Wayland, But There Still Could Be X12&quot;&gt;We Have Mir &amp;amp; Wayland, But There Still Could Be X12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;phxcms_page_sub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=MTUwNTk&quot; title=&quot;X.Org: Open-Source HTML5 Terminal Emulator To Support X11&quot;&gt;Open-Source HTML5 Terminal Emulator To Support X11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
[Phoronix] Ryan Gordon's Linux Game Porting Guidance
</title>
</item>
<item>
<link>
http://paulgraham.com/cities.html
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;td width=&quot;455&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://ep.yimg.com/ca/I/paulgraham_2202_7992711&quot; width=&quot;157&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; hspace=&quot;0&quot; vspace=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Cities and Ambition&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;May 2008&lt;p&gt;
Great cities attract ambitious people.  You can sense it when you
walk around one.  In a hundred subtle ways, the city sends you a
message: you could do more; you should try harder.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The surprising thing is how different these messages can be.  New
York tells you, above all: you should make more money.  There are
other messages too, of course.  You should be hipper.  You should
be better looking.  But the clearest message is that you should be
richer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What I like about Boston (or rather Cambridge) is that the message
there is: you should be smarter.  You really should get around to
reading all those books you've been meaning to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you ask what message a city sends, you sometimes get surprising
answers.  As much as they respect brains in Silicon Valley, the
message the Valley sends is: you should be more powerful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That's not quite the same message New York sends.  Power matters
in New York too of course, but New York is pretty impressed by a
billion dollars even if you merely inherited it.  In Silicon Valley
no one would care except a few real estate agents.  What matters
in Silicon Valley is how much effect you have on the world.  The
reason people there care about Larry and Sergey is not their wealth
but the fact that they control Google, which affects practically
everyone.&lt;/p&gt;_____&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;How much does it matter what message a city sends?  Empirically,
the answer seems to be: a lot. You might think that if you had
enough strength of mind to do great things, you'd be able to transcend
your environment.  Where you live should make at most a couple
percent difference.  But if you look at the historical evidence,
it seems to matter more than that.  Most people who did great things
were clumped together in a few places where that sort of thing was
done at the time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can see how powerful cities are from something I wrote about
&lt;a href=&quot;http://paulgraham.com/taste.html&quot;&gt;earlier&lt;/a&gt;: the case of the Milanese Leonardo.  
Practically every
fifteenth century Italian painter you've heard of was from Florence,
even though Milan was just as big.  People in Florence weren't
genetically different, so you have to assume there was someone born
in Milan with as much natural ability as Leonardo.  What happened
to him?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If even someone with the same natural ability as Leonardo
couldn't beat the force of environment, do you suppose you can?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don't.  I'm fairly stubborn, but I wouldn't try to fight this
force.  I'd rather use it.  So I've thought a lot about where to
live.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'd always imagined Berkeley would be the ideal place&amp;#x2014;that
it would basically be Cambridge with good weather.  But when I
finally tried living there a couple years ago, it turned out not
to be.  The message Berkeley sends is: you should live better.  Life
in Berkeley is very civilized.  It's probably the place in America
where someone from Northern Europe would feel most at home.  But
it's not humming with ambition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In retrospect it shouldn't have been surprising that a place so
pleasant would attract people interested above all in quality of
life.  Cambridge with good weather, it turns out, is not Cambridge.
The people you find in Cambridge are not there by accident.  You
have to make sacrifices to live there.  It's expensive and somewhat
grubby, and the weather's often bad.  So the kind of people you
find in Cambridge are the kind of people who want to live where the
smartest people are, even if that means living in an expensive,
grubby place with bad weather.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As of this writing, Cambridge seems to be the intellectual capital
of the world.  I realize that seems a preposterous claim.  What
makes it true is that it's more preposterous to claim about anywhere
else.  American universities currently seem to be the best, judging
from the flow of ambitious students.  And what US city has a stronger
claim?  New York?  A fair number of smart people, but diluted by a
much larger number of neanderthals in suits.  The Bay Area has a
lot of smart people too, but again, diluted;  there are two great
universities, but they're far apart.  Harvard and MIT are practically
adjacent by West Coast standards, and they're surrounded by about
20 other colleges and universities.
[&lt;a href=&quot;http://paulgraham.com/cities.html#f1n&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cambridge as a result feels like a town whose main industry is
ideas, while New York's is finance and Silicon Valley's is startups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;_____&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you talk about cities in the sense we are, what you're really
talking about is collections of people.  For a long time cities
were the only large collections of people, so you could use the two
ideas interchangeably.  But we can see how much things are changing
from the examples I've mentioned.  New York is a classic great city.
But Cambridge is just part of a city, and Silicon Valley is not
even that.  (San Jose is not, as it sometimes claims, the capital
of Silicon Valley.  It's just 178 square miles at one end of it.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maybe the Internet will change things further.  Maybe one day the
most important community you belong to will be a virtual one, and
it won't matter where you live physically.  But I wouldn't bet on
it.  The physical world is very high bandwidth, and some of the
ways cities send you messages are quite subtle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the exhilarating things about coming back to Cambridge every
spring is walking through the streets at dusk, when you can see
into the houses.  When you walk through Palo Alto in the evening,
you see nothing but the blue glow of TVs.  In Cambridge you see
shelves full of promising-looking books.  Palo Alto was probably
much like Cambridge in 1960, but you'd never guess now that there
was a university nearby.  Now it's just one of the richer neighborhoods
in Silicon Valley. 
[&lt;a href=&quot;http://paulgraham.com/cities.html#f2n&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A city speaks to you mostly by accident&amp;#x2014;in things you see
through windows, in conversations you overhear.  It's not something
you have to seek out, but something you can't turn off.  One of the
occupational hazards of living in Cambridge is overhearing the
conversations of people who use interrogative intonation in declarative
sentences.  But on average I'll take Cambridge conversations over
New York or Silicon Valley ones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A friend who moved to Silicon Valley in the late 90s said the worst
thing about living there was the low quality of the eavesdropping.
At the time I thought she was being deliberately eccentric. Sure,
it can be interesting to eavesdrop on people, but is good quality
eavesdropping so important that it would affect where you chose to
live?  Now I understand what she meant.  The conversations you
overhear tell you what sort of people you're among.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;_____&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No matter how determined you are, it's hard not to be influenced
by the people around you.  It's not so much that you do whatever a
city expects of you, but that you get discouraged when no one around
you cares about the same things you do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's an imbalance between encouragement and discouragement like
that between gaining and losing money.  Most people overvalue
negative amounts of money: they'll work much harder to avoid losing
a dollar than to gain one.  Similarly, though there are plenty of
people strong enough to resist doing something just because that's
what one is supposed to do where they happen to be, there are few
strong enough to keep working on something no one around them cares
about.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because ambitions are to some extent incompatible and admiration
is a zero-sum game, each city tends to focus on one type of ambition.
The reason Cambridge is the intellectual capital is not just that
there's a concentration of smart people there, but that there's
nothing &lt;i&gt;else&lt;/i&gt; people there care about more.  Professors in
New York and the Bay area are second class citizens&amp;#x2014;till they
start hedge funds or startups respectively.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This suggests an answer to a question people in New York have
wondered about since the Bubble: whether New York could grow into
a startup hub to rival Silicon Valley.  One reason that's unlikely
is that someone starting a startup in New York would feel like a
second class citizen. 
[&lt;a href=&quot;http://paulgraham.com/cities.html#f3n&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;]
There's already something else people in New York admire more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the long term, that could be a bad thing for New York.  The power
of an important new technology does eventually convert to money.
So by caring more about money and less about power than Silicon
Valley, New York is recognizing the same thing, but slower.
[&lt;a href=&quot;http://paulgraham.com/cities.html#f4n&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;]
And in fact it has been losing to Silicon Valley at its own game:
the ratio of New York to California residents in the Forbes 400 has
decreased from 1.45 (81:56) when the list was first published in
1982 to .83 (73:88) in 2007.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;_____&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not all cities send a message.  Only those that are centers for
some type of ambition do.  And it can be hard to tell exactly what
message a city sends without living there.  I understand the messages
of New York, Cambridge, and Silicon Valley because I've lived for
several years in each of them.  DC and LA seem to send messages
too, but I haven't spent long enough in either to say for sure what
they are.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The big thing in LA seems to be fame.  There's an A List of people
who are most in demand right now, and what's most admired is to be
on it, or friends with those who are.  Beneath that the message is
much like New York's, though perhaps with more emphasis on physical
attractiveness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In DC the message seems to be that the most important thing is who
you know.  You want to be an insider.  In practice this seems to
work much as in LA.  There's an A List and you want to be on it or
close to those who are.  The only difference is how the A List is
selected.  And even that is not that different.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the moment, San Francisco's message seems to be the same as
Berkeley's: you should live better.  But this will change if enough
startups choose SF over the Valley.  During the Bubble that was a
predictor of failure&amp;#x2014;a self-indulgent choice, like buying
expensive office furniture.  Even now I'm suspicious when startups
choose SF.  But if enough good ones do, it stops being a self-indulgent
choice, because the center of gravity of Silicon Valley will shift
there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I haven't found anything like Cambridge for intellectual ambition.
Oxford and Cambridge (England) feel like Ithaca or Hanover: the
message is there, but not as strong.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paris was once a great intellectual center.  If you went there in
1300, it might have sent the message Cambridge does now.  But I
tried living there for a bit last year, and the ambitions of the
inhabitants are not intellectual ones.  The message Paris sends now
is: do things with style.  I liked that, actually.  Paris is the
only city I've lived in where people genuinely cared about art.  In
America only a few rich people buy original art, and even the more
sophisticated ones rarely get past judging it by the brand name of
the artist.  But looking through windows at dusk in Paris you can
see that people there actually care what paintings look like.
Visually, Paris has the best eavesdropping I know. 
[&lt;a href=&quot;http://paulgraham.com/cities.html#f5n&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's one more message I've heard from cities: in London you can
still (barely) hear the message that one should be more aristocratic.
If you listen for it you can also hear it in Paris, New York, and
Boston.  But this message is everywhere very faint.  It would have
been strong 100 years ago, but now I probably wouldn't have picked
it up at all if I hadn't deliberately tuned in to that wavelength
to see if there was any signal left.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;_____&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So far the complete list of messages I've picked up from cities is:
wealth, style, hipness, physical attractiveness, fame, political
power, economic power, intelligence, social class, and quality of
life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My immediate reaction to this list is that it makes me slightly
queasy.  I'd always considered ambition a good thing, but I realize
now that was because I'd always implicitly understood it to mean
ambition in the areas I cared about.  When you list everything
ambitious people are ambitious about, it's not so pretty.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On closer examination I see a couple things on the list that are
surprising in the light of history.  For example, physical
attractiveness wouldn't have been there 100 years ago (though it
might have been 2400 years ago).  It has always mattered for women,
but in the late twentieth century it seems to have started to matter
for men as well.  I'm not sure why&amp;#x2014;probably some combination
of the increasing power of women, the increasing influence of actors
as models, and the fact that so many people work in offices now:
you can't show off by wearing clothes too fancy to wear in a factory,
so you have to show off with your body instead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hipness is another thing you wouldn't have seen on the list 100
years ago.  Or wouldn't you?  What it means is to know what's what.
So maybe it has simply replaced the component of social class that
consisted of being &quot;au fait.&quot;  That could explain why hipness seems
particularly admired in London: it's version 2 of the traditional
English delight in obscure codes that only insiders understand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Economic power would have been on the list 100 years ago, but what
we mean by it is changing.  It used to mean the control of vast
human and material resources.  But increasingly it means the ability
to direct the course of technology, and some of the people in a
position to do that are not even rich&amp;#x2014;leaders of important
open source projects, for example.  The Captains of Industry of
times past had laboratories full of clever people cooking up new
technologies for them.  The new breed are themselves those people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As this force gets more attention, another is dropping off the list:
social class.  I think the two changes are related.  Economic power,
wealth, and social class are just names for the same thing at
different stages in its life: economic power converts to wealth,
and wealth to social class.  So the focus of admiration is simply
shifting upstream.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;_____&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Does anyone who wants to do great work have to live in a great city?
No; all great cities inspire some sort of ambition, but they aren't
the only places that do.  For some kinds of work, all you need is
a handful of talented colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What cities provide is an audience, and a funnel for peers.  These
aren't so critical in something like math or physics, where no
audience matters except your peers, and judging ability is sufficiently
straightforward that hiring and admissions committees can do it
reliably.  In a field like math or physics all you need is a
department with the right colleagues in it.  It could be anywhere&amp;#x2014;in
Los Alamos, New Mexico, for example.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's in fields like the arts or writing or technology that the
larger environment matters.  In these the best practitioners aren't
conveniently collected in a few top university departments and
research labs&amp;#x2014;partly because talent is harder to judge, and
partly because people pay for these things, so one doesn't need to
rely on teaching or research funding to support oneself.  It's in
these more chaotic fields that it helps most to be in a great city:
you need the encouragement of feeling that people around you care
about the kind of work you do, and since you have to find peers for
yourself, you need the much larger intake mechanism of a great city.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You don't have to live in a great city your whole life to benefit
from it.  The critical years seem to be the early and middle ones
of your career.  Clearly you don't have to grow up in a great city.
Nor does it seem to matter if you go to college in one.  To most
college students a world of a few thousand people seems big enough.
Plus in college you don't yet have to face the hardest kind of
work&amp;#x2014;discovering new problems to solve.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's when you move on to the next and much harder step that it helps
most to be in a place where you can find peers and encouragement.
You seem to be able to leave, if you want, once you've found both.
The Impressionists show the typical pattern: they were born all
over France (Pissarro was born in the Carribbean) and died all over
France, but what defined them were the years they spent together
in Paris.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;_____&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unless you're sure what you want to do and where the leading center
for it is, your best bet is probably to try living in several
places when you're young.  You can never tell what message a city
sends till you live there, or even whether it still sends one.
Often your information will be wrong: I tried living in Florence
when I was 25, thinking it would be an art center, but it turned
out I was 450 years too late.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even when a city is still a live center of ambition, you won't know
for sure whether its message will resonate with you till you hear
it.  When I moved to New York, I was very excited at first.  It's
an exciting place.  So it took me quite a while to realize I just
wasn't like the people there.  I kept searching for the Cambridge
of New York.  It turned out it was way, way uptown: an hour uptown
by air.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some people know at 16 what sort of work they're going to do, but
in most ambitious kids, ambition seems to precede anything specific
to be ambitious about.  They know they want to do something great.
They just haven't decided yet whether they're going to be a rock
star or a brain surgeon.  There's nothing wrong with that.  But it
means if you have this most common type of ambition, you'll probably
have to figure out where to live by trial and error.  You'll
probably have to find the city where you feel at home to know what sort of
ambition you have.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Notes&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&quot;f1n&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;]
This is one of the advantages of not having the universities
in your country controlled by the government.  When governments
decide how to allocate resources, political deal-making causes
things to be spread out geographically.  No central goverment would
put its two best universities in the same town, unless it was the
capital (which would cause other problems).  But scholars seem to
like to cluster together as much as people in any other field, and
when given the freedom to they derive the same advantages from it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&quot;f2n&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;]
There are still a few old professors in Palo Alto, but one by
one they die and their houses are transformed by developers into
McMansions and sold to VPs of Bus Dev.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&quot;f3n&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;]
How many times have you read about startup founders who continued
to live inexpensively as their companies took off?  Who continued
to dress in jeans and t-shirts, to drive the old car they had in
grad school, and so on?  If you did that in New York, people would
treat you like shit.  If you walk into a fancy restaurant in San
Francisco wearing a jeans and a t-shirt, they're nice to you; who
knows who you might be?  Not in New York.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One sign of a city's potential as a technology center is the number
of restaurants that still require jackets for men.  According to
Zagat's there are none in San Francisco, LA, Boston, or Seattle, 
4 in DC, 6 in Chicago, 8 in London, 13 in New York, and 20 in Paris.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Zagat's lists the Ritz Carlton Dining Room in SF as requiring jackets
but I couldn't believe it, so I called to check and in fact they
don't. Apparently there's only one restaurant left on the entire West
Coast that still requires jackets: The French Laundry in Napa Valley.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&quot;f4n&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;]
Ideas are one step upstream from economic power, so it's
conceivable that intellectual centers like Cambridge will one day
have an edge over Silicon Valley like the one the Valley has over
New York.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This seems unlikely at the moment; if anything Boston is falling
further and further behind.  The only reason I even mention the
possibility is that the path from ideas to startups has recently
been getting smoother.  It's a lot easier now for a couple of hackers
with no business experience to start a startup than it was 10 years
ago.  If you extrapolate another 20 years, maybe the balance of
power will start to shift back.  I wouldn't bet on it, but I wouldn't
bet against it either.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&quot;f5n&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;]
If Paris is where people care most about art, why is New York
the center of gravity of the art business?  Because in the twentieth
century, art as brand split apart from art as stuff.  New York is
where the richest buyers are, but all they demand from art is brand,
and since you can base brand on anything with a sufficiently
identifiable style, you may as well use the local stuff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Thanks&lt;/b&gt; to Trevor Blackwell, Sarah Harlin, Jessica Livingston,
Jackie McDonough, Robert Morris, and David Sloo for reading drafts
of this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Cities and Ambition (2008)
</title>
</item>
<item>
<link>
http://techcrunch.com/2014/01/18/why-silicon-valley-cant-find-europe/
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-entry text&quot;&gt;


&lt;img src=&quot;http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2014/01/shutterstock_162097541.jpg?w=738&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor&amp;#x2019;s note:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#xA0;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.crunchbase.com/person/sten-kamkivi&quot;&gt;Sten Tamkivi&lt;/a&gt; has been a software entrepreneur for 16 years and spent the recent half of his career as an early executive at Skype in Tallinn, Estonia. Sten is now an Entrepreneur in Residence at &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.crunchbase.com/financial-organization/andreessen-horowitz&quot;&gt;Andreessen Horowitz&lt;/a&gt;. Follow him on his &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://sten.tamkivi.com/&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#xA0;and on Twitter &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/seikatsu&quot;&gt;@seikatsu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to Europe these days &amp;#x2013; to Berlin, London, Helsinki &amp;#x2013; drop in on any of the regional tech confabs and you will quickly see&amp;#xA0;that the European startup scene is in the most bustling, vibrant shape it&amp;#x2019;s ever been. The potential is everywhere, and the energy is undeniable. Then you return Stateside, in my case to Palo Alto, and Europe isn&amp;#x2019;t just irrelevant among the tech industry power-set. It has virtually ceased to exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is a mistake. Blame for the ruptured relationship lies on both sides of the Atlantic, but it is Europeans that have the power, and should have the motivation, to mend things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x2019;m proud to be Estonian and European, but recently realized that very soon I will have been living in California for 10 percent of my life. I had a front-row seat to the first Internet boom as an exchange student at the super-wired Monta Vista High School in Apple&amp;#x2019;s backyard. I returned to the U.S. with some frequency initially as an executive with Skype, and later to pursue a business degree at Stanford. My latest perch in Silicon Valley today is as an entrepreneur-in-residence with venture capital firm Andreessen Horowitz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me give you a small taste of the way Europe was woven into the discussion at Stanford&amp;#x2019;s Graduate School of Business. Over the course of four quarters I heard one professor make one joke about short-term macroeconomic troubles in Greece. We also had a visit from a well-dressed and charming British banker in our private equity class. That&amp;#x2019;s it. No European startups, no cases of European success stories or failures. A joke and a banker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few isolated examples of systematic bridge building, like the fantastic five-years-running European Entrepreneurship seminar at Stanford&amp;#x2019;s Engineering school can fulfill targeted curiosity, but Europe is not visible as a theme in other classes across the curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Important Places&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x2019;m not blaming Stanford. In talking to many people about my growing realization that the place of my birth simply didn&amp;#x2019;t matter to most people in the Valley, I began to understand that there is a mental hierarchy of &amp;#x201C;important places&amp;#x201D; for people building, investing in and studying tech companies in Silicon Valley. They exist in the following order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Silicon Valley.&lt;/strong&gt; Practically considered, the opportunity cost of venturing out of the bustling 30-mile radius of Sand Hill Road, whether you are an entrepreneur, investor or academic, is usually just too high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The U.S. East Coast.&lt;/strong&gt; Yes, stuff is happening in Boston and New York, but not so much that a once-a-month trip can&amp;#x2019;t cover most of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. China.&lt;/strong&gt; Massive tech companies do rise in China and go public in the United States, and Chinese investors have gobs of cash to invest in the Valley. There is a constant back and forth between both Pacific coasts. But it&amp;#x2019;s not just geography, and the historic manufacturing relationship that is stimulating this cozy dynamic. The Valley is looking more and more towards China for the next tech trends and expansion opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. The rest of Asia.&lt;/strong&gt; India&amp;#x2019;s diaspora links to the U.S. are strong. Southeast Asia&amp;#x2019;s growth is hard to miss, and there is interesting mobile stuff happening in Korea and Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Latin America/South America.&lt;/strong&gt; Markets in Mexico and Brazil are increasingly ripe for Silicon Valley tech, but the region is still a distant gleam for most companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Europe.&lt;/strong&gt; Here is what I mostly hear about Europe: &amp;#x201C;I took my wife/husband to Paris last year for our anniversary, and we dropped by Rome. Great food, so much history, Europe is wonderful!&amp;#x201D; For vacation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than relying solely on my anecdotal examples of &amp;#x201C;important places,&amp;#x201D; I turned to LinkedIn. Mapping my network through the lens of the topic at hand, I can confirm that, while Estonia, the Nordics and Europe in general comprise a tightly knit blue blob, and Skype in Estonia (orange) and internationally (green) is an organism in itself, the Silicon Valley venture capital and serial entrepreneurship circles float as a distant burgundy cloud. And the international graduate student and teacher body of Stanford is even further out on the right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2014/01/sten-tamkivi-europe-map.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter  wp-image-941576&quot; alt=&quot;Sten Tamkivi Europe map&quot; src=&quot;http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2014/01/sten-tamkivi-europe-map.jpg?w=1024&amp;amp;h=625&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those familiar with Granovetter&amp;#x2019;s theory about the strength of weak ties should feel a wave of joy here. Sure, there are benefits of weak ties, but then again, there are virtues to tight-knit communities talking to each other frequently, sharing the successes and learning from each other&amp;#x2019;s mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that is exactly what is missing between the U.S. and Europe &amp;#x2014; a real bridge. So how do we build one, and what can both partners in constructing this connection hope to gain?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#x2019;s start with Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Why the Hell Are You in Silicon Valley?&amp;#xA0;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;And Don&amp;#x2019;t Say It&amp;#x2019;s the Money&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raising money tends to be the No. 1 rationale from founders when asked why they&amp;#x2019;re in the Valley. It&amp;#x2019;s also the No. 1 mistake people make. You will be far more successful raising seed and early-stage VC financing close to home, on whichever side of the Atlantic it may be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, the internationalization of the venture capital industry is well on its way, and one can draw quite pretty graphs of the increasing money flow across the globe. Bollocks. Here&amp;#x2019;s why you, European entrepreneur, aren&amp;#x2019;t going to get that money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at closed early-stage deals listings in Pitchbook, it is very clear that U.S.-based VCs invest in U.S. companies, and European VCs invest in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-941577&quot; alt=&quot;Tamkivi chart&quot; src=&quot;http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2014/01/tamkivi-chart.jpg?w=1024&amp;amp;h=576&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my experience, this mindset applies to institutional investors in a clearly structured way, but is a notable behavior even for private angels in AngelList. Investors believe that there is much more that they bring to the table than just money &amp;#x2013; but that ineffable &amp;#x201C;value&amp;#x201D; is hard to bring across long distances and multiple time zones. No matter how much the video calling has improved, board seats, hiring networks, corporate development efforts and just quick (unscheduled!) calls work much better in proximity. Raise your money at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of building a solid bridge with the U.S. is having a solid reason for being here, other than money.&amp;#xA0;Selfies&amp;#xA0;at Infinite Loop Drive and group pictures in front of Facebook and Google headquarters don&amp;#x2019;t count.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One good reason for touching down at SFO might be that it&amp;#x2019;s because the companies that matter in your space &amp;#x2013; the&amp;#xA0;ones you want to compete with, learn from, partner with or steal bored employees from &amp;#x2013;&amp;#xA0;are in Silicon Valley. Ditto for customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, you need to honestly evaluate decamping from Europe against your own personal strengths and networks. I am in the thick of things on Sand Hill Road. Yet that relative advantage doesn&amp;#x2019;t change the fact that I have been building software companies for 16 years in Estonia and worked mostly with teams around Scandinavia and in Prague or London. This is where the best engineers I know are. This is the core of my network. This is my actual unfair home-court advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anything makes me stay Stateside, it must far outweigh the strongholds I&amp;#x2019;m leaving behind. That applies to every European (indeed everyone wherever they are from) pondering a move to Silicon Valley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Why Silicon Valley Should Love Europe Back&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if exchanging money for equity isn&amp;#x2019;t the way to create tighter bonds between Europe and the Valley, the question becomes: how can we build more&amp;#xA0;&lt;i&gt;non-financial&lt;/i&gt;&amp;#xA0;ties between our scenes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When building high-value ties in any network, the question should never be what you&amp;#xA0;&lt;i&gt;get&lt;/i&gt;, but rather what can you&amp;#xA0;&lt;i&gt;give&lt;/i&gt;&amp;#xA0;to the other party? What can you help with? What can you teach? What can you spare? This tends to be true with your friends, your community, and your country &amp;#x2013;&amp;#xA0; and how you ought to think about transatlantic relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we Europeans can muster the confidence, and the U.S. can tone down its arrogance, Europe actually has a lot to give to Silicon Valley. Here are just a few examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talent.&lt;/strong&gt; Silicon Valley&amp;#x2019;s weakest spot today is finding enough good engineers and designers. The European contribution here in the simplest case is talent. The next level of complexity, but more sustainable for both sides, are development outposts across the pond. This could also take the form of M&amp;amp;A targets that Europe could offer &amp;#x2013; something that Meg Whitman in her eBay CEO days used to call &amp;#x201C;off-balance-sheet R&amp;amp;D&amp;#x201D; when buying up another innovative marketplace team in the Netherlands or Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about making this a two-way street, and providing interesting-timed job adventures for early-career Valley experts? Why be the 3,481st guy in Facebook, when during a three-year stint in a cool European city you can be No.1 in the entire country in what you do? Yes, moving American hotshots to Europe can be a tough sell, but we did it successfully at Skype, and companies like Soundcloud are doing it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sharing new models.&lt;/strong&gt; For any European who has spent an extended time here, Silicon Valley can often feel surprisingly backwards. When it comes to online and mobile applications truly embedded in how people go about their daily chores, how they sign and exchange legal documents, how they interact with the government, how they do their consumer banking, how they receive services from their doctors and so forth, many places in Europe are light years ahead of what is widely available in the U.S. We can share those ideas and expertise.&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;400 million customers.&lt;/strong&gt; For most&amp;#xA0;successful entrepreneurial ventures, there comes a day when growth needs to be found outside of the home market. And no matter how much the mobile handset makers talk about the next billion people coming online in Africa, and how lucrative the already-online billions of users in Asia are, the most common scenario for the Groupons and Airbnbs and Ubers of the foreseeable future is still to figure out their expansion strategy for the U.K., Germany and France.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe is still the rational next market for most U.S. rocket ships who are looking to find customers with above-average incomes and access to credit cards who live on infrastructure you can deliver your products and services to. Who better&lt;b&gt;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/b&gt;to help U.S. entrepreneurs crack Europe than Europeans?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global skills.&lt;/strong&gt; The value of understanding foreign markets does not stop with Europe, though. Far too much of U.S.-originated innovation is born in the form of English-language, iOS-only apps with hard-coded dollar signs. European entrepreneurs, especially those from the smallest countries, are much better trained at operating globally in multi-currency, multi-cultural markets. As a proof point, look at how the likes of Finnish Rovio (Angry Birds) and Supercell (Clash of Clans) or Skypers in London or Tallinn and Evernoters in Z&amp;#xFC;rich or Moscow have conquered the astonishingly tough Chinese and Japanese markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security and privacy.&lt;/strong&gt; In the post-Snowden days we&amp;#x2019;re living in, there is a new set of questions around the physical and legal location of users&amp;#x2019; data and the regulations governing its privacy. Although the rules and behaviors driving this have been evolving in a U.S.-centric way thanks to U.S.-based Internet giants, if you look at where the&amp;#xA0;&lt;i&gt;users&lt;/i&gt;&amp;#xA0;of the Internet live today,&amp;#xA0;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_number_of_Internet_users&quot;&gt;less than 10 percent&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#xA0;of them are in the United States. And that share is declining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is obvious that nations other than the U.S. will have an increasing say in the governance mechanisms and regulation of the system with Europe at the forefront. And this is not just a government thing. The European tech scene can help its U.S. peers figure things out as private entities first.&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we Europeans can follow through with an approach of giving something unique and valuable, as opposed to just trying to get funding from the other side, I believe the European and Silicon Valley tech scenes have a shot at moving closer together. For U.S. players, this would presume paying a little bit more attention to the world outside. For Europeans, it&amp;#x2019;s mustering a bit more confidence in ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sure more non-financial bridges can be built. And as it&amp;#xA0;&lt;a&gt;has been shown by some VC investment-related research&lt;/a&gt;: Cold hard cash will eventually follow the international corridors where smart people are already on the move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Image: &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.shutterstock.com&quot;&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;


								
							&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Why Silicon Valley Can’t Find Europe
</title>
</item>
<item>
<author>
ROBERT HARRIS
</author>
<link>
http://www.nytimes.com/2014/01/18/opinion/the-whistle-blower-who-freed-dreyfus.html
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;article id=&quot;story&quot; class=&quot;story theme-main&quot;&gt;

    

    
    

                
    &lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;KINTBURY, England &amp;#x2014; Georges Picquart died 100 years ago this Saturday. To which the response from most quarters is likely to be &amp;#x201C;Georges who?&amp;#x201D; Even in his native France, his centenary is passing largely unremarked. Yet in the days of Queen Victoria and Theodore Roosevelt, Picquart was a figure of global controversy, revered and reviled in equal measure as the world&amp;#x2019;s most famous whistle-blower. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;Unlike his 21st-century counterparts Bradley Manning and Edward Snowden, Picquart was neither a disaffected nor a junior figure in the organization he was to expose. On the contrary: In October 1894 he was a brilliant, rising army officer. One of his steppingstones to advancement had been a professorship at the &amp;#xC9;cole Sup&amp;#xE9;rieure de Guerre, and one of the officer-cadets he had taught there was a Jewish artillery captain, Alfred Dreyfus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;Picquart, like many of his contemporaries, was casually anti-Semitic. It came as no surprise to him when Dreyfus &amp;#x2014; the only Jew on the general staff &amp;#x2014; was suspected of passing secret intelligence to the Germans. It was Picquart who provided a sample of Dreyfus&amp;#x2019;s handwriting to the investigators. And when expert analysis seemed to confirm Dreyfus&amp;#x2019;s guilt, it was Picquart who met his unsuspecting former pupil in the Ministry of War so he could be quietly bundled off to prison.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media photo embedded has-adjacency layout-large-horizontal&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;http://static01.nyt.com/images/2014/01/18/opinion/18harris/18harris-articleLarge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;media-viewer-candidate&quot;&gt;
            &lt;meta value=&quot;http://static01.nyt.com/images/2014/01/18/opinion/18harris/18harris-articleLarge.jpg&quot;&gt;
            &lt;meta value=&quot;548&quot;&gt;
            &lt;meta value=&quot;600&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;In December, Picquart attended Dreyfus&amp;#x2019;s court-martial as an official observer. For reasons of national security it was held behind closed doors. When told that a file of intelligence evidence existed, conclusively proving Dreyfus&amp;#x2019;s guilt, Picquart supported the decision to show it in secret to the judges.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;The file clinched the conviction. Dreyfus was sentenced to life imprisonment. On Jan. 5, 1895, before a crowd of 20,000 shouting, &amp;#x201C;Death to the Jew!&amp;#x201D; Dreyfus had his sword broken and the insignia of his rank torn from his uniform. Observing the spectacle, Picquart remarked laconically to a fellow officer: &amp;#x201C;He&amp;#x2019;s a Jew, don&amp;#x2019;t forget that. He&amp;#x2019;s thinking of the weight of the gold braid and how much it&amp;#x2019;s worth.&amp;#x201D; In March, Dreyfus was transported to Devil&amp;#x2019;s Island, off the coast of South America, where he was denied all human contact, including conversation with his guards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;Picquart, meanwhile, prospered. Six months later, at age 40, he was made the youngest colonel in the French Army and put in charge of the tiny intelligence unit, known as the Statistical Section, that had compiled the evidence against Dreyfus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;The section&amp;#x2019;s prize agent was a cleaner at the German Embassy, Marie Bastian, who supplied the contents of the wastepaper basket of the military attach&amp;#xE9;, Col. Maximilian von Schwartzkoppen. It was she who was the source of the &amp;#x201C;bordereau&amp;#x201D; &amp;#x2014; the note that an expert had concluded was in Dreyfus&amp;#x2019;s hand. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;Nine months into Picquart&amp;#x2019;s tenure, Bastian passed on a pneumatic telegram card &amp;#x2014; a &amp;#x201C;petit bleu&amp;#x201D; &amp;#x2014; that von Schwartzkoppen had torn into 40 fragments. Glued together, the telegram revealed that the German attach&amp;#xE9; was receiving intelligence from a serving French officer, Maj. Charles Ferdinand Walsin Esterhazy. Picquart immediately put Esterhazy under surveillance. He turned out to have the classic profile of a spy: a drunkard, a gambler, heavily indebted, and leading a double life with a prostitute in Montmartre. Moreover, he was dangerously active: He had recently applied for a job in the general staff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;Sitting in his office, Picquart compared Esterhazy&amp;#x2019;s letters with the bordereau. &amp;#x201C;I was terrified,&amp;#x201D; he testified later. &amp;#x201C;The two writings were not similar; they were identical.&amp;#x201D; The next day he showed them to the handwriting expert, Alphonse Bertillon, whose evidence had helped convict Dreyfus. Bertillon confirmed Esterhazy&amp;#x2019;s writing was a perfect match, but saw no reason to revise his original judgment: &amp;#x201C;It merely shows that the Jews have trained someone else to write using the Dreyfus system.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;Picquart&amp;#x2019;s next step was to inspect the intelligence that had been passed to Dreyfus&amp;#x2019;s judges. &amp;#x201C;I took possession of the secret file for the first time since my entry into the service. I confess that my amazement was profound. I was expecting overwhelming evidence. I found nothing.&amp;#x201D; Indeed, such scant evidence as there was had plainly been fabricated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;Picquart took his discoveries to the chief of the French general staff, Gen. Raoul de Boisdeffre, and to the overall head of military intelligence, Gen. Charles-Arthur Gonse. Their reaction appalled him. He was told to avoid any avenues of inquiry that might lead to a reopening of the Dreyfus case. &amp;#x201C;What does it matter to you,&amp;#x201D; demanded Gonse, &amp;#x201C;if one Jew stays on Devil&amp;#x2019;s Island?&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;&amp;#x201C;Well,&amp;#x201D; replied Picquart, &amp;#x201C;because he&amp;#x2019;s innocent ...&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;He pressed on with his investigation, to the irritation of his superiors. Two months later, he was relieved of his duties. By the spring of 1897, he was an exile, transferred to a native regiment in Tunisia on what amounted to a near-suicidal mission into the southern Sahara.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;It was then that Picquart, after 25 years&amp;#x2019; army service, realized he had no alternative but to break ranks. He passed his evidence against Esterhazy to a senior politician, the vice president of the senate, Auguste Scheurer-Kestner. Then, at the end of 1897, he provided &amp;#xC9;mile Zola with the information that enabled the novelist to write his celebrated expos&amp;#xE9; of the affair, &amp;#x201C;J&amp;#x2019;Accuse ...!&amp;#x201D; Picquart&amp;#x2019;s reward was to be dismissed from the army, framed as a forger and locked up in solitary confinement for more than a year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;It was not until 1906 that justice was finally done; Dreyfus&amp;#x2019;s conviction was quashed, and Picquart was restored to the army with the rank of brigadier general. That fall, when his friend and fellow Dreyfusard, Georges Clemenceau &amp;#x2014; the owner of the newspaper that published &amp;#x201C;J&amp;#x2019;Accuse ...!&amp;#x201D; became prime minister, he made Picquart minister of war, a post he held for three years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;On Jan. 18, 1914, six months before the outbreak of the First World War, while in command of the Second Army Corps at Amiens, Picquart died of edema of the face &amp;#x2014; effectively, suffocation &amp;#x2014; following a riding accident. He was 59. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;He had no family to preserve his memory: A bachelor with a succession of married mistresses, he left no children. A large section of the army never forgave him for betraying his comrades. And some of Dreyfus&amp;#x2019;s supporters continued to accuse him of anti-Semitism. An awkward figure in death as well as life, he slipped through the cracks of history.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;And yet the injustices against which he fought so courageously &amp;#x2014; the inherent unreliability of secret courts and secret evidence, the dangers of rogue intelligence agencies becoming laws unto themselves, the instinctive response of governments and national security organizations to cover up their mistakes, the easy flourishing of &amp;#x201C;national security&amp;#x201D; to stifle democratic scrutiny &amp;#x2014; all these continue. &amp;#x201C;Dreyfus was the victim,&amp;#x201D; Clemenceau observed, &amp;#x201C;but Picquart was the hero.&amp;#x201D; On this day, he deserves to be remembered. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt; &lt;em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Robert Harris&lt;/em&gt; is the author of a forthcoming novel about Georges Picquart, &amp;#x201C;An Officer and a Spy.&amp;#x201D; &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;footer class=&quot;story-footer story-content&quot;&gt;
        
    &lt;/footer&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
The Whistle-Blower Who Freed Dreyfus
</title>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
