<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version='2.0'>
<channel>
<generator>
clj-rss
</generator>
<link>
https://news.ycombinator.com
</link>
<title>
myread
</title>
<description>
myread
</description>
<item>
<link>
http://blog.samaltman.com/super-successful-companies
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-body&quot; id=&quot;post_body_642280&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent some time recently thinking about what companies that grow up to be extremely successful do when they are very young. I came up with the following list. It&amp;#x2019;s from personal experience and I&amp;#x2019;m sure there are plenty of exceptions. While plenty of non-successful startups do some of these things too, I think there is value in trying to match the patterns.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;*&lt;b&gt;They are obsessed with the quality of the product/experience.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/b&gt;Almost a little too obsessed&amp;#x2014;they spend a lot of time on details that at first glance wouldn&amp;#x2019;t seem to be really important.&amp;#xA0; The founders of these companies react as if they feel physical pain when something isn&amp;#x2019;t quite right with the product or a user has a bad customer support experience.&lt;b&gt;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/b&gt;Although they believe in launching early and iterating, they generally won't release something crappy. (This is not an excuse to launch slowly.&amp;#xA0; You're probably taking too long to launch.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As part of this, they don't put anyone between the founders and the users.&amp;#xA0; The founders of these companies do things like sales and customer support themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;*&lt;b&gt;They are obsessed with talent.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/b&gt;The founders take great pride in the quality of their team and do whatever it takes to get the best people to join them.&amp;#xA0; Everyone says they only want to hire the best people, but the best founders don't compromise on this point.&amp;#xA0; If they do make a hiring mistake, they fix it very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And they hire very slowly.&amp;#xA0; They don't get any thrill out of having employees for its own sake, and they do the dirty work themselves at the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As part of this, they really focus on getting the culture of the company right.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;*They can explain the vision for the company in a few clear words.&lt;/b&gt;&amp;#xA0;This is most striking in contrast to companies that require multiple complicated sentences to explain, which never seem to do really well.&amp;#xA0; Also, they can articulate why they're going to succeed even if others going after the problem have failed, and they have a clear insight about why their market is a great one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More generally, they communicate very well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;*They generate revenue very early on in their lives.&amp;#xA0;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/b&gt;Often as soon as they get their first user.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;*They are tough and calm&lt;/b&gt;.&amp;#xA0; Founders of great companies are always tough and unflappable.&amp;#xA0; Every startup seems like it's going to die--sometimes multiple times in a single day--and founders of really successful companies just seem to pull out a gun and shoot the villain&amp;#xA0;without losing their train of thought.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Formidableness can be developed; I've seen weak-seeming founders grow into it fast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;*They keep expenses low.&amp;#xA0;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/b&gt;In addition to hiring slowly, they start off very frugal. Interestingly, the companies that don't do this (and usually fail) often justify it by saying &quot;we're thinking really big&quot;. &amp;#xA0;After everything is working really well, they will sometimes ramp up expenses a lot but manage to still only spend where it matters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;*They make something a small number of users really love.&lt;/b&gt;&amp;#xA0;Paul Buchheit was the first person I ever heard point this out, but it's really true.&amp;#xA0; Successful startups nearly always start with an initial core of super happy users that become very dependent on their product, and then expand from there.&amp;#xA0; The strategy of something that starts with something a huge number of people sort of like empirically does not work as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;*They grow organically.&amp;#xA0;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/b&gt;And they are generally skeptical of inorganic strategies like big partnership deals and to a lesser extent PR.&amp;#xA0; They certainly don't have huge press events to launch their startup.&amp;#xA0; Mediocre founders focus on big PR launches to answer their growth prayers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;*They are focused on growth.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/b&gt;The founders always know their user and revenue numbers.&amp;#xA0; There&amp;#x2019;s never any hesitation when you ask them.&amp;#xA0; They have targets they are trying to hit for the next week, month, and year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;*&lt;b&gt;They balance a focus on growth with strategic thinking about the future.&amp;#xA0;&amp;#xA0;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/b&gt;They have clear plans and strong opinions about what they're going to build that no one can talk them out of.&amp;#xA0; But they focus more on execution in the moment than building out multi-year strategic plans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another way this trait shows itself is &quot;right-sized&quot; first projects.&amp;#xA0; You can't go from zero to huge; you have to find something not too big and not too small to build first.&amp;#xA0; They seem to have an innate talent for figuring out right-sized projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;b&gt;*They do things that don't scale.&amp;#xA0;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/b&gt;Paul Graham has&amp;#xA0;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paulgraham.com/ds.html&quot;&gt;written about this&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#xA0; The best founders take it unusually far.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;*They have a whatever-it-takes attitude.&lt;/b&gt;&amp;#xA0;There are some things about running a startup that are not fun.&amp;#xA0; Mediocre founders try to hire people for the parts that they don't like.&amp;#xA0; Great founders just do whatever they think is in the best interest of the company, even if they're not &quot;passionate&quot; about that part of the business.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;*They prioritize well&lt;/b&gt;.&amp;#xA0; In any given day there are 100 reasonable things that you could work on.&amp;#xA0; It's easy to get pulled into a fire on number 7, or even to spend time at a networking event or something like that that probably ranks in the mid-90s.&amp;#xA0; The founders that are really successful are relentless about making sure they get to their top two or three priorities each day (as part of this, they figure out what the right priorities are), and ignoring other items.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;*The founders are nice.&lt;/b&gt;&amp;#xA0; I'm sure this doesn't always apply, but the most successful founders I know are nicer than average.&amp;#xA0; They're tough, they're very competitive, and they are ruthless, but they are fundamentally nice people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;*They don't get excited about pretending to run a startup.&lt;/b&gt;&amp;#xA0; They care about being successful, not going through the motions to look successful.&amp;#xA0; They get no thrill from having a 'real' company; they don't spend a lot of time interviewing lawyers and accountants or going to network events or anything like that.&amp;#xA0; They want to win and don't care much about how they look doing so.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One reason that this is super important is that they are willing to work on things that seem trivial, like a website that lets you stay on an air mattress in someone's house.&amp;#xA0; Most of the best ideas seem like bad ideas when they start, and if you're more into appearance than substance, you won't want people laughing at you.&amp;#xA0; You are far better off starting a company that people laugh at but keeps growing relentlessly than a company with a beautiful office that seems serious but is always two quarters away from starting its growth ramp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;*They get stuff done.&lt;/b&gt;&amp;#xA0;Mediocre founders spend a lot of time talking about grand plans; the best founders may be working on things that seem small but get them done extraordinarily quickly.&amp;#xA0; Every time you talk to them, they've gotten a few new things done.&amp;#xA0; Even if they're working on big projects, they get small chunks done incrementally and have demonstratable progress--they never disappear for a year and jump from nothing to a huge project being completed.&amp;#xA0; And they're reliable--if they tell you they'll do something, it happens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;*They move fast.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/b&gt;They make quick decisions on everything.&amp;#xA0; They respond to emails quickly.&amp;#xA0; This is one of the most striking differences between great and mediocre founders.&amp;#xA0; Great founders are execution machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Super successful companies
</title>
</item>
<item>
<link>
https://stripe.com/blog/ctf3-coming-soon
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;ctf3-coming-soon&quot;&gt;

  

  &lt;p&gt;
  It's been over a year since our last &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/blog/capturetheflag&quot;&gt;Capture the Flag&lt;/a&gt;
  competition, and in the meanwhile we've fielded &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jszobody/status/423187875111268352&quot;&gt;dozens&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/micahflee/status/327171379764011008&quot;&gt;of&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/paraboul/status/363288046331891714&quot;&gt;inquiries&lt;/a&gt;
  about when the next one's coming. The wait is almost over: CTF3 will
  be here a week from today.
  &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;
  Next Wednesday, starting at &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe-ctf.com/&quot;&gt;11am San Francisco time&lt;/a&gt; (2pm
  Boston, 7pm London, 6am Melbourne), we'll be launching CTF3.
  &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;
  This time around, we're trying something a bit different. Rather than
  being about security, CTF3 will focus on distributed systems
  engineering. You'll learn how to build fault-tolerant, performant
  software while playing around with a bunch of cool cutting-edge
  technologies. Like with previous CTFs, our goal is to give you
  hands-on exposure to interesting engineering problems that you
  normally only get to read about. If you've been wanting to really &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grok&quot;&gt;grok&lt;/a&gt; things like &lt;a href=&quot;http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/um/people/lamport/pubs/paxos-simple.pdf&quot;&gt;Paxos&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://ramcloud.stanford.edu/wiki/download/attachments/11370504/raft.pdf&quot;&gt;Raft&lt;/a&gt;,
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/10/github-hit-with-another-ddos-attack-second-in-two-days-and-major-service-outage/&quot;&gt;DDOS&lt;/a&gt;
  prevention, &lt;a href=&quot;https://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/display/solr/Distributed+Search+with+Index+Sharding&quot;&gt;distributed
  search&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bitcoin&quot;&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt; (and maybe
  even &lt;a href=&quot;http://graphics.stanford.edu/~seander/bithacks.html&quot;&gt;bit
  twiddling&lt;/a&gt;), now's your chance.
  &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;
  As always, we're building this CTF for programmers of all skill levels
  and backgrounds. Even if the above sounds daunting, you should still
  give it a shot &amp;#x2014; you might be surprised by what you can
  accomplish. For those looking for some competition, there will be
  leaderboards where you can compete against your friends or the CTF
  community at large.
  &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;
  Want to meet and hack alongside your fellow CTFers in person?  While
  the main gathering will once again be based on IRC (check back for
  details next week), we'll also be hosting kickoff events in &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/events/ctf3-kickoff-sf&quot;&gt;San Francisco&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/events/ctf3-kickoff-cambridge&quot;&gt;Boston&lt;/a&gt;, and
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/events/ctf3-kickoff-london&quot;&gt;London&lt;/a&gt;.
  &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;
  Over the next week, the CTF team (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sidd&quot;&gt;Siddarth Chandrasekaran&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alberge&quot;&gt;Andy Brody&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/chranderson&quot;&gt;Christian Anderson&lt;/a&gt;, and
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thegdb&quot;&gt;I&lt;/a&gt;) will be putting the
  finishing touches on CTF3. See you on the other side!
  &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;div id=&quot;get-started&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The countdown has started. &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe-ctf.com/&quot; class=&quot;button blue medium rounded&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Notify me&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Coming soon: Stripe CTF3, distributed systems edition
</title>
</item>
<item>
<link>
https://github.com/swannodette/lt-cljs-tutorial
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;js-repo-pjax-container&quot; class=&quot;repository-content context-loader-container&quot;&gt;
          







  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/swannodette/lt-cljs-tutorial&quot; class=&quot;repository-lang-stats-graph js-toggle-lang-stats tooltipped downwards&quot; title=&quot;Show language statistics&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;language-color&quot;&gt;Clojure&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;







&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/swannodette/lt-cljs-tutorial/find/master&quot; class=&quot;js-show-file-finder&quot;&gt;Show File Finder&lt;/a&gt;


  &lt;div id=&quot;readme&quot; class=&quot;clearfix announce instapaper_body md&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;name&quot;&gt;
      
      README.md
    &lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An introduction to the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/clojure/clojurescript&quot;&gt;ClojureScript&lt;/a&gt; programming
language aimed at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lighttable.com&quot;&gt;Light Table&lt;/a&gt; users. You
can open &lt;code&gt;lt-cljs-tutorial.cljs&lt;/code&gt; in Light Table and evaluate it
interactively by adding a Light Table UI connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this can be a kind of ClojureScript wiki of sorts for Light
Table users.  Pull requests welcome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/article&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;


        &lt;/div&gt;

      &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Light Table ClojureScript Tutorial
</title>
</item>
<item>
<link>
http://kimonify.kimonolabs.com/kimload?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.kimonolabs.com%2Fwelcome.html
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-8 article-body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Web scraping. It's something we all love to hate. If you're a developer, you know what we're talking about. You wish the data you needed to power your app, model or visualization was available via API. But, most of the time it's not. So, you decide to build a web scraper. You write a ton of code, employ a laundry list of libraries and techniques, all for something that's by definition unstable, has to be hosted somewhere, and needs to be maintained over time.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;We've felt this pain, many times over. So we built kimono to do all this heavy lifting for us. We actually decided to go a step further and make it easy enough for anyone to use, not just developers. If getting access to structured data from around the web is so interesting to us, why wouldn't it be interesting to everyone else, even people who can't code? Our first step toward solving this problem is not just to make building a web scraper easy, but to add a simple app builder feature, letting users see their data in an app vs. raw JSON. In fact, my Mom is using an app she built with kimono right now to check ski conditions near Lake Tahoe.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;So, what does a web scraper for anyone really look like? Actually, you're already using it (unless you're on a mobile device, in which case you should totally come back using your computer). &lt;/p&gt;
          
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Notice how kimono self organized the data into two different collections for you? We felt it important keep things straightforward and allow users to just point and click while we figure out the underlying structure automatically. As we worked through the problem we defined a set of design principles like these that would underpin an ideal solution. We touch upon these below (more detail in blog posts to come). A good solution must:&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;ol class=&quot;axioms&quot;&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;h3&gt;Be accessible straight from the browser&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;We wanted to create something that could be used anytime, anywhere by anyone. This meant no downloads, no installs, no system requirements. The challenge was to create a way for triggering kimono on any page you are looking at in your browser of choice.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;h3&gt;Recognize relationships amongst data like a human would&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Interpreting the HTML tags and DOM hierarchy often doesn't yield the true associations and structure of the data. We therefore needed to build in enough intelligence to figure out what you really want, and how the elements you've chosen are truly associated, without you having to think about a data model or underlying structure.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;h3&gt;Be flexible enough to work across different sites and data formats&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Each web site is different and presents its own unique challenges, from truly malformed HTML to dumps of Microsoft excel / word documents and pages serving up data dynamically with AJAX.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;h3&gt;Run and be hosted in the cloud&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In order to depend on the scraped data, we'd need to be able to store caches of run jobs on cloud hosted servers and send alerts when things go wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;

        &lt;p&gt;Kimono is the first iteration of our solution to the scraping problem. It's still in beta and we want to invite you to check it out. We would love your feedback  - for bugs, feature suggestions or anything else. Your input will help us make kimono better, so you never have to write a web scraper again. Hope to see you kimonifying pages on the web soon!&lt;/p&gt;
        
        &lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2013; Pratap and Ryan&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;a class=&quot;btn btn-primary kim-dont-touch kimonolink-bottom&quot; href=&quot;http://www.kimonolabs.com/&quot;&gt;Try it out for free&lt;/a&gt;
        
      &lt;/div&gt;
      
    &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Show HN: Kimono – Never write a web scraper again
</title>
</item>
<item>
<author>
Kurt Mackey
</author>
<link>
http://blog.mongohq.com/making-remote-work-work-an-adventure-in-time-and-space/
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;article id=&quot;post-368&quot; class=&quot;post-368 post type-post status-publish format-standard hentry category-mongohq-2&quot;&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Mon&amp;#xAD;goHQ is a dis&amp;#xAD;trib&amp;#xAD;uted com&amp;#xAD;pany, with 21 employ&amp;#xAD;ees scat&amp;#xAD;tered across Cal&amp;#xAD;i&amp;#xAD;for&amp;#xAD;nia, Alabama, Utah, Wind&amp;#xAD;sor Ontario, Que&amp;#xAD;bec, and Lon&amp;#xAD;don. This isn&amp;#x2019;t rare, by any means, and is becom&amp;#xAD;ing more com&amp;#xAD;mon as tech&amp;#xAD;nol&amp;#xAD;ogy cor&amp;#xAD;po&amp;#xAD;ra&amp;#xAD;tions evolve &amp;#x2026; par&amp;#xAD;tic&amp;#xAD;u&amp;#xAD;larly when they real&amp;#xAD;ize that the inter&amp;#xAD;sec&amp;#xAD;tion of the entire pop&amp;#xAD;u&amp;#xAD;la&amp;#xAD;tion of good hack&amp;#xAD;ers and the area that&amp;#x2019;s rea&amp;#xAD;son&amp;#xAD;ably acces&amp;#xAD;si&amp;#xAD;ble to their office looks some&amp;#xAD;thing like&amp;#xA0;this:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; alt=&quot;Good Hacker intersection with office area&quot; src=&quot;http://blog.mongohq.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/good-hacker-sf-venn-diagram.png&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most posts like this talk a lot about the tools, which is under&amp;#xAD;stand&amp;#xAD;able because they&amp;#x2019;re so much fun to futz around with. At their best, though, tools that help with dis&amp;#xAD;trib&amp;#xAD;uted teams are an exten&amp;#xAD;sion of a remote friendly work&amp;#xAD;place, and get&amp;#xAD;ting to that is *hard*. We&amp;#x2019;re prob&amp;#xAD;a&amp;#xAD;bly 80% of the way there, and with enough dili&amp;#xAD;gence will be 82% of the way there by the end of this&amp;#xA0;year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Work&amp;#xAD;ing well remotely takes&amp;#xA0;practice&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#x2019;ve started ask&amp;#xAD;ing about remote work expe&amp;#xAD;ri&amp;#xAD;ence and skills very early in a promis&amp;#xAD;ing inter&amp;#xAD;view cycle. We expect a lot from peo&amp;#xAD;ple, and the &amp;#x201C;remote require&amp;#xAD;ment&amp;#x201D; just adds another dimen&amp;#xAD;sion of dif&amp;#xAD;fi&amp;#xAD;culty to their jobs. The nor&amp;#xAD;mal response, par&amp;#xAD;tic&amp;#xAD;u&amp;#xAD;larly from peo&amp;#xAD;ple who&amp;#x2019;ve been phys&amp;#xAD;i&amp;#xAD;cally present at offices all their lives, is a bit non&amp;#xAD;cha&amp;#xAD;lant. They assume that &amp;#x201C;remote work&amp;#x201D; means &amp;#x201C;I can spend a lot of time ski&amp;#xAD;ing and work from the&amp;#xA0;lodge&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; alt=&quot;Steve somewhere exotic, and snowy&quot; src=&quot;http://blog.mongohq.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/steve-telecommuting.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;#x2019;s true, kind of, as evi&amp;#xAD;denced by Steve up there. He does go ski&amp;#xAD;ing a lot and has been known to work from the lodge. He also, when not ski&amp;#xAD;ing, starts his days roughly 6 hours later than a nor&amp;#xAD;mal Lon&amp;#xAD;doner to make sure he&amp;#x2019;s around to talk to peo&amp;#xAD;ple on the supe&amp;#xAD;rior Amer&amp;#xAD;i&amp;#xAD;can time zones (except Pacific time, Pacific time is&amp;#xA0;awful).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What they don&amp;#x2019;t always think about, though, is the inher&amp;#xAD;ent fire&amp;#xAD;wall a com&amp;#xAD;mute cre&amp;#xAD;ates between &amp;#x201C;work&amp;#x201D; and &amp;#x201C;per&amp;#xAD;sonal life&amp;#x201D;. Work&amp;#xAD;ing out of a home office opens up an entire world of sur&amp;#xAD;pris&amp;#xAD;ingly difficult-&amp;#x200B;&amp;#x200B;to-&amp;#x200B;&amp;#x200B;handle dis&amp;#xAD;trac&amp;#xAD;tions, par&amp;#xAD;tic&amp;#xAD;u&amp;#xAD;larly for those of us with fam&amp;#xAD;i&amp;#xAD;lies. It&amp;#x2019;s easy to avoid a gui&amp;#xAD;tar wield&amp;#xAD;ing tod&amp;#xAD;dler when the office is 5 miles away and he has no driver&amp;#x2019;s license. It&amp;#x2019;s harder when the wall between the liv&amp;#xAD;ing room and the office makes a delight&amp;#xAD;ful bang&amp;#xAD;ing noise when struck with a&amp;#xA0;guitar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Every&amp;#xAD;one works remotely, even from an&amp;#xA0;office&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you did the math, you noticed we have about four times as many peo&amp;#xAD;ple as we do loca&amp;#xAD;tions. Mon&amp;#xAD;goHQ has offices in both San Mateo, CA (about 15 miles south of San Fran&amp;#xAD;cisco) and Birm&amp;#xAD;ing&amp;#xAD;ham, AL. Hav&amp;#xAD;ing cen&amp;#xAD;tral&amp;#xAD;ized offices can wreck a bud&amp;#xAD;ding remote friendly cul&amp;#xAD;ture. Work&amp;#xAD;ing in a way that&amp;#x2019;s inclu&amp;#xAD;sive of peo&amp;#xAD;ple who aren&amp;#x2019;t phys&amp;#xAD;i&amp;#xAD;cally (or even tem&amp;#xAD;po&amp;#xAD;rally) present is not entirely nat&amp;#xAD;ural, and exclud&amp;#xAD;ing remote employ&amp;#xAD;ees from impor&amp;#xAD;tant inter&amp;#xAD;ac&amp;#xAD;tions is a quick path to&amp;#xA0;agony.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Watercooler gossip&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.mongohq.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/4798856225_497f8a1566_b-700x468.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#x2019;ve expe&amp;#xAD;ri&amp;#xAD;enced some vari&amp;#xAD;ant of this prob&amp;#xAD;lem every time a new hire has joined in one of our offices, and are now very explicit about the &amp;#x201C;work as if you&amp;#x2019;re not here&amp;#x201D; stan&amp;#xAD;dard. We expect every&amp;#xAD;one to work with the remote col&amp;#xAD;lab&amp;#xAD;o&amp;#xAD;ra&amp;#xAD;tion tools, be avail&amp;#xAD;able via the same chan&amp;#xAD;nels, and pro&amp;#xAD;duce writ&amp;#xAD;ten arti&amp;#xAD;facts of inter&amp;#xAD;ac&amp;#xAD;tions that are impor&amp;#xAD;tant to share. This is a tough require&amp;#xAD;ment to stick to. We&amp;#x2019;ve encoun&amp;#xAD;tered peo&amp;#xAD;ple who func&amp;#xAD;tion very well in an office envi&amp;#xAD;ron&amp;#xAD;ment, but can&amp;#x2019;t seem to func&amp;#xAD;tion&amp;#xA0;remotely.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Hyper&amp;#xAD;sen&amp;#xAD;si&amp;#xAD;tiv&amp;#xAD;ity to &amp;#x201C;the&amp;#xA0;feels&amp;#x201D;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like most decep&amp;#xAD;tively sim&amp;#xAD;ple ideas, remote work is easy and amaz&amp;#xAD;ing when every&amp;#xAD;thing is going well. If your com&amp;#xAD;pany is killing it, all the hockey sticks point up, and every&amp;#xAD;one gets along amaz&amp;#xAD;ingly well, the remote work cul&amp;#xAD;ture is prob&amp;#xAD;a&amp;#xAD;bly good. There is dan&amp;#xAD;ger, how&amp;#xAD;ever, when things go south. We&amp;#x2019;ve expe&amp;#xAD;ri&amp;#xAD;enced the emo&amp;#xAD;tional troughs as a com&amp;#xAD;pany, and had indi&amp;#xAD;vid&amp;#xAD;u&amp;#xAD;als fight their own per&amp;#xAD;sonal&amp;#xA0;battles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The real&amp;#xAD;ity of a remote work&amp;#xAD;place is that the con&amp;#xAD;nec&amp;#xAD;tions are largely arti&amp;#xAD;fi&amp;#xAD;cial con&amp;#xAD;structs. Peo&amp;#xAD;ple can be very, very iso&amp;#xAD;lated. A person&amp;#x2019;s default behav&amp;#xAD;ior when they go into a funk is to avoid seek&amp;#xAD;ing out inter&amp;#xAD;ac&amp;#xAD;tions, which is effec&amp;#xAD;tively the same as actively with&amp;#xAD;draw&amp;#xAD;ing in a remote work envi&amp;#xAD;ron&amp;#xAD;ment. It takes a tremen&amp;#xAD;dous effort to get on video chats, use our text based com&amp;#xAD;mu&amp;#xAD;ni&amp;#xAD;ca&amp;#xAD;tion tools, or even call some&amp;#xAD;one dur&amp;#xAD;ing a dark&amp;#xA0;time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#x2019;re learn&amp;#xAD;ing how to inter&amp;#xAD;pret the emo&amp;#xAD;tional state of peo&amp;#xAD;ple we only rarely see, and started work&amp;#xAD;ing to delib&amp;#xAD;er&amp;#xAD;ately draw peo&amp;#xAD;ple out of iso&amp;#xAD;la&amp;#xAD;tion with com&amp;#xAD;pany wide video events. We&amp;#x2019;ve even tried record&amp;#xAD;ing bits of these events (a recent one had a series of light&amp;#xAD;ning talks) and shar&amp;#xAD;ing them around after&amp;#xAD;ward in an effort to get face time, even if just one way. This is a hard prob&amp;#xAD;lem, though, and there&amp;#x2019;s really very lit&amp;#xAD;tle we can do about it other than notice that it&amp;#x2019;s&amp;#xA0;happening.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The prac&amp;#xAD;ti&amp;#xAD;cal (and the&amp;#xA0;tools!)&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In gen&amp;#xAD;eral, a dis&amp;#xAD;trib&amp;#xAD;uted team is a series of com&amp;#xAD;mu&amp;#xAD;ni&amp;#xAD;ca&amp;#xAD;tion prob&amp;#xAD;lems. We tackle this in two gen&amp;#xAD;eral ways. First, we favor async com&amp;#xAD;mu&amp;#xAD;ni&amp;#xAD;ca&amp;#xAD;tion when&amp;#xA0;possible:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;We have a cen&amp;#xAD;tral &amp;#x201C;work tool&amp;#x201D; (it&amp;#x2019;s home grown, we call it Com&amp;#xAD;pose) we use to record what we&amp;#x2019;re pro&amp;#xAD;duc&amp;#xAD;ing each day. Any&amp;#xAD;one who wants to know what some&amp;#xAD;one is up to, or what&amp;#x2019;s been accom&amp;#xAD;plished on project X, can find out here &amp;#x2026; assum&amp;#xAD;ing everyone&amp;#x2019;s doing their&amp;#xA0;job.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Most day to day com&amp;#xAD;mu&amp;#xAD;ni&amp;#xAD;ca&amp;#xAD;tion hap&amp;#xAD;pens in &lt;a href=&quot;http://hipchat.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hipchat&lt;/a&gt;, with some work hap&amp;#xAD;pen&amp;#xAD;ing in project spe&amp;#xAD;cific rooms. It&amp;#x2019;s rea&amp;#xAD;son&amp;#xAD;ably easy to catch up on a day or two of activ&amp;#xAD;ity most of the&amp;#xA0;time.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;When we do have meet&amp;#xAD;ings (this is a whole post by itself), we like to have pre-&amp;#x200B;&amp;#x200B;reads avail&amp;#xAD;able on a Wiki. These get updated with use&amp;#xAD;ful infor&amp;#xAD;ma&amp;#xAD;tion as the meet&amp;#xAD;ing pro&amp;#xAD;gresses, with the goal of mak&amp;#xAD;ing the actual meet&amp;#xAD;ings optional. We use &lt;a href=&quot;http://hackpad.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hack&amp;#xAD;pad&lt;/a&gt; for this, mostly, but have also used Con&amp;#xAD;flu&amp;#xAD;ence and Github&amp;#x2019;s&amp;#xA0;wikis.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Email is a bit of a beast, but we do have &amp;#x201C;open&amp;#x201D; mail&amp;#xAD;ing lists and try to include those on most email com&amp;#xAD;mu&amp;#xAD;ni&amp;#xAD;ca&amp;#xAD;tions. The caveat is &amp;#x201C;try&amp;#x201D;, though, we haven&amp;#x2019;t been com&amp;#xAD;pletely suc&amp;#xAD;cess&amp;#xAD;ful in build&amp;#xAD;ing good com&amp;#xAD;pany email&amp;#xA0;habits.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;We also encour&amp;#xAD;age face&amp;#xA0;time:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sqwiggle.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sqwig&amp;#xAD;gle&lt;/a&gt; is really good for this, and there are any&amp;#xAD;where from 3 to 10 peo&amp;#xAD;ple on our Sqwig&amp;#xAD;gle setup at any given time. Sqwig&amp;#xAD;gle takes a pic&amp;#xAD;ture of whoever&amp;#x2019;s on every so often, and gets bonus points for help&amp;#xAD;ing us record peo&amp;#xAD;ples&amp;#x2019; embar&amp;#xAD;rass&amp;#xAD;ing poses for&amp;#xA0;posterity:&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; alt=&quot;Derp&quot; src=&quot;http://blog.mongohq.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/sqwiggle-shenanigans.png&quot;&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Google Hang&amp;#xAD;outs come in handy for sched&amp;#xAD;uled events. We used to have a per&amp;#xAD;pet&amp;#xAD;ual Hang&amp;#xAD;out on wall mounted tele&amp;#xAD;vi&amp;#xAD;sions in both offices, but that cre&amp;#xAD;ated a sort of audi&amp;#xAD;ence /&amp;#x200B; pre&amp;#xAD;sen&amp;#xAD;ter vibe that was a lit&amp;#xAD;tle&amp;#xA0;odd.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;We have a &lt;a href=&quot;http://doublerobotics.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dou&amp;#xAD;ble Robot&amp;#xAD;ics&lt;/a&gt; robot in each office. Remote employ&amp;#xAD;ees can &amp;#x201C;drop in&amp;#x201D;, drive around, and even pull off low level&amp;#xA0;pranks.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Does real estate count as a tool? We have an apart&amp;#xAD;ment near our San Mateo office that any&amp;#xAD;one can use when they&amp;#x2019;re in town. Peo&amp;#xAD;ple tend to travel to San Mateo about once every 6 weeks on&amp;#xA0;average.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;It&amp;#x2019;s a&amp;#xA0;process&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are try&amp;#xAD;ing to build a remote friendly cul&amp;#xAD;ture, the best advice we have for you is &amp;#x201C;just keep iter&amp;#xAD;at&amp;#xAD;ing&amp;#x201D;. It&amp;#x2019;s not an easy thing to do, but it&amp;#x2019;s an amaz&amp;#xAD;ing capa&amp;#xAD;bil&amp;#xAD;ity for a com&amp;#xAD;pany to have. Our con&amp;#xAD;tin&amp;#xAD;ued attempts to do it well have resulted in some phe&amp;#xAD;nom&amp;#xAD;e&amp;#xAD;nal peo&amp;#xAD;ple join&amp;#xAD;ing we never would have met oth&amp;#xAD;er&amp;#xAD;wise. We&amp;#x2019;ve mostly been able to get this far by pow&amp;#xAD;er&amp;#xAD;ing through the tough stuff, com&amp;#xAD;mit&amp;#xAD;ting to un-&amp;#x200B;&amp;#x200B;natural but valu&amp;#xAD;able habits, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://joel.is/post/59525266381/the-joys-and-benefits-of-working-as-a-distributed-team&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;learn&amp;#xAD;ing&lt;/a&gt; from other &lt;a href=&quot;https://zapier.com/blog/how-manage-remote-team/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;com&amp;#xAD;pa&amp;#xAD;nies&lt;/a&gt; who are &lt;a href=&quot;http://zachholman.com/posts/how-github-works-asynchronous/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;try&amp;#xAD;ing&lt;/a&gt; to do&amp;#xA0;similar.&lt;/p&gt;    &lt;/article&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Making remote work work: An adventure in time and space
</title>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
