<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version='2.0'>
<channel>
<generator>
clj-rss
</generator>
<link>
https://news.ycombinator.com
</link>
<title>
myread
</title>
<description>
myread
</description>
<item>
<link>
http://zulko.github.io/blog/2014/01/23/making-animated-gifs-from-video-files-with-python/#
</link>
<description>

</description>
<title>
Making GIFs From Video Files With Python
</title>
</item>
<item>
<author>
Romain Dillet
</author>
<link>
http://techcrunch.com/2014/01/25/soundcloud-raises-60-million-at-700-million-valuation/
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-entry text&quot;&gt;


&lt;img src=&quot;http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/soundcloudcribs.jpg?w=640&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/&quot;&gt;SoundCloud&lt;/a&gt; recently closed a Series D round of funding led by &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.crunchbase.com/financial-organization/institutional-venture-partners&quot;&gt;Institutional Venture Partners&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.crunchbase.com/financial-organization/the-chernin-group&quot;&gt;the Chernin Group&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://blogs.wsj.com/digits/2014/01/24/music-sharing-service-soundcloud-raises-new-funds-at-700-million-valuation/&quot;&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/a&gt; first reported the news. It has since been confirmed by &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.ivp.com/news/press-release/why-soundcloud-will-rule-the-digital-audio-world#.UuOj8U01iOG&quot;&gt;IVP&lt;/a&gt; and SoundCloud. Previous investors also participated in the round, including Kleiner Perkins Caufield &amp;amp; Byers, GGV Capital, Index Ventures and Union Square Ventures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SoundCloud&amp;#x2019;s ultimate goal is to become the &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2013/10/29/soundcloud-now-reaches-250-million-listeners-in-its-quest-to-become-the-audio-platform-of-the-web/&quot;&gt;audio platform of the web&lt;/a&gt;, or the YouTube of audio. Just like YouTube, user-generated content remains the startup&amp;#x2019;s fuel. Every minute, 12 hours of sound and music are uploaded to the platform. For comparison&amp;#x2019;s sake, YouTube &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/yt/press/statistics.html&quot;&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; 100 hours of content uploaded every minute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many up-and-coming electronic music artists use SoundCloud to release mixtapes and share them around the web. Well-known musicians also release singles or live recordings on the platform to share them with their fans on Twitter or Facebook. In other words, SoundCloud is the perfect place to transform a music file into a URL and embeddable music player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pullquote-wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;Seeing American VC firms putting a lot of faith in a European startup is a big win for the Berlin startup scene.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in October at Disrupt Europe, SoundCloud co-founder and CEO Alexander Ljung &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2013/10/29/soundcloud-now-reaches-250-million-listeners-in-its-quest-to-become-the-audio-platform-of-the-web/&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; that the company was focused on growth and engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#x2019;s why it simplified its premium offering. &amp;#x201C;The big thing when we made that change is that we went from four different account levels with a fairly wide range of pricing to two different levels with a smaller range,&amp;#x201D; Ljung said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a free account, you can upload up to 2 hours of music, while the most expensive plan allows you to upload an unlimited amount of music for $12 a month (&amp;#x20AC;9). Subscriptions used to be much more expensive, and an unlimited plan was out of reach for many amateur artists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;#x2019;s funding news is probably the consequence of this focus on growth. At Disrupt, Ljung said that subscription numbers were &amp;#x201C;pretty much exactly on our forecast.&amp;#x201D; Seeing American VC firms putting a lot of faith in a European startup is a big win for the Berlin startup scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But SoundCloud still has to find the major hidden, yet reachable, treasure. Most of SoundCloud&amp;#x2019;s 250 million users turn to SoundCloud to consume music, listen to artist-curated playlists and comment. They aren&amp;#x2019;t content creators; they carefully curate a music feed by following artists on the platform. For now, they don&amp;#x2019;t generate a lot of money for the company &amp;#x2014; the website has never been inundated with ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://recode.net/2014/01/24/soundcloud-has-a-new-pile-of-cash-and-wants-to-cut-deals-with-big-music/&quot;&gt;Re/code&lt;/a&gt;, the company is now trying to sign content deals with major music labels. It would put SoundCloud in the same league as other big music companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x2019;s still unclear whether the company wants to create yet another subscription service like Spotify or Rdio, a music store like the iTunes Store or the Amazon MP3 Store, a radio-like experience like Pandora or iTunes Radio, or something completely different. It&amp;#x2019;s a crowded market, but signing these deals is an important step for the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With music labels on board, the company could get more users, more monetization options and better content to convince advertisers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;video-container&quot; id=&quot;008cac3cfc&quot;&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;


								
							&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
SoundCloud Raises $60 Million at $700 Million Valuation
</title>
</item>
<item>
<author>
Megan Farokhmanesh on Jan 25, 2014 at 11:00a @Megan_Nicolett
</author>
<link>
http://www.polygon.com/2014/1/25/5344390/nvidia-marketing-manager-killed-during-train-rescue-attempt
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;m-entry__follow-bar&quot; id=&quot;follow-bar&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;m-entry__follow-bar__highlighted&quot;&gt;Stay Connected.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt; Follow Polygon Now!&lt;/span&gt;
    
    
    
  &lt;/div&gt;


          


          


          

&lt;div class=&quot;m-entry__body&quot; id=&quot;article-body&quot;&gt;
            

&lt;p&gt;Nvidia marketing manager Philip Scholz was killed on Jan. 20 after attempting to pull a man off the train tracks at the Santa Clara Caltrain Station in California, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mercurynews.com/twitter/ci_24989424/tech-worker-killed-by-train-santa-clara-was&quot;&gt;Mercury News&lt;/a&gt; reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to surveillance footage taken just before his death, Scholz laid on his stomach and attempted to help pull the man to safety just before the train hit both men around 5:30 p.m. at 50 to 70 mph. Scholz was killed in the accident, while the man he helped remains in critical condition at the hospital. His identity has not yet been released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scholz, age 35, was raised in Washington. He attended Santa Clara University in California and was married to Emily Scholz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The memorial for Philip Scholz will take place at 10 a.m. on Feb. 10 at the Veterans Memorial Building in Pleasanton.&lt;/p&gt;

          &lt;/div&gt;

          
          
        &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Nvidia marketing manager killed during train rescue attempt
</title>
</item>
<item>
<link>
http://www.lawyersgunsmoneyblog.com/2014/01/christ-i-hate-blackboard
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry&quot;&gt;

							

							




							&lt;p&gt;Hundreds of years from now, after disease and fire and famine have thinned the human herd to a shrunken patchwork of sagging, skeletal bands of jagged, half-mad wraiths &amp;#x2014; when the parched soil chokes forth desiccated roots and the air is a toxic brume slumping down on the arched, knotted backs of the still-barely-living &amp;#x2014; a remote spur of humanity will somehow recover the capacity to speak, an ability long since abandoned by their ancestors, who were mute-struck with the unfathomable despair of those cursed to watch everything they love die. After generations of dry-throated croaking and lung-starched wheezing, their tongues swollen with thirst and punctured with abscesses that never heal, these distant people will bring forth a new language to survey the boundaries of their pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, their speech will flow together in single, blasphemous strands of adjectival protest; they will speak without subjects, no proper names or pronouns to jolt them into the kind of self-recognition that could only serve as a spur to mass, urgent suicide. In time, their words will be hacked into tinier fragments of salivated fury, as their lips and tongues and few-remaining-teeth jostle ruthlessly to disgorge themselves into the foul space that separates one antagonist from another. With arm-sized splinters of trees that were fortunate enough to perish centuries before, they will jab massive holes into their upper palates to accommodate the new sounds needed to register their misfortune and threaten each other with gross physical harm. Inbred mutants with hideous nasocranial deformities will gain selective advantage in the linguistic struggle for existence. They will use this new language to enslave one another, to plot out gristly sprees that might be called murder if there were anything near to law restraining them, like a weak sphincter, from unleashing their worst. There will be decades of forced labor, violent spasms of resistance and recrimination carried out with grossly disproportionate injury to bystanders who are, alas, never as innocent as they seem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the outskirts of this new language, lurking on its crimsoned frontier, will lie words that will themselves have been cast into exile &amp;#x2013; foul offgassings within a lexicon that itself stands as a towering monument to the boundlessly obscene, words that will curve backward and devour themselves, each one an afflicted universe in the process of total collapse, words that exist for microseconds before streaking, unremembered and unmourned, into the void.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the words, if I could shit them into being, that I would use to catalogue the depth of my loathing for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=blackboard+sucks&amp;amp;ie=utf-8&amp;amp;oe=utf-8&amp;amp;aq=t&amp;amp;rls=org.mozilla:en-US:official&amp;amp;client=firefox-a&quot;&gt;Blackboard&lt;/a&gt;. When I die, I want my whiskey-pickled body larded into a cryonic chamber, then buried deep in the earth. A thousand years from now, I want these loping, crookspined human gargoyles to dig me up and reanimate me. I will learn their language; I will amble to the profane horizon of their blood-gorged vernacular; I will force them at spear-point to build me a time machine; then I will murder them all with my bare hands. I will return to all of you then to bear witness, in a rapturous tornado of filth, to my contempt for that unholy system of course mismanagement software.&lt;/p&gt;

							

						&lt;/div&gt;

						



						

					&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Christ, I hate Blackboard
</title>
</item>
<item>
<author>
Jonathan Sposato
</author>
<link>
http://www.inc.com/magazine/201402/jonathan-sposato/lessons-from-selling-to-google.html
</link>
<description>
&lt;div id=&quot;articlecontent&quot; score=&quot;23.75&quot;&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;articlecontent&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    

    
  

        

                
        
                
                            
    




 

	

	
	








&lt;bodycopy id=&quot;bodycopy&quot;&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jonathan Sposato: Founder of Phatbits and Picnik&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I founded Phatbits, which made XML desktop applications, in 2004. A year later, Google offered to acquire the business. We closed the deal after quick and collegial negotiations, and our group integrated into the Google Gadgets division easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My one regret was agreeing to stay on for four years. I wound up leaving after a year. I underestimated what it would feel like to be a salaryman, no longer in control of my own destiny. But overall, the integration was a success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I sold Picnik, a photo-sharing site, to Google five years later, I assumed everything would be about the same. That wasn't the case. This time, negotiations were complex, lasting almost six months.We faced a dizzying amount of changes in the first three months after the acquisition, being shuttled from one part of the company to the next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One-third of our 25-person team, including my two business partners, quit right off the bat. I stayed for two years to offer some sense of continuity. By 2012, Google shut down Picnik entirely. I felt like I let a bunch of great people down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back, I should have insisted that Google's crystal ball for Picnik was clearer. I sometimes wonder whether I should have sold the company at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, as an angel investor in six startups, I advise entrepreneurs who are thinking about selling to think carefully about the return on investment, including the effect on team culture, not just the bottom line. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/bodycopy&gt;



    


	

		




	


	


		

&lt;/div&gt;


</description>
<title>
What I Wish I Had Known Before Selling to Google
</title>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
