<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version='2.0'>
<channel>
<generator>
clj-rss
</generator>
<link>
https://news.ycombinator.com
</link>
<title>
myread
</title>
<description>
myread
</description>
<item>
<author>
Zachary M. Seward, David Yanofsky, Zachary M. Seward and David Yanofsky
</author>
<link>
http://qz.com/167993/frere-jones-is-suing-hoefler-for-his-half-of-the-worlds-preeminent-digital-type-foundry/
</link>
<description>
&lt;div class=&quot;item-body&quot; score=&quot;32.5&quot;&gt;
		&lt;div score=&quot;30.0&quot;&gt;
			
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.typography.com/&quot;&gt;Hoefler &amp;amp; Frere-Jones&lt;/a&gt;, the preeminent digital type foundry, has broken out into civil war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type designer Tobias Frere-Jones claims he has been cheated out of his half of the company by his business partner, Jonathan Hoefler. In a blistering lawsuit filed today in New York City, Frere-Jones says he was duped into transferring ownership of several fonts, including the world-famous &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.typography.com/fonts/whitney/overview/&quot;&gt;Whitney&lt;/a&gt;, to Hoefler &amp;amp; Frere-Jones (HFJ) on the understanding that he would own 50% of the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In the most profound treachery and sustained exploitation of friendship, trust and confidence, Hoefler accepted all of the benefits provided by Frere-Jones while repeatedly promising Frere-Jones that he would give him the agreed equity, only to refuse to do so when finally demanded,” the suit claims. Here’s the full complaint:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hoefler couldn’t immediately be reached for comment. Messages left at the offices of HFJ weren’t immediately returned. (See below for their statement.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frere-Jones joined the company that would come to be called HFJ in 1999. The suit portrays Frere-Jones as the firm’s design genius, and Hoefler as the business and marketing man. In public, the pair have generally been regarded as equals. But the contract that made it so, according to the lawsuit, was never written down and signed. Frere-Jones claims he had an oral contract with Hoefler that entitles him to half the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dispute came to a head last year. ”Stop it. I’m working on it. Stop harassing me,” Hoefler allegedly wrote to Frere-Jones last summer. The suit claims, “On October 21, 2013, for the first time, Hoefler explicitly reneged on his personal agreement to transfer 50% of HTF to Frere-Jones.” (HTF refers to the Hoefler Type Foundry, the company’s original name.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frere-Jones’s lawyer, Fredric Newman, a senior partner at Hoguet Newman Regal &amp;amp; Kenney, said in a phone interview, ”The two partners tried to resolve it, but couldn’t, and so Mr. Frere-Jones had no choice but to sue to enforce his rights.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The firm is perhaps the most important type designer of the 21st century. Its fonts have graced the branding of billion-dollar companies, and the covers of glossy magazines. Movie-trailer warning labels in the United States are set in Gotham, an HFJ typeface that was also famously used by Barack Obama’s 2008 presidential campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;qz-inline-image aligncenter&quot; score=&quot;16.25&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;http://qzprod.files.wordpress.com/2014/01/gotham.png?w=640&amp;amp;h=499&quot; class=&quot;size-medium_10&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Gotham&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
			&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Gotham&lt;/span&gt;
			&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Hoefler &amp;amp; Frere-Jones&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;p&gt;HFJ’s typefaces have won admiration from designers by taking advantage of the limitless environment of digital design. Where most typefaces only had two weights and two styles in one width, HFJ became known for creating typefaces with several weights and several styles in several widths that included advanced features like alternate characters, and support for multiple alphabets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;qz-inline-image aligncenter&quot; score=&quot;16.25&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;http://qzprod.files.wordpress.com/2014/01/screen-shot-2014-01-16-at-6-51-41-pm.png?w=640&amp;amp;h=412&quot; class=&quot;size-medium_10&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Whitney&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
			&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Whitney&lt;/span&gt;
			&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Hoefler &amp;amp; Frere-Jones&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;update&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update (Jan. 17, 2:45pm ET): &lt;/strong&gt;HFJ &lt;a href=&quot;http://typography.com/press/20140117&quot;&gt;released a statement&lt;/a&gt;, set in the firm’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.typography.com/fonts/mercury-text/overview/&quot;&gt;Mercury&lt;/a&gt; typeface, denying Frere-Jones’s claims and saying the company will henceforth be known as Hoefler &amp;amp; Co.:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week, designer Tobias Frere-Jones, a longtime employee of The Hoefler Type Foundry, Inc. (d/b/a “Hoefler &amp;amp; Frere-Jones”), decided to leave the company. With Tobias’s departure, the company founded by Jonathan Hoefler in 1989 will become known as Hoefler &amp;amp; Co.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following his departure, Tobias filed a claim against company founder Jonathan Hoefler. Its allegations are not the facts, and they profoundly misrepresent Tobias’s relationship with both the company and Jonathan. Whether as The Hoefler Type Foundry, Hoefler &amp;amp; Frere-Jones, or Hoefler &amp;amp; Co., our company has always been a great place for designers, which is why it’s always been and will continue to be a great place for design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It goes without saying that all of us are disappointed by Tobias’s actions. The company will vigorously defend itself against these allegations, which are false and without legal merit. In the meantime, we’re all hard at work, continuing to create the kinds of typefaces that designers have come to expect from us for more than 25 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;


		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
</description>
<title>
Frere-Jones is suing Hoefler for half of preeminent digital type foundry
</title>
</item>
<item>
<author>
Robinson Meyer
</author>
<link>
http://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2014/01/what-happens-when-the-president-sits-down-next-to-you-at-a-cafe/283074/
</link>
<description>
&lt;div class=&quot;article-content&quot; score=&quot;40.0&quot;&gt;

                
                
        &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.theatlantic.com/newsroom/img/posts/2014/01/arrow_at_rob/a291b9199.jpg&quot; width=&quot;570&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The author, at &quot;work&quot; (Pete Souza/The White House)&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;big&gt;Before&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thursday into Friday, my head cold got worse, so on Friday morning I walked down to a bar-cafe-restaurant in my neighborhood. I had been there for a few hours when youthful, vigorous men and women wearing Business Semi-Formal started quietly going one by one among the customers sitting near me. They would crouch, adopt an expression of deep sympathy, and say something. The customer would look a little confused, pick up laptop and coat, and move to another table.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Next to me, cafe staff had made a long table by pushing three smaller tables together. Five Millennials sat around it. They were well-dressed like Ryan Seacrest is well-dressed, and they seemed nervous. The head of their table hadn’t been filled. I had assumed someone important, someone hoity-toity, would be coming, someone like a foundation executive director.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a little bit annoying, but my legs ached and the Internet was spotty and I wanted to go to a different, better coffee shop, so I asked for the check. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then a man, another of the handsome ones, came by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey,” he murmured. “Will you be leaving soon?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I said I wasn’t sure. I’d asked for the check.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Okay,” he said. “I just wanted to let you know the president will be stopping by.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oh&lt;/em&gt;, I thought. &lt;em&gt;The president of what?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re welcome to stay, but one of our agents will be coming around to swipe you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I understood. An agent came around to swipe me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world is made of people: I get this. Our republic only works if we know our leaders are fallible humans. I disagree with the Obama Administration about plenty. None of this kept me from experiencing immediate, full-on, feverish anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;big&gt;During&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the president arrived, 40 minutes later—stepping out of his SUV, smiling, with a little wave—the nerves subsided. The cafe is split into two long halves, and he first turned to visit its opposite half, smiling, shaking hands, shaking more hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then—for the first time in nearly an hour—I could work. I found that I was so accustomed to his voice, how he holds his body, his aura, that ignoring him in person is as easy as ignoring a TV. &lt;em&gt;Easier,&lt;/em&gt; in fact. He stops being the president and starts being That Guy Who You See In Tweets, That Guy Who Gives Speeches, That Guy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That Guy shook exactly half the hands on the other side of the restaurant. He came back to our side. He addressed the five people sitting adjacent to me—who were, indeed, apparently there to talk to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That Guy said he would save our whole side of the restaurant for after the meal. But then, next to me, on my other side, he spotted a baby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He apologized to the group. He could not resist, he said, a baby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;big&gt;Concerning the Baby&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;He picked up the baby. The baby’s mom told him about the baby. Before, I had asked her if she would like pictures of them meeting, so I got out my phone and documented the event. One of those pictures is above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pete Souza, the official White House photographer, was also there. He documented the event a little better than I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;✈ Baby Force One ✈ &lt;a href=&quot;http://t.co/0e2075cbb2&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/0e2075cbb2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— The White House (@WhiteHouse) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/WhiteHouse/statuses/421801910937481216&quot;&gt;January 11, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is little else to say about the baby. He was adorable. Obama really seemed to appreciate holding him, and bounced him for probably a minute. The baby's mom told him that their family had just been stationed in Kenya, that that’s where the baby was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He seemed to stumble for a second, as he realized he could not phrase a joke in exactly the way he could phrase it in private.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s, that’s where Donald Trump thinks I was born,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then he handed the baby back to his mom. It was then that I made my only physical contact with the president. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;big&gt;My Only Physical Contact With the President&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The president hands the baby back to its mom. The president makes eye contact with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Great to see you,” says the president.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The president extends his hand while simultaneously pivoting on his right foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His hands grasp mine. &lt;em&gt;They feel like the rough surface of your favorite baseball.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eye contact was broken mid-handshake. His hand trailed his turned body *which has already turned on the pivoted foot.* He greeted a couple across the way from me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This concludes my communication with the president of the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;big&gt;My Only Source for This Section Is What I Eavesdropped&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.theatlantic.com/newsroom/img/posts/2014/01/IMG_0002-1/2031f8e7a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;570&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Obama sat down at the head of the table. There was a brief photo op at the opposite end of the table. I surreptitiously took a picture to remember what being on the other side of a wall of cameras felt like, but now it seems more remarkable that &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;I can see the president’s undershirt.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;He had come to my local cafe to meet with five young people. According to White House background, provided to me after he left, they met to discuss how to get more 18-34 year-olds to sign up for the coverage under the Affordable Care Act. (The law depends on 18-34 year-olds signing up for healthcare.) One of the five was a navigator, someone employed to help families sign up; another helped explain the law at a mall over the holidays.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;They talked about health care stuff for the first 20 minutes. The five shared their experiences, and some of them spoke quietly, so I couldn’t hear them that well.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;At one point the president said, “Now, this isn’t public yet.” I perked up.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;“Thirty percent of somethingsomethingsomething is mumblemumble,” he said.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;I didn’t hear. I had failed as a journalist, so I went to the bathroom.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;big&gt;Failure&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got back, they were talking about music. Circumstantial evidence indicates that, while I was in the bathroom, they talked about Beyoncé. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conversation moved on. They talked about cell phones, and Obama mentioned how Malia did not receive one until she was 16. One of the young people pointed out that, unlike most parents, the president could always argue that he’d know where she was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They segued to talking about social media (I couldn’t hear their exact words). &lt;em&gt;Now&lt;/em&gt;, I thought. Now I could do tech journalism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The president said something—I could not hear all of it—about new social media apps that were for messaging, new apps that only somethingsomething’d for eight seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Snapchat,” said one of the young people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The president made a comment about how different apps were now popular. Someone—it might have been the president—said the word “Instagram.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess that they were talking about the difficulty of doing political outreach on Snapchat or one of this newer, less textual ilk? I’m not sure. Then the president drops this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It seems like they don’t use Facebook anymore,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Facebook is so uncool even the president of the United States knows it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not sure who the &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; is. A White House representative I talked to afterward hypothesized that it might be the 18 to 34 year-olds whom the President hopes will sign up for the healthcare law.  Maybe it was the third-person singular, gender-neutral pronoun. I don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a question of high hermeneutic importance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Only Other Thing I Overheard&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michelle has begun watching &lt;em&gt;Scandal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s not that exciting,” said the president, of the White House. Staffers “don’t have enough time to engage in too much scandalous behavior.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Then the meal was over. Obama got up and took a photo with the five. He put his jacket back down, walked past me, and greeted the rest of the restaurant’s customers. He turned at the end, said good-bye to the baby again as he passed (tousling his hair), rounded the corner, and was gone.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;A crowd had gathered across the street. It cheered as Obama got back in his SUV.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;big&gt;After&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Millennial closest to Obama, and therefore also closest to me, asked who I was. They asked me if I had photo-bombed. I had not, really. In this, I missed the greatest photobombing opportunity of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had, however, won Snapchat. Forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.theatlantic.com/newsroom/img/posts/2014/01/IMG_0005_2/e64bb3375.jpg&quot; width=&quot;346&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


        
            &lt;/div&gt;


</description>
<title>
Facebook is so uncool even the president of the United States knows it.
</title>
</item>
<item>
<link>
http://blog.spark.io/2014/01/17/open-source-thermostat/
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;section&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, Google bought Nest, a connected devices company, for $3.2 billion. This might seem like an ungodly sum for a company that makes thermostats and smoke detectors, but it makes absolute sense. Nest&amp;#x2019;s products are beautifully designed, their team is overflowing with talent, and they were the first company to figure out what the &amp;#x201C;Internet of Things&amp;#x201D; means to consumers and deliver products that people actually &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in order to do this, Nest had to spend millions of dollars on R&amp;amp;D to build the basic infrastructure behind the product. The high cost made it impossible for anyone but the extremely well-capitalized to enter the market and create connected things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, we want to change that. At Spark, we&amp;#x2019;re making it easier to bring connected devices to market with the Spark Core, our Wi-Fi development kit, and the Spark Cloud, our cloud service for connected devices. And to prove it, we built our own approximation of the Nest Learning Thermostat in one day &amp;#x2014; and we&amp;#x2019;ve open sourced everything. In this process, we&amp;#x2019;ve come to respect the incredible technical challenges that Nest has solved while also coming to understand how much the game has changed since they first started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;820&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/blog.spark.io/finalproduct.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/blog.spark.io/finalproduct.webm&quot; type=&quot;video/webm&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fair warning - we&amp;#x2019;re not claiming to have matched the Nest thermostat in a day; far from it. But remember &amp;#x2014; every polished product starts as a rough prototype. As Alexis Ohanian &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/towynlin/status/421456323138441216&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; last week, &amp;#x201C;The first version of everything you love is janky!&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hardware&quot;&gt;Hardware&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, you need hardware. In our case, that means sensors for temperature and humidity, plus a motion sensor to figure out whether you&amp;#x2019;re home, and relays to control the furnace and the fan. We also need a display so you can see the current temperature, and an enclosure to protect the messy bits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;820&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/blog.spark.io/breadboarded.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/blog.spark.io/breadboarded.webm&quot; type=&quot;video/webm&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing we did this morning (after whiteboarding our attack plan) was to breadboard the hardware. Breadboarding is a non-permanent way to create an early hardware prototype. We chose a number of components for this product:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.spark.io&quot;&gt;Spark Core&lt;/a&gt; served as our connected brain.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;We display the temperature on a few &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adafruit.com/products/870&quot;&gt;Adafruit 8x8 LED matrices&lt;/a&gt;. The interface for the displays is a common I2C bus.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The primary sensor is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digikey.com/product-detail/en/HIH6131-021-001/480-3652-6-ND/2704706&quot;&gt;Honeywell HumidIcon&lt;/a&gt; temperature and humidity sensor, which shares the I2C bus with the displays.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;For our MVP, we decided a couple LEDs could represent whether the heat and fan were on. In the end the same pins would be connected to relays instead of the LEDs.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;If you want to save energy when a person&amp;#x2019;s not home, then you need a way to know when they are home so you can err on the side of comfort again. We added a &lt;a href=&quot;http://pewa.panasonic.com/assets/pcsd/catalog/napion-catalog.pdf&quot;&gt;Panasonic PIR motion detector&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, it took about an hour to throw together this breadboarded prototype, although we had to order the components a couple of days beforehand. It took another couple of hours to pull together working firmware (see the software section below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;820&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/blog.spark.io/cncmilled.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/blog.spark.io/cncmilled.webm&quot; type=&quot;video/webm&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step is to build an enclosure. The Nest enclosure is glass and aluminum, which are both very pretty but not very handy for prototyping. Instead, we chose acrylic and wood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we CNC milled two wooden rings: one to act as a stationary base, and other to spin freely as a temperature controller (turn the ring clockwise to increase the temperature, and counterclockwise to decrease the temperature).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;820&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/blog.spark.io/lasercut.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/blog.spark.io/lasercut.webm&quot; type=&quot;video/webm&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, we laser cut three acrylic disks: one to act as the faceplate (which we later sanded to make it frosty), a second to act as the wall mounting plate, and a third connects the spinning wooden ring to a potentiometer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;820&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/blog.spark.io/enclosure.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/blog.spark.io/enclosure.webm&quot; type=&quot;video/webm&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we completed the enclosure, we converted our breadboarded circuit into a more permanent design by permanently soldering the components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;820&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/blog.spark.io/mohitsoldering.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/blog.spark.io/mohitsoldering.webm&quot; type=&quot;video/webm&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;software&quot;&gt;Software&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, you need software. Some of this software runs on the thermostat (often called &amp;#x2018;firmware&amp;#x2019;), reading data from the sensors, controlling the relays, and displaying data on the screen. But since this is a connected thermostat, we also want a web interface so that it can be controlled from your smartphone or computer. And since it&amp;#x2019;s a learning thermostat, we also want to do some machine learning so that we can over time improve your comfort and energy efficiency. This software will run in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;820&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/blog.spark.io/workingproto.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/blog.spark.io/workingproto.webm&quot; type=&quot;video/webm&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2018;Firmware&amp;#x2019; is called &lt;em&gt;firm&lt;/em&gt; because it&amp;#x2019;s traditionally more locked down than software, since it runs on a little chip that usually is never accessed again after the product is delivered to the customer. But adding an internet connection changes things pretty significantly. Firmware is no longer &lt;em&gt;firm&lt;/em&gt; when you can update it from anywhere with the click of a button. With a Spark Core, you can flash new code onto your chip using our web IDE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;820&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/blog.spark.io/joescode.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/blog.spark.io/joescode.webm&quot; type=&quot;video/webm&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our thermostat is complemented with a cloud-based web app that handles all of the complex logic of the thermostat. By doing this in the cloud, we can iterate faster using high-level programming languages and frameworks like Ruby on Rails rather than low-level embedded C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Spark Cloud exposes your connected device through a REST API. That means that you can interact with it from any language that can generate HTTP requests, which is basically anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beauty of a connected device is that it can be constantly improving, whether it&amp;#x2019;s by updating the firmware, updating the cloud software, or by using machine learning to optimize and improve the logic of the device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;820&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/blog.spark.io/softwareinaction.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/blog.spark.io/softwareinaction.webm&quot; type=&quot;video/webm&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our user interface is a simple web app with a javascript knob that lets you select the desired temperature. The UI also includes a graph of historical temperatures, because data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;connectivity&quot;&gt;Connectivity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;#x2019;ve got your hardware and your software, it&amp;#x2019;s time to link the two worlds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow you&amp;#x2019;ve got to get your thing online, and there are dozens of ways to do this. The simplest method is by adding a Wi-Fi module, so your product can act as a client on your local Wi-Fi network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.spark.io&quot;&gt;Spark Core&lt;/a&gt; has a Wi-Fi module built in, and because it&amp;#x2019;s integrated with the micro-controller, &amp;#x2018;connectivity&amp;#x2019; is made easy. The Core automatically connects to the Spark Cloud through an encrypted tunnel, so you&amp;#x2019;ve got a secure connection to a cloud gateway out of the box. No programming the Wi-Fi module, and no finding or building communications protocols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;putting_it_all_together&quot;&gt;Putting it all together&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once our thermostat was complete, it was time to assemble it all together into the final package and mount it on the wall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;820&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/blog.spark.io/underthecovers.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/blog.spark.io/underthecovers.webm&quot; type=&quot;video/webm&quot;&gt;&lt;/source&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in, we spent about $70 on components to put this together (including $39 for the Spark Core); the wood and acrylic were free. We started working at 10am and finished at 3am, with 3.5 engineers involved (one went to bed early), and the only work we did in advance was order the electronic components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get_excited_crazy_things_are_possible&quot;&gt;Get excited, crazy things are possible.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#x2019;re not saying that you can build a $3.2 billion company in a day. But we &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; saying that you can build a $3.2 billion company, and it&amp;#x2019;s easier now than it&amp;#x2019;s ever been before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Connected devices/Internet of Things/M2M/Industrial Internet is a certified &lt;strong&gt;big deal&lt;/strong&gt;, and the Nest acquisition proves it. It doesn&amp;#x2019;t matter whether you&amp;#x2019;re a software developer with no hardware experience, an embedded designer with no web experience, or a psych major with no experience whatsoever. This is the next frontier, and it&amp;#x2019;s time to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your billion dollar company starts with a million dollar product, and your million dollar product starts with a hundred dollar prototype. So what are you waiting for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To download the open source files for the Spark thermostat, visit our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.github.com/spark/thermostat&quot;&gt;Github page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow us on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/sparkdevices&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, discuss at &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=7075626&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;, and get a Spark Core at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.spark.io&quot;&gt;spark.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
            


        &lt;/section&gt;

        &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Building an open source Nest
</title>
</item>
<item>
<link>
http://jstherightway.org/
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;wrapper&quot;&gt;
                

                &lt;h3&gt;ABOUT&lt;/h3&gt;

                &lt;p&gt;
                    Created by Netscape in 1995 as an extension of HTML for Netscape Navigator 2.0, JavaScript had as its main function the manipulation of HTML documents and form validation.

                    Before winning this name so famous nowadays, JavaScript was called Mocha, after LiveScript and finally, when it was released by Sun Microsystems, was baptized with the name by which he is known today.

                    Because of the similar names, people confuses JavaScript with Java. Although both have the lexical structure of programming, they are not the same language.

                    Different from C, C# and Java, JavaScript is an interpreted language. It means that it needs an &quot;interpreter&quot;. In case of JavaScript, the interpreter is the browser.
                &lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;h3&gt;CURRENT VERSION&lt;/h3&gt;

                &lt;p&gt;
                    The JavaScript standard is ECMAScript. As of 2012, all modern browsers fully support ECMAScript 5.1. Older browsers support at least ECMAScript 3. A 6th major revision of the standard is being worked on.
                &lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;p&gt;
                    A good reference to versions, references and news about JavaScript, you can find at &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/JavaScript&quot;&gt;Mozilla Developer Network&lt;/a&gt;.
                &lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;h3&gt;THE DOM&lt;/h3&gt;

                &lt;p&gt;
                    The Document Object Model (DOM) is an API for HTML and XML documents. It provides a structural representation of the document, enabling you to modify its content and visual presentation by using a scripting language such as JavaScript. See more at &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/DOM&quot;&gt;Mozilla Developer Network - DOM&lt;/a&gt;.
                &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/section&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
JavaScript: The Right Way
</title>
</item>
<item>
<link>
http://pages.cs.wisc.edu/~remzi/OSTEP/
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;td width=&quot;800pt&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to &lt;b&gt;Operating Systems: Three Easy Pieces&lt;/b&gt; (now version 0.6.1 -- see
&lt;a href=&quot;http://pages.cs.wisc.edu/~remzi/OSTEP/log.html&quot;&gt;BOOK NEWS&lt;/a&gt; for details), a free
online (and available for purchase in printed form) operating systems book!
The book is centered around three conceptual pieces that are fundamental to
operating systems: &lt;b&gt;virtualization,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;concurrency,&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;persistence.&lt;/b&gt; 
In understanding the conceptual, you will also learn the practical, including
how an operating system does things like schedule the CPU, manage memory, and
store files persistently. Lots of fun stuff!&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;This book &lt;b&gt;is and will always be free&lt;/b&gt; in PDF form, as
seen below, on a chapter-by-chapter basis. For those of you wishing to &lt;b&gt;BUY&lt;/b&gt; 
a copy, please consider the following:&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;table&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;70&quot; src=&quot;http://pages.cs.wisc.edu/~remzi/OSTEP/book-cover-two.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;/td&gt; 

&lt;td&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A wonderful
&lt;a href=&quot;http://pages.cs.wisc.edu/~remzi/OSTEP/book-hardcover.html&quot;&gt;hardcover edition&lt;/a&gt; - this may be the best printed
form of the book (it really looks pretty good), but it is also the most
expensive way to obtain &lt;i&gt;the black book&lt;/i&gt; of operating systems.&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;li&gt;An almost-as-wonderful (and somewhat cheaper)
&lt;a href=&quot;http://pages.cs.wisc.edu/~remzi/OSTEP/book-softcover.html&quot;&gt;softcover edition&lt;/a&gt; - this way is pretty great too,
if you like to read printed material but want to save a few bucks.&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;li&gt;A pretty awesome
&lt;a href=&quot;http://pages.cs.wisc.edu/~remzi/OSTEP/book-electronic.html&quot;&gt;electronic edition&lt;/a&gt; (for only ten dollars!) -
this is a nice convenience and adds things like a hyperlinked table of contents,
glossary of terms, lists of hints, tips, and other systems-building advice,
and a few other small things not seen in the free version below.&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ul&gt; 
 
&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;/table&gt; 


&lt;p&gt;These paid methods are both brought to you by the demand of various students
and professors; they are also a nice way to show your pecuniary appreciation
to the authors.&lt;/p&gt; 


&lt;p&gt;
And now, the free online form of the book, in chapter-by-chapter form:
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Two professors at my university have decided to create a free OS book because &quot;book prices are too high&quot;
</title>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
