<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version='2.0'>
<channel>
<generator>
clj-rss
</generator>
<link>
https://news.ycombinator.com
</link>
<title>
myread
</title>
<description>
myread
</description>
<item>
<link>
http://www.gamezebo.com/news/2014/01/20/king-has-trademarked-word-candy-and-youre-probably-infringing
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;page_reviewbox_content_details font14&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fltleft gaprt20 gapbot20&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2a34166a1c224507ff54-79590be14f37a3e58649da10f58ee927.r67.cf1.rackcdn.com/news/game_title_image/1390232832.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have an intellectual property &amp;#x2013; especially one that&amp;#x2019;s worth millions of dollars &amp;#x2013; you want to protect it. But can such protections ever go too far? That&amp;#x2019;s the question a lot of industry watchers are asking this morning, as developers far and wide whose games include the word &amp;#x2018;candy&amp;#x2019; are getting emails from Apple on behalf of King, the makers of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gamezebo.com/games/candy-crush-saga/review&quot;&gt;Candy Crush Saga&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trademarkia.com/candy-85842584.html&quot;&gt;a filing with the US trademark office&lt;/a&gt; dated February 6, 2013, King.com Limited registered claim to the word &amp;#x2018;candy&amp;#x2019; as it pertains to video games and, strangely, clothing. On January 15, 2014 the filing was approved. And now, a mere five days later, reports are coming in from developers that they&amp;#x2019;re being asked to remove their app (or prove that their game doesn&amp;#x2019;t infringe upon the trademark).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x201C;Lots of devs are frustrated cause it seems so ridiculous&amp;#x201D; says Benny Hsu, the maker of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/all-candy-casino-slots-jewels/id788815470&quot;&gt;All Candy Casino Slots &amp;#x2013; Jewel Craze Connect: Big Blast Mania Land&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Benny&amp;#x2019;s game, which shares no similarities with King&amp;#x2019;s properties aside from the word &amp;#x2018;candy,&amp;#x2019; is one of a number of games that have been targeted by King.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;gallery colorbox-load&quot; title=&quot;news&quot; href=&quot;http://2a34166a1c224507ff54-79590be14f37a3e58649da10f58ee927.r67.cf1.rackcdn.com/news/full/1390231848.&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2a34166a1c224507ff54-79590be14f37a3e58649da10f58ee927.r67.cf1.rackcdn.com/news/medium/1390231847.&quot; alt=&quot;news&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hsu contacted Sophie Hallstrom, King&amp;#x2019;s IP paralegal, to discuss the matter further. Rather than the simple &amp;#x201C;oops, our mistake&amp;#x201D; that Benny was hoping for, he was given a very finite response. &amp;#x201C;Your use of CANDY SLOTS in your app icon uses our CANDY trade mark exactly, for identical goods, which amounts to trade mark infringement and is likely to lead to consumer confusion and damage to our brand,&amp;#x201D; reads Hallstrom&amp;#x2019;s reply. &amp;#x201C;The addition of only the descriptive term &quot;SLOTS&quot; does nothing to lessen the likelihood of confusion.&amp;#x201D;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So how does a word like &amp;#x2018;candy&amp;#x2019; get trademarked? According to Martin Schwimmer, a partner at the IP legal firm &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.leasonellis.com/&quot;&gt;Leeson Ellis&lt;/a&gt; (and the man behind &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trademarkblog.com/&quot;&gt;The Trademark Blog&lt;/a&gt;), it&amp;#x2019;s all about how strong a connection the claimant has to that mark when it comes to a particular good or service. Think of Apple, for example. Nobody is going to expect the electronics giant to lay claim over the fruit, but if someone were to try to market an electronic device under that name, you&amp;#x2019;d better believe their lawyers would swoop in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So the question then, is whether or not there&amp;#x2019;s a strong enough connection between the word &amp;#x2018;candy&amp;#x2019; and video games as it pertains to &lt;em&gt;Candy Crush Saga&lt;/em&gt;. According to the US Trademark Office, the answer is a bona fide yes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still, holding a trademark and being able to enforce it are entirely different things. Schwimmer is quick to point out the difference between suggestive marks and unique ones. &amp;#x201C;Someone can't plausibly claim that they came up with the term TEENAGE MUTANT NINJA TURTLES on their own. &amp;#xA0;An incredibly unique trademark like that is somewhat easy to protect.&amp;#x201D; But something generic &amp;#x2013; a dictionary word like candy? That can be a lot trickier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;gallery colorbox-load&quot; title=&quot;news&quot; href=&quot;http://2a34166a1c224507ff54-79590be14f37a3e58649da10f58ee927.r67.cf1.rackcdn.com/news/full/1390231780.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2a34166a1c224507ff54-79590be14f37a3e58649da10f58ee927.r67.cf1.rackcdn.com/news/medium/1390231778.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;news&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Benny Hsu's &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/all-candy-casino-slots-jewels/id788815470&quot;&gt;All Candy Casino Slots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x201C;Suggestive marks are protectable, but the problem is that third parties can claim that they thought up their mark on their own.&amp;#x201D; And in the case of something as generic as &amp;#x2018;candy,&amp;#x2019; it doesn&amp;#x2019;t seem that farfetched to think that a lot of developers may have.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x201C;As to how far King can enforce its rights, it will be a function of how strong its mark has become, and how similar the third party name is. &amp;#xA0;It would likely be able to enforce its rights against marks that are connotatively, phonetically or visually similar, for games that are conceivably competitive,&amp;#x201D; Schwimmer tells us. &amp;#x201C;King can't go after candy companies because candy companies don't use the term CANDY as a trademark &amp;#x2013; they use it to identify their product.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#x2019;re a developer who has received one of these letters from King, Schwimmer&amp;#x2019;s advice is simple: call a lawyer. &amp;#x201C;A trademark lawyer can be very useful in obtaining a coexistence agreement. &amp;#xA0;Often a trademark owner will accept a settlement in which the possibility of confusion is mitigated, perhaps because the developer will not expand into areas more directly competitive with the trademark owner.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But in an App Store littered with small indie developers, this is an option that seems out of reach for developers like Benny Hsu. &amp;#x201C;Myself and other indie developers don't have the money or resources to fight back&amp;#x2026; I plan on changing the name if that is what I must do.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With Apple seemingly complicit in King&amp;#x2019;s claims &amp;#x2013; the letter Tsu initially received came through the iTunes legal department &amp;#x2013; one can&amp;#x2019;t help but wonder what the future of the App Store and suggestive trademarks might be.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x201C;Last year I learned I couldn't use the word MEMORY because it was trademarked,&amp;#x201D; said Hsu. &amp;#x201C;Now I wonder what other common words will be trademarked in the App Store.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;tags&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Read more:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gamezebo.com/tag/candy-crush-saga&quot;&gt;Candy Crush Saga&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gamezebo.com/tag/king&quot;&gt;King&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gamezebo.com/tag/copyright&quot;&gt;copyright&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
 
 
 
 
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Candy Crush Saga creators have trademarked the word “candy”
</title>
</item>
<item>
<author>
Dan Levine
</author>
<link>
http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/01/20/us-google-iv-trial-idUSBREA0J0PC20140120
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;articleLocation&quot;&gt;SAN FRANCISCO&lt;/span&gt; (Reuters) - Intellectual Ventures is set to square off this week against Google Inc's Motorola Mobility unit in the first trial that the multibillion-dollar patent-buying firm has undertaken since it was founded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Privately-held Intellectual Ventures sued Motorola in 2011, claiming the mobile phone maker infringed patents covering a variety of smartphone-related technologies, including Google Play. Motorola has denied the allegations and will now go to trial over three of those patents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Barring any last-minute settlements, jury selection is scheduled to begin on Tuesday at a federal court in Wilmington, Delaware.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The trial takes place amid an unfolding debate in Congress over patent reform, in which Intellectual Ventures and Google are on opposite sides. Google is backing attempts to curb software patents and make it easier to fight lawsuits, while IV has warned that Congress should not act too rashly to weaken patent owners' rights.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;IV and other patent aggregators have faced criticism from some in the technology industry, who argue that patent litigation and royalty payments have become a burdensome tax on innovation. They say firms like IV, which do not primarily make products, are exploiting the patent system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But IV argues that unlike some of the firms denounced as &quot;patent trolls,&quot; it invests only in quality intellectual property and does not file frivolous lawsuits. IV also says it helps inventors get paid for their innovations while helping tech companies protect and manage their intellectual property.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Should the Delaware jury rule against Motorola and uphold IV's patents, it could bolster the firm's argument that it does not buy frivolous patents, said Shubha Ghosh, a University of Wisconsin Law School professor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet a win for Motorola could be held up as evidence that the U.S. government issues too many dubious patents. And even if IV prevails, Google could still argue that patent litigation before a jury of non-expert citizens is akin to a lottery, said Ghosh, who supports patent reform.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Just because you have a winning ticket doesn't mean it's not still a lottery,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;IV and Google both declined to comment on the upcoming trial.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since its founding in 2000, IV has raised about $6 billion (3.6 billion pounds) from investors and has bought tens of thousands of intellectual property assets from a variety of sources. Google was an investor in IV's first patent acquisition fund, but did not join later vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;IV filed a barrage of lawsuits in 2010 against companies in various sectors, and most defendants have since settled.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;THE INVENTORS&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two of the patents in the upcoming Motorola trial cover inventions by Richard Reisman, U.S. government records show. Through his company, Teleshuttle, Reisman has developed several patent portfolios for various technologies, including an online update service, according to the Teleshuttle website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;IV claims that the two Reisman patents cover several of Motorola's older-generation cellphones that have Google Play, a platform for Android smartphone apps. Motorola argues that IV's patents should never have been issued because the inventions were known in the field already.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reisman did not respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the patents in play against Motorola has been in a courtroom before. Teleshuttle and a British partner, BTG, sued Microsoft and Apple in 2004 using one of the same patents now in play against Motorola.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2006, Teleshuttle and BTG sold their patent rights to Delaware-based Twintech EU LLC for $35 million up front, plus a percentage of future licensing fees, according to BTG's website. At the same time as the sale, BTG and Teleshuttle abruptly withdrew their cases against Apple and Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft and Apple were both early investors in Intellectual Ventures. IV often uses subsidiary companies to buy patents, and then transfer them at a later date to related corporate entities, though public records do not indicate whether IV had an ownership interest in Twintech.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;IV took title on the patents from Twintech in September 2011 and sued Motorola a month later, U.S. records show. In a 2011 blog post, Reisman wrote that his deal with IV provided resources &quot;to let me focus on my work as an inventor.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft declined to comment while Apple did not respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another patent being asserted against Motorola was originally issued to Rajendra Kumar in 2006. Kumar's company, Khyber Technologies, transferred it to Balustare Processing NY LLC in July 2011, which passed it over to IV about a month later, patent records show.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Khyber Technologies was founded in 1991 with the goal of creating the next generation of handheld computing products, according to its website. The patent that IV obtained from Khyber covers detachable handset technology, which IV claims Motorola used in its defunct Lapdock product.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kumar declined to comment on the IV lawsuit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If IV wins, damages will be decided at a later proceeding. The trial is expected to last about ten days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The case in U.S. District Court, District of Delaware is Intellectual Ventures I and Intellectual Ventures II, 11-908.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Reporting by Dan Levine; editing by Jonathan Weber)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Google set to face Intellectual Ventures in landmark patent trial
</title>
</item>
<item>
<link>
http://www.esa.int/Our_Activities/Space_Science/Rosetta/ESA_s_sleeping_beauty_wakes_up_from_deep_space_hibernation
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;layout&quot;&gt;
            
            
            &lt;div id=&quot;container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                                
                



                    




                        
                

                
                                
                
                                
                
                
                &lt;div id=&quot;content&quot;&gt;                                             

                                        
                    
                    
                                            
                        
                        
                        
                                                
                                                                        
                        
                        &lt;div id=&quot;content_box&quot;&gt;                        
                            
                            &lt;div id=&quot;col3_c&quot;&gt;

                                
                                
                                                                
                                
                                                                                               
                                
                                                                
                                
                                
                                
                                                                
                                                                                                
                                
                                





    
    







       

		                				
    
        
          
        
    
    











    


    


            
                                     
    




    
        

        
                
    
                                                  
    




&lt;div id=&quot;article&quot;&gt;

        
&lt;div class=&quot;article_header&quot;&gt;
        
    &lt;div class=&quot;img_obj img_full&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;img&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.esa.int/ESA_Multimedia/Images/2014/01/Rosetta_Wake-up_signal&quot;&gt;                                  &lt;img src=&quot;http://www.esa.int/var/esa/storage/images/esa_multimedia/images/2014/01/rosetta_wake-up_signal/13492304-2-eng-GB/Rosetta_Wake-up_signal_large.jpg&quot; width=&quot;625&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;p class=&quot;txt&quot;&gt;Rosetta Wake-up signal&lt;/p&gt;        &lt;/div&gt; 
            &lt;/div&gt;
        
        
&lt;/div&gt;    



&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;art_date&quot;&gt;20 January 2014&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
It was a fairy-tale ending to a tense chapter in the story of the Rosetta space mission this evening as ESA heard from its distant spacecraft for the first time in 31 months.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
Rosetta is chasing down Comet 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko, where it will become the first space mission to rendezvous with a comet, the first to attempt a landing on a comet&amp;#x2019;s surface, and the first to follow a comet as it swings around the Sun.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Since its launch in 2004, Rosetta has made three flybys of Earth and one of Mars to help it on course to its rendezvous with 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko, encountering asteroids Steins and Lutetia along the way.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Operating on solar energy alone, Rosetta was placed into a deep space slumber in June 2011 as it cruised out to a distance of nearly 800 million km from the warmth of the Sun, beyond the orbit of Jupiter.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Now, as Rosetta&amp;#x2019;s orbit has brought it back to within &amp;#x2018;only&amp;#x2019; 673 million km from the Sun, there is enough solar energy to power the spacecraft fully again.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 
                

    &lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;s_1&quot;&gt;
        
        
                
                    
                                                
                                                            
        
       
        
                
                                    
                        
            
                             
            











    


    


            
                                     
    




            
                                    
                                                    
                                  
            
                
                        
                                    
                        
                        
               
                        
            
                        
            
            

            
            &lt;div class=&quot;img_obj l_img&quot;&gt;
                
                                    &lt;div class=&quot;img&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.esa.int/ESA_Multimedia/Images/2013/01/Rosetta_calls_home&quot;&gt;                        
                        &lt;img src=&quot;http://www.esa.int/var/esa/storage/images/esa_multimedia/images/2013/01/rosetta_calls_home/13489284-1-eng-GB/Rosetta_calls_home_medium.jpg&quot; width=&quot;305&quot; alt=&quot;Rosetta calls home&quot;&gt;

                                                &lt;/a&gt;
                        &lt;p class=&quot;txt&quot;&gt;Rosetta calls home&lt;/p&gt;                    &lt;/div&gt; 
                            &lt;/div&gt;

                
        
        &lt;p&gt;
Thus today, still about 9 million km from the comet, Rosetta&amp;#x2019;s pre-programmed internal &amp;#x2018;alarm clock&amp;#x2019; woke up the spacecraft. After warming up its key navigation instruments, coming out of a stabilising spin, and aiming its main radio antenna at Earth, Rosetta sent a signal to let mission operators know it had survived the most distant part of its journey.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The signal was received by both NASA&amp;#x2019;s Goldstone and Canberra ground stations at 18:18 GMT/ 19:18 CET, during the first window of opportunity the spacecraft had to communicate with Earth. It was immediately confirmed in ESA&amp;#x2019;s space operations centre in Darmstadt and the successful wake-up announced via the @ESA_Rosetta twitter account, which tweeted: &amp;#x201C;Hello, World!&amp;#x201D;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&amp;#x201C;We have our comet-chaser back,&amp;#x201D; says Alvaro Gim&amp;#xE9;nez, ESA&amp;#x2019;s Director of Science and Robotic Exploration. &amp;#x201C;With Rosetta, we will take comet exploration to a new level. This incredible mission continues our history of &amp;#x2018;firsts&amp;#x2019; at comets, building on the technological and scientific achievements of our first deep space mission Giotto, which returned the first close-up images of a comet nucleus as it flew past Halley in 1986.&amp;#x201D;
&lt;/p&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;                

    &lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;s_2&quot;&gt;
        
        
                
                    
                                                
                                                            
        
       
        
                
                                    
                        
            
                             
            







  
    



    


    


                




            
                                    
                                                    
                                  
            
                
                        
                                    
                        
                        
               
             
                
                                                                        
                                        
            
                        
            
            

            
            

                
        
        &lt;p&gt;
&amp;#x201C;This was one alarm clock not to hit snooze on, and after a tense day we are absolutely delighted to have our spacecraft awake and back online,&amp;#x201D; adds Fred Jansen, ESA&amp;#x2019;s Rosetta mission manager.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Comets are considered the primitive building blocks of the Solar System and likely helped to &amp;#x2018;seed&amp;#x2019; Earth with water, perhaps even the ingredients for life. But many fundamental questions about these enigmatic objects remain, and through its comprehensive, in situ study of Comet 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko, Rosetta aims to unlock the secrets contained within.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&amp;#x201C;All other comet missions have been flybys, capturing fleeting moments in the life of these icy treasure chests,&amp;#x201D; says Matt Taylor, ESA&amp;#x2019;s Rosetta project scientist. &amp;#x201C;With Rosetta, we will track the evolution of a comet on a daily basis and for over a year, giving us a unique insight into a comet&amp;#x2019;s behaviour and ultimately helping us to decipher their role in the formation of the Solar System.&amp;#x201D;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But first, essential health checks on the spacecraft must be completed. Then the eleven instruments on the orbiter and ten on the lander will be turned on and prepared for studying Comet 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&amp;#x201C;We have a busy few months ahead preparing the spacecraft and its instruments for the operational challenges demanded by a lengthy, close-up study of a comet that, until we get there, we know very little about,&amp;#x201D; says Andrea Accomazzo, ESA&amp;#x2019;s Rosetta operations manager.
&lt;/p&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;                

    &lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;s_3&quot;&gt;
        
        
                
                    
                                                
                                                            
        
       
        
                
                                    
                        
            
                             
            














    


            
                                     
    




            
                                    
                                                    
                                  
            
                
                        
                                    
                        
                        
               
                        
            
                        
            
            

            
            &lt;div class=&quot;img_obj l_img&quot;&gt;
                
                                    &lt;div class=&quot;img&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.esa.int/ESA_Multimedia/Images/2013/12/Rosetta_and_Philae_at_comet6&quot;&gt;                        
                        &lt;img src=&quot;http://www.esa.int/var/esa/storage/images/esa_multimedia/images/2013/12/rosetta_and_philae_at_comet6/13463574-2-eng-GB/Rosetta_and_Philae_at_comet_medium.jpg&quot; width=&quot;305&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;

                                                &lt;/a&gt;
                        &lt;p class=&quot;txt&quot;&gt;Rosetta and Philae at comet &lt;/p&gt;                    &lt;/div&gt; 
                            &lt;/div&gt;

                
        
        &lt;p&gt;
Rosetta&amp;#x2019;s first images of 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko are expected in May, when the spacecraft is still 2 million km from its target. Towards the end of May, the spacecraft will execute a major manoeuvre to line up for its critical rendezvous with the comet in August.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
After rendezvous, Rosetta will start with two months of extensive mapping of the comet&amp;#x2019;s surface, and will also make important measurements of the comet&amp;#x2019;s gravity, mass and shape, and assess its gaseous, dust-laden atmosphere, or coma. The orbiter will also probe the plasma environment and analyse how it interacts with the Sun&amp;#x2019;s outer atmosphere, the solar wind.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Using these data, scientists will choose a landing site for the mission&amp;#x2019;s 100 kg Philae probe. The landing is currently scheduled for 11 November and will be the first time that a landing on a comet has ever been attempted.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In fact, given the almost negligible gravity of the comet&amp;#x2019;s 4 km-wide nucleus, Philae will have to use ice screws and harpoons to stop it from rebounding back into space after touchdown.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Among its wide range of scientific measurements, Philae will send back a panorama of its surroundings, as well as very high-resolution pictures of the surface. It will also perform an on-the-spot analysis of the composition of the ices and organic material, including drilling down to 23 cm below the surface and feeding samples to Philae&amp;#x2019;s on-board laboratory for analysis.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The focus of the mission will then move to the &amp;#x2018;escort&amp;#x2019; phase, during which Rosetta will stay alongside the comet as it moves closer to the Sun, monitoring the ever-changing conditions on the surface as the comet warms up and its ices sublimate.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The comet will reach its closest distance to the Sun on 13 August 2015 at about 185 million km, roughly between the orbits of Earth and Mars. Rosetta will follow the comet throughout the remainder of 2015, as it heads away from the Sun and activity begins to subside.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&amp;#x201C;We will face many challenges this year as we explore the unknown territory of comet 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko and I&amp;#x2019;m sure there will be plenty of surprises, but today we are just extremely happy to be back on speaking terms with our spacecraft,&amp;#x201D; adds Matt Taylor.
&lt;/p&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;    
 

                    
        
          
        
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;div id=&quot;indepth&quot;&gt;


        
                        

    &lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;s_4&quot;&gt;
        
        
                
                
        
       
                
        
        &lt;p&gt;
In 1964, the Conventions of the European Launcher Development Organisation (ELDO) and the European Space Research Organisation (ESRO) entered into force. A little more than a decade later, the European Space Agency (ESA) was established, taking over from these two organisations.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
2014 will be dedicated to addressing the future in the light of these 50 years of unique achievements in space, which have put ESA among the leading space agencies in the world.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The motto 'serving European cooperation and innovation' underlines how much ESA, together with the national delegations from its 20 Member States, space industry and the scientific community, has made a difference.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Fifty years of European cooperation in space is an anniversary for the whole space sector in Europe, which can be proud of its results and achievements. But it is more than that: it is a testimony that the idea of Europe, European identity and progress has been served by ESA, and that continues to be its mission for the future.
&lt;/p&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;                        

    &lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;s_5&quot;&gt;
        
        
                
                
        
       
                
        
        &lt;p&gt;
The European Space Agency (ESA) is Europe's gateway to space.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
ESA is an intergovernmental organisation, created in 1975, with the mission to shape the development of Europe's space capability and ensure that investment in space delivers benefits to the citizens of Europe and the world.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
ESA has 20 Member States: Austria, Belgium, the Czech Republic, Denmark, Finland, France, Germany, Greece, Ireland, Italy, Luxembourg, the Netherlands, Norway, Poland, Portugal, Romania, Spain, Sweden, Switzerland and the United Kingdom, of whom 18 are Member States of the EU.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
ESA has Cooperation Agreements with eight other Member States of the EU. Canada takes part in some ESA programmes under a Cooperation Agreement.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
ESA is also working actively with the EU, for the implementation of the programmes Galileo and Copernicus.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
By coordinating the financial and intellectual resources of its members, ESA can undertake programmes and activities far beyond the scope of any single European country.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
ESA develops the launchers, spacecraft and ground facilities needed to keep Europe at the forefront of global space activities.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Today, it launches satellites for Earth observation, navigation, telecommunications and astronomy, sends probes to the far reaches of the Solar System and cooperates in the human exploration of space.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Learn more at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.esa.int/&quot;&gt;www.esa.int&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;

For further information:&lt;br&gt;
ESA Media Relations Office&lt;br&gt;
Email: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:media@esa.int&quot;&gt;media@esa.int&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Tel: +33 1 53 69 72 99
&lt;/p&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;                        
                        
                        
                        
                
        &lt;/div&gt;

     
    
    



&lt;div id=&quot;social&quot;&gt;










    &lt;table cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;th&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Rate this&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/th&gt;            &lt;th&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Views&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;th class=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Share&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attribute-star-rating&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;starrating&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;ezsr_rating_13487712&quot; class=&quot;ezsr-star-rating&quot;&gt;
   &lt;li id=&quot;ezsr_rating_percent_13487712&quot; class=&quot;ezsr-current-rating&quot;&gt;Currently &lt;span&gt;5&lt;/span&gt; out of 5 Stars.&lt;/li&gt;
   
             &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;ezsr_13487712_5_1&quot; title=&quot;Rate 1 stars out of 5&quot; class=&quot;ezsr-stars-1&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;ezsr_13487712_5_2&quot; title=&quot;Rate 2 stars out of 5&quot; class=&quot;ezsr-stars-2&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;ezsr_13487712_5_3&quot; title=&quot;Rate 3 stars out of 5&quot; class=&quot;ezsr-stars-3&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;ezsr_13487712_5_4&quot; title=&quot;Rate 4 stars out of 5&quot; class=&quot;ezsr-stars-4&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;ezsr_13487712_5_5&quot; title=&quot;Rate 5 stars out of 5&quot; class=&quot;ezsr-stars-5&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    
Rating: &lt;span id=&quot;ezsr_average_13487712&quot; class=&quot;ezsr-average-rating&quot;&gt;4.82&lt;/span&gt;/5
(&lt;span id=&quot;ezsr_total_13487712&quot;&gt;325&lt;/span&gt; votes cast)
 
&lt;p id=&quot;ezsr_just_rated_13487712&quot; class=&quot;ezsr-just-rated hide&quot;&gt;Thank you for rating!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ezsr_has_rated_13487712&quot; class=&quot;ezsr-has-rated hide&quot;&gt;You have already rated this page, you can only rate it once!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ezsr_changed_rating_13487712&quot; class=&quot;ezsr-changed-rating hide&quot;&gt;Your rating has been changed, thanks for rating!&lt;/p&gt;
    
            
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;views&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;viewcount&quot;&gt;70033&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;right&quot;&gt;
                
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



    
    
    
    

&lt;/div&gt;












 
    
                                
                                
                                
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    

                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                                                
                                
                                
                                
                                  
                                
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                            
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    
                    
                                      
                &lt;/div&gt;
                  

                
                






                


                
                
                                
                



&lt;div id=&quot;sb&quot;&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt; 


        
    
            
                           
                    
                        
                                                
            
                        
                            
                
                                                
                 
                    
                    
                    
                                                                                




  		
                                                                 
                                
             
            
                        
                &lt;li&gt;
                &lt;li class=&quot;sb_sep&quot;&gt;                                
            
                    
                        
                                                
            
                        
                            
                
                                                
                 
                    
                    
                    
                                                                                




  		
                                                                 
                                
             
            
                        
                &lt;li&gt;
                &lt;li class=&quot;sb_sep&quot;&gt;                                
            
                    
                        
                                                
            
                        
                                            
                
                                




  		
                                                    
             
            
                        
                &lt;li&gt;
                &lt;li class=&quot;sb_sep&quot;&gt;                                
            
                    
                        
                                                
            
                        
                                            
                
                                




  		
                                                    
             
            
                        
                &lt;li&gt;
                &lt;li class=&quot;sb_sep&quot;&gt;                                
            
                    
                        
                                                
            
                        
                                            
                
                                




  		
                                                    
             
            
                        
                &lt;li&gt;
                &lt;li class=&quot;sb_sep&quot;&gt;                                
            
                       
        
        &lt;/ul&gt;
    
    
&lt;/div&gt;
                                
                
                                
                
                
                
                       
            &lt;/div&gt; 
            
        &lt;/li&gt;
        
        
    &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Rosetta: ESA’s ‘sleeping beauty’ wakes up from deep space hibernation
</title>
</item>
<item>
<author>
Also on The Switch, How candidate Obama would've replied to President Obama's NSA speech
</author>
<link>
http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/the-switch/wp/2014/01/17/half-of-taxpayer-funded-research-will-soon-be-available-to-the-public/
</link>
<description>
&lt;article id=&quot;post-14394&quot; class=&quot;post-14394 post type-post status-publish format-standard hentry category-uncategorized&quot; score=&quot;51.25&quot;&gt;
		&lt;header class=&quot;entry-header&quot;&gt;
			&lt;/header&gt;
		
		&lt;div id=&quot;post-content&quot; class=&quot;cf entry-content&quot; score=&quot;33.75&quot;&gt;
		
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_14417&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-14417&quot; alt=&quot;(Horia Varlan)&quot; src=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/the-switch/files/2014/01/testtubes.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/10361931@N06/4290846294/in/photolist-7xaH7w-cYAJ7h-cYAJPG-cYACQA-cYADSs-cYAJuy-cYAJEN-cYAG2E-cYAD9U-cYAEYN-cYAFSS-cYAFAf-cYAKxJ-cYACZj-cYAHTu-cYAHrb-cYAErq-cYAH8U-cYAK9Q-cYADpC-cYAHxJ-cYADH7-cYAEH9-cYAKnS-cYAERy-cYAGN9-cYAF89-cYAE37-cYAGXU-cYAFgU-cYAJZS-cYAKXd-cYAHgS-cYAKJ3-cYACuo-cYAEyS-cYACkf-cYAHGb-cYADgy-cYACFb-cYAFqW-cYAFLd-bwWBiK-8BPqqs-dfF1ZQ-8f1j6D-eLjUWp-eLjUKe-eLjV9e-hRKZPe-cQkE4h&quot;&gt;Horia Varlan&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proponents of the open access model for academic research notched a huge victory Thursday night when Congress passed a budget that will make about half of taxpayer-funded research available to the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep inside the $1.1 trillion Consolidated Appropriations Act for 2014 is a provision that requires federal agencies under the Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education portion of the bill with research budgets of $100 million or more to provide the public with online access to the research that they fund within 12 months of publication in a peer-reviewed journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;According to the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sparc.arl.org/news/omnibus-appropriations-bill-codifies-white-house-directive&quot;&gt;Scholarly Publishing and Academic Resources Coalition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt; (SPARC), this means approximately $31 billion of the total $60 billion annual U.S. investment in taxpayer-funded research will become openly accessible. “This is an important step toward making federally funded scientific research available for everyone to use online at no cost,” said SPARC Executive Director Heather Joseph in a news  release. The language in the appropriations bill mirrors that in the White House &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2013/02/22/expanding-public-access-results-federally-funded-research&quot;&gt;open access memo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt; from last year, and a National Institutes of Health public access program &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://publicaccess.nih.gov/policy.htm&quot;&gt;enacted in 2008&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sen. Tom Harkin (D-Iowa) who was instrumental in getting the NIH program launched told The Post: &quot;Expanding this policy to public health and education research is a step toward a more transparent government and better science.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the government funds a significant chunk of academic research in the United States, most taxpayers do not have access to the results of that research, which is often kept in pay-walled databases controlled by commercial publishers. As the Internet has made it far easier for academics to share their research results, many have pushed for a more open system that allows public sharing of scholarly research commonly called &quot;open access.&quot; But some publishers have &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/the-switch/wp/2013/12/19/how-one-publisher-is-stopping-academics-from-sharing-their-research/&quot;&gt;cracked down&lt;/a&gt;, even going after individual professors who post their research on their university Web pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, Congress has considered various legislative proposals concerning access to publicly funded research. The Fair Access to Science and Technology Research Act would have mandated that publicly funded research be freed up within six months of publication. Another, the Research Works Act, would have effectively prohibited open access mandates and rolled back the NIH's public access program.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;entry-footer&quot; score=&quot;0.0&quot;&gt;
		
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
		
&lt;/article&gt;

</description>
<title>
Half of taxpayer funded research will soon be available to the public
</title>
</item>
<item>
<link>
http://www.gigamonkeys.com/code-reading/
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;contents&quot;&gt;
          
          &lt;p class=&quot;dateline&quot;&gt;
          20 January 2014
          &lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;I have started code reading groups at the last two companies I&amp;#x2019;ve worked at, Etsy and Twitter, and some folks have asked for my advice about code reading and running code reading groups. Tl;dr: don&amp;#x2019;t start a code reading group. What you should start instead I&amp;#x2019;ll get to in a moment but first I need to explain how I arrived at my current opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;As a former English major and a sometimes writer, I had always been drawn to the idea that code is like literature and that we ought to learn to write code the way we learn to write English: by reading good examples. And I&amp;#x2019;m certainly not the only one to have taken this point of view&amp;#x2014;Donald Knuth, in addition to his work on &lt;em&gt;The Art of Computer Programming&lt;/em&gt; and TeX, has long been a proponent of what he calls Literate Programming and has published several of his large programs as books.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;On the other hand, long before I got to Etsy and started my first code reading group I had in hand several pieces of evidence that should have suggested to me that this was the wrong way to look at things.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;First, when I did my book of interviews with programmers, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codersatwork.com&quot;&gt;Coders at Work&lt;/a&gt;, I asked pretty much everyone about code reading. And while most of them said it was important and that programmers should do it more, when I asked them about what code they had read recently, very few of them had any great answers. Some of them had done some serious code reading as young hackers but almost no one seemed to have a regular habit of reading code. Knuth, the great synthesizer of computer science, does seem to read a lot of code and Brad Fitzpatrick was able to talk about several pieces of open source code that he had read just for the heck of it. But they were the exceptions.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;If that wasn&amp;#x2019;t enough, after I finished &lt;em&gt;Coders&lt;/em&gt; I had a chance to &lt;a href=&quot;http://codequarterly.com/2011/hal-abelson/&quot;&gt;interview Hal Abelson&lt;/a&gt;, the famous MIT professor and co-author of the &lt;em&gt;Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs&lt;/em&gt;. The first time I talked to him I asked my usual question about reading code and he gave the standard answer&amp;#x2014;that it was important and we should do it more. But he too failed to name any code he had read recently other than code he was obliged to: reviewing co-workers&amp;#x2019; code at Google where he was on sabbatical and grading student code at MIT. Later I asked him about this disconnect:&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Seibel:&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;#x2019;m still curious about this split between what people say and what they actually do. Everyone says, &amp;#x201C;People should read code&amp;#x201D; but few people seem to actually do it. I&amp;#x2019;d be surprised if I interviewed a novelist and asked them what the last novel they had read was, and they said, &amp;#x201C;Oh, I haven&amp;#x2019;t really read a novel since I was in grad school.&amp;#x201D; Writers actually read other writers but it doesn&amp;#x2019;t seem that programmers really do, even though we say we should.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abelson:&lt;/em&gt; Yeah. You&amp;#x2019;re right. But remember, a lot of times you crud up a program to make it finally work and do all of the things that you need it to do, so there&amp;#x2019;s a lot of extraneous stuff around there that isn&amp;#x2019;t the core idea.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Seibel:&lt;/em&gt; So basically you&amp;#x2019;re saying that in the end, most code isn&amp;#x2019;t worth reading?&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abelson:&lt;/em&gt; Or it&amp;#x2019;s built from an initial plan or some kind of pseudocode. A lot of the code in books, they have some very cleaned-up version that doesn&amp;#x2019;t do all the stuff it needs to make it work.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Seibel:&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;#x2019;m thinking of the preface to SICP, where it says, &amp;#x201C;programs must be written for people to read and only incidentally for machines to execute.&amp;#x201D; But it seems the reality you just described is that in fact, most programs are written for machines to execute and only incidentally, if at all, for people to read.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abelson:&lt;/em&gt; Well, I think they start out for people to read, because there&amp;#x2019;s some idea there. You explain stuff. That&amp;#x2019;s a little bit of what we have in the book. There are some fairly significant programs in the book, like the compiler. And that&amp;#x2019;s partly because we think the easiest way to explain what it&amp;#x2019;s doing is to express that in code.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;Yet somehow even this explicit acknowledgement that most real code isn&amp;#x2019;t actually in a form that can be simply read wasn&amp;#x2019;t enough to lead me to abandon the literature seminar model when I got to Etsy. For our first meeting I picked Jeremy Ashkenas&amp;#x2019;s backbone.js because many of the Etsy developers would be familiar with Javascript and because I know Jeremy is particularly interested in writing readable code. I still envisioned something like a literature seminar but I figured that a lot of people wouldn&amp;#x2019;t actually have done the reading in advance (well, maybe not so different from a literature seminar) so I decided to start things off by presenting the code myself before the group discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;As I prepared my presentation, I found myself falling into my usual pattern when trying to really understand a piece of code&amp;#x2014;in order to grok it I have to essentially rewrite it. I&amp;#x2019;ll start by renaming a few things so they make more sense to me and then I&amp;#x2019;ll move things around to suit my ideas about how to organize code. Pretty soon I&amp;#x2019;ll have gotten deep into the abstractions (or lack thereof) of the code and will start making bigger changes to the structure of the code. Once I&amp;#x2019;ve completely rewritten the thing I usually understand it pretty well and can even go back to the original and understand it too. I have always felt kind of bad about this approach to code reading but it's the only thing that's ever worked for me.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;My presentation to the code reading group started with stock backbone.js and then walked through the changes I would make to it to make it, by my lights, more understandable. At one point I asked if people thought we should move on to the group discussion but nobody seemed very interested. Hopefully seeing my refactoring gave people some of the same insights into the underlying structure of the original that I had obtained by doing the refactoring.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;The second meeting of the Etsy code reading group featured Avi Bryant demonstrating how to use the code browsing capabilities of Smalltalk to navigate through some code. In that case, because few of the Etsy engineers had any experience with Smalltalk, we had no expectation that folks would read the code in advance. But the presentation was an awesome chance for folks to get exposed to the power of the Smalltalk development environment and for me to heckle Avi about Smalltalk vs Lisp differences.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          &lt;p&gt;When I got to Twitter I inexplicably still had the literature seminar model in mind even though neither of the two meetings of the Etsy reading group&amp;#x2014;which folks seemed to like pretty well&amp;#x2014;followed that model at all. When I sent out the email inviting Twitter engineers to join a code reading group the response was pretty enthusiastic. The first meeting was, yet again, a presentation of some code, in this case the internals of the Scala implementation of Future that is used throughout Twitter&amp;#x2019;s many services, presented by Marius Eriksen, who wrote most of it.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;It was sometime after that presentation that I finally realized the obvious: code is not literature. We don&amp;#x2019;t read code, we &lt;em&gt;decode&lt;/em&gt; it. We examine it. A piece of code is not literature; it is a specimen. Knuth said something that should have pointed me down this track when I asked him about his own code reading:&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Knuth:&lt;/em&gt; But it&amp;#x2019;s really worth it for what it builds in your brain. So how do I do it? There was a machine called the Bunker Ramo 300 and somebody told me that the Fortran compiler for this machine was really amazingly fast, but nobody had any idea why it worked. I got a copy of the source-code listing for it. I didn&amp;#x2019;t have a manual for the machine, so I wasn&amp;#x2019;t even sure what the machine language was.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;But I took it as an interesting challenge. I could figure out &lt;code&gt;BEGIN&lt;/code&gt; and then I would start to decode. The operation codes had some two-letter mnemonics and so I could start to figure out &amp;#x201C;This probably was a load instruction, this probably was a branch.&amp;#x201D; And I knew it was a Fortran compiler, so at some point it looked at column seven of a card, and that was where it would tell if it was a comment or not.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;After three hours I had figured out a little bit about the machine. Then I found these big, branching tables. So it was a puzzle and I kept just making little charts like I&amp;#x2019;m working at a security agency trying to decode a secret code. But I knew it worked and I knew it was a Fortran compiler&amp;#x2014;it wasn&amp;#x2019;t encrypted in the sense that it was intentionally obscure; it was only in code because I hadn&amp;#x2019;t gotten the manual for the machine.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;Eventually I was able to figure out why this compiler was so fast. Unfortunately it wasn&amp;#x2019;t because the algorithms were brilliant; it was just because they had used unstructured programming and hand optimized the code to the hilt.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;It was just basically the way you solve some kind of an unknown puzzle&amp;#x2014;make tables and charts and get a little more information here and make a hypothesis. In general when I&amp;#x2019;m reading a technical paper, it&amp;#x2019;s the same challenge. I&amp;#x2019;m trying to get into the author&amp;#x2019;s mind, trying to figure out what the concept is. The more you learn to read other people&amp;#x2019;s stuff, the more able you are to invent your own in the future, it seems to me.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;He&amp;#x2019;s not describing reading literature; he&amp;#x2019;s describing a scientific investigation. So now I have a new mode for how people should get together to gain insights from code which I explained to the Twitter code reading group like this:&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;Preparing for the talk I&amp;#x2019;m going to give to the Girls who Code cohort, I started thinking about what to tell them about code reading and code they should read. And once again it struck me that for all the lip service we pay to the idea of reading code, most programmers really don&amp;#x2019;t read that much code, at least not just for the sake of reading it. As a simple proof: name me one piece of code that you&amp;#x2019;ve read and that you can be reasonably sure that most other good programmers will have read or will at least have heard of. Not many, right? Probably none.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;But then it hit me. Code is not literature and we are not readers. Rather, interesting pieces of code are specimens and we are naturalists. So instead of trying to pick out a piece of code and reading it and then discussing it like a bunch of Comp Lit. grad students, I think a better model is for one of us to play the role of a 19th century naturalist returning from a trip to some exotic island to present to the local scientific society a discussion of the crazy beetles they found: &amp;#x201C;Look at the antenna on this monster! They look incredibly ungainly but the male of the species can use these to kill small frogs in whose carcass the females lay their eggs.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;The point of such a presentation is to take a piece of code that the presenter has understood deeply and for them to help the audience understand the core ideas by pointing them out amidst the layers of evolutionary detritus (a.k.a. kluges) that are also part of almost all code. One reasonable approach might be to show the real code and then to show a stripped down reimplementation of just the key bits, kind of like a biologist staining a specimen to make various features easier to discern.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;The ideal presentation should be aimed at an audience of gentleman and lady programmers&amp;#x2014;smart, and generally capable but without, necessarily, any specific knowledge of the domain from which the code comes. Presentations should provide enough context for the audience to to understand what the code is and should explain any details of the implementation language that may be obscure to the average programmer.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;Since I had my epihany we&amp;#x2019;ve had several meetings of the code reading group, now known as the Royal Society of Twitter for Improving Coding Knowledge, along the new lines. We&amp;#x2019;re still learning about the best ways to present code but the model feels very right. Also, I no longer feel bad about my dissection-based approach to reading code.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;The biggest lesson so far is that code is very dense. A half hour presentation is just enough time to present maybe a dozen meaty lines of code and one main idea. It is also almost certainly the case that the presenters, who have to actually really dig down into a piece of code, get more out of it than anybody. But it does seem that a good presentation can at least expose people to the main ideas and maybe give them a head start if they do decide to read the code themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Code is not Literature
</title>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
