<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version='2.0'>
<channel>
<generator>
clj-rss
</generator>
<link>
https://news.ycombinator.com
</link>
<title>
myread
</title>
<description>
myread
</description>
<item>
<link>
http://i.imgur.com/z44bhed.png
</link>
<description>

</description>
<title>
When cryptographic functions go bad
</title>
</item>
<item>
<link>
http://pastebin.com/yCw3eze1
</link>
<description>

</description>
<title>
A friend wrote this code for a class where we're graded on lines of code. I am horrified.
</title>
</item>
<item>
<author>
dbasch
</author>
<link>
http://diegobasch.com/dogecoin-and-the-appeal-of-small-numbers
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content&quot;&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Dogecoin is a unique phenomenon in the fascinating world of cryptocurrencies. It&amp;#x2019;s barely six weeks old, and as I write this post its network has more computing power than any other cryptocurrency except for Bitcoin. It made headlines this weekend when its community &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/jan/20/jamaican-bobsled-team-raises-dogecoin-winter-olympics&quot;&gt;raised enough money to send the Jamaican bobsled team to the Sochi Winter Olympics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a technical standpoint, Dogecoin is essentially a branded clone of Litecoin (the second cryptocurrency in terms of total market value). Without a doubt one of the most important factors contributing to Dogecoin&amp;#x2019;s popularity is its community. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/dogecoin/&quot;&gt;Dogecoin subreddit&lt;/a&gt; has almost 40k users right now. The front page usually has a good mix of humor, good will, finance, and technology. Check it out if you haven&amp;#x2019;t already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#x2019;s another more subtle factor that I believe plays in Dogecoin&amp;#x2019;s favor: its tiny value. One DOGE is worth about $0.0015 right now. In other words, one dollar buys you about 600-700 DOGE. Contrast that with Bitcoin: $1 is about 0.001 BTC. This puts Bitcoin and Dogecoin in two completely different mental buckets for most people. One BTC is comparable to an ounce of gold. The press &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=bitcoin+gold&amp;amp;tbm=nws&quot;&gt;reinforces this idea&lt;/a&gt;, and many people view Bitcoin as a digital store of value. The daily transaction volume of BTC is about 0.2 percent of the total bitcoins in existence, which means that BTC does not circulate very much yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contrast this with Dogecoin, for which the &lt;a href=&quot;http://coinmarketcap.com/&quot;&gt;daily transaction volume is close to 15%&lt;/a&gt;. Where does that money go? Perhaps the most common usage of DOGE is to give online tips. Compare the activity of Reddit&amp;#x2019;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/bitcointip&quot;&gt;bitcointip&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#xA0;and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en-us.reddit.com/user/dogetipbot&quot;&gt;dogetipbot&lt;/a&gt;, and you&amp;#x2019;ll see the latter is much more active. What would you prefer as a tip, 100 DOGE or 0.000002 BTC? Both are almost meaningless in terms of monetary value, but receiving 100 units of a coin does feel better. It&amp;#x2019;s also easier to give tips; you don&amp;#x2019;t have to think much about tipping someone 10, 25 or 100 DOGE. With BTC you either have to choose a dollar amount, or be very careful with the number of zeroes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason a DOGE is worth so little is the total supply of coins. The Bitcoin software has an embedded constant called MAX_MONEY. For Bitcoin it&amp;#x2019;s set to 21 million, which means that if Bitcoin takes over as a world currency it will be impossible for most people to ever own one. Litecoin is only slightly better, at 84 million. For DOGE, it&amp;#x2019;s one hundred billion (perhaps more, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dogecoin/dogecoin/issues/23&quot;&gt;yet to be decided&lt;/a&gt;). This makes it unlikely that one DOGE will be worth $1 any time soon (or ever). It&amp;#x2019;s easy and fun to exchange $20 for 10k DOGE and give a fraction of them to strangers on the internet. Anyone can still mine hundreds of dogecoins per day with a desktop computer, and not feel very attached to them. Being a &amp;#x201C;slumdoge millionaire&amp;#x201D; is still affordable to many.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a world where people get a kick out of likes or retweets, Dogetips take it up a notch. A Dogetip is an upvote that you can use, internet karma points that are actually worth something. So fun, very value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/NksbGlL.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image credit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/binxalot&quot;&gt;/u/binxalot&lt;/a&gt;, this person deserves tips. Of course I accept them too &lt;img src=&quot;http://diegobasch.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; class=&quot;wp-smiley&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DHpZsQCDKq9WbqyqfetMcGq87pFZfkwLBh
&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;

	
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Dogecoin and the Appeal of Small Numbers
</title>
</item>
<item>
<link>
http://www.megalith.co.uk/8086tiny/
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;text_area&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;About 8086tiny&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;8086tiny is a free, open source PC XT-compatible emulator/virtual machine written in C. It is, we believe, the smallest of its kind (the fully-commented source is under 25K). Despite its size, 8086tiny provides a highly accurate 8086 CPU emulation, together with support for PC peripherals including XT-style keyboard, floppy/hard disk, clock, and Hercules graphics. 8086tiny is powerful enough to run software like AutoCAD, Windows 3.0, and legacy PC games.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;8086tiny is highly portable and runs on practically any little endian machine, from simple 32-bit MCUs upwards. 8086tiny has successfully been deployed on 32-bit/64-bit Intel machines (Windows, Mac OS X and Linux), Nexus 4/ARM (Android), iPad 3 and iPhone 5S (iOS), and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.raspberrypi.org&quot;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt; (Linux).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The philosophy of 8086tiny is to keep the code base as small as possible, and through the open source license encourage individual developers to tune and extend it as per their specific requirements, adding support, for example, for more complex instruction sets (e.g. Pentium) or peripherals (e.g. mouse). Any questions, comments or suggestions are very welcome in our &lt;a href=&quot;http://8086tiny.freeforums.net&quot;&gt;forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;An obfuscated version of 8086tiny (condensed into just 4043 bytes of C code) was a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ioccc.org/years-spoiler.html#2013_cable3&quot;&gt;winner of the 2013 IOCCC contest&lt;/a&gt;. Significant interest followed for a documented, commented, maintainable version. The result is the distribution presented here.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;div class=&quot;section_box2&quot;&gt;
	        &lt;p class=&quot;post_title&quot;&gt;Feature Highlights&lt;/p&gt;
        	&lt;div class=&quot;text_area&quot;&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;8086tiny's feature highlights include:&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Highly accurate, complete 8086 CPU emulation (including undocumented features and behavior)&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Support for all standard PC peripherals: keyboard, 3.5&quot; floppy drive, hard drive, video (Hercules graphics and CGA color text mode, including direct video memory access), real-time clock, timers&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Disk images are compatible with standard Windows/Mac/UNIX mount tools for simple interoperability&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Complete source code provided (including custom BIOS)&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ul&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;8086tiny is highly portable, with minimal system requirements:&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Minimal C runtime library support required (uses POSIX file I/O and time functions only - no memory management or string functions)&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Uses SDL 1.2 for graphics, but can compile without SDL for text-only applications&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Storage requirement: typically around 20KB for compiled binary, 9KB for BIOS image, and 720KB/1.44MB for floppy disk image
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;System RAM requirement: around 1.5MB&lt;/li&gt;
        	&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      	&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;div class=&quot;section_box2&quot;&gt;
	        &lt;p class=&quot;post_title&quot;&gt;Screenshots&lt;/p&gt;
        	&lt;div class=&quot;text_area&quot;&gt;
			&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.megalith.co.uk/8086tiny/images/screenshot_dos.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.megalith.co.uk/8086tiny/images/screenshot_dos.png&quot; width=&quot;164&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.megalith.co.uk/8086tiny/images/screenshot_win3.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.megalith.co.uk/8086tiny/images/screenshot_win3.png&quot; width=&quot;164&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.megalith.co.uk/8086tiny/images/screenshot_123.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.megalith.co.uk/8086tiny/images/screenshot_123.png&quot; width=&quot;164&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;MS-DOS 6.22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Windows 3.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Lotus 1-2-3 R2.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
        	&lt;/div&gt;
      	&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;div class=&quot;section_box2&quot;&gt;
	        &lt;p class=&quot;post_title&quot;&gt;Applications&lt;/p&gt;
        	&lt;div class=&quot;text_area&quot;&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;Some possible applications:&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Run legacy PC software and games on modern hardware&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Teach computer architecture and Intel assembly language in a safe, sandboxed environment&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Deploy on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.raspberrypi.org&quot;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt; to make the world's cheapest ($25) complete IBM-compatible PC&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Extend the code base to develop a lean, modern-processor VM&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ul&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;If you develop an application that makes use of 8086tiny, and would like a link to it here, please get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;
        	&lt;/div&gt;
      	&lt;/div&gt;
        
	

        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
8086tiny: The world's smallest PC emulator
</title>
</item>
<item>
<author>
douglas.macmillan@wsj.com Biography
</author>
<link>
http://online.wsj.com/news/articles/SB10001424052702304632204579337043662898228
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
      

 &lt;p&gt;In the crowded field of online payments, venture capitalists are betting Stripe Inc. is a standout worth more than a billion dollars. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The payments startup has raised about $80 million in new funding this week from venture-capital investors including Khosla Ventures, Sequoia Capital, and Founders Fund, said brothers John and Patrick Collison, the company's co-founders, in an interview. Stripe, at just over four years old, is now...
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Payments Startup Stripe (YC S10) Joins the Billion Dollar Club
</title>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
