<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version='2.0'>
<channel>
<generator>
clj-rss
</generator>
<link>
https://news.ycombinator.com
</link>
<title>
myread
</title>
<description>
myread
</description>
<item>
<link>
http://www.gigamonkeys.com/code-reading/
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;contents&quot;&gt;
          
          &lt;p class=&quot;dateline&quot;&gt;
          20 January 2014
          &lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;I have started code reading groups at the last two companies I&amp;#x2019;ve worked at, Etsy and Twitter, and some folks have asked for my advice about code reading and running code reading groups. Tl;dr: don&amp;#x2019;t start a code reading group. What you should start instead I&amp;#x2019;ll get to in a moment but first I need to explain how I arrived at my current opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;As a former English major and a sometimes writer, I had always been drawn to the idea that code is like literature and that we ought to learn to write code the way we learn to write English: by reading good examples. And I&amp;#x2019;m certainly not the only one to have taken this point of view&amp;#x2014;Donald Knuth, in addition to his work on &lt;em&gt;The Art of Computer Programming&lt;/em&gt; and TeX, has long been a proponent of what he calls Literate Programming and has published several of his large programs as books.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;On the other hand, long before I got to Etsy and started my first code reading group I had in hand several pieces of evidence that should have suggested to me that this was the wrong way to look at things.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;First, when I did my book of interviews with programmers, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codersatwork.com&quot;&gt;Coders at Work&lt;/a&gt;, I asked pretty much everyone about code reading. And while most of them said it was important and that programmers should do it more, when I asked them about what code they had read recently, very few of them had any great answers. Some of them had done some serious code reading as young hackers but almost no one seemed to have a regular habit of reading code. Knuth, the great synthesizer of computer science, does seem to read a lot of code and Brad Fitzpatrick was able to talk about several pieces of open source code that he had read just for the heck of it. But they were the exceptions.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;If that wasn&amp;#x2019;t enough, after I finished &lt;em&gt;Coders&lt;/em&gt; I had a chance to &lt;a href=&quot;http://codequarterly.com/2011/hal-abelson/&quot;&gt;interview Hal Abelson&lt;/a&gt;, the famous MIT professor and co-author of the &lt;em&gt;Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs&lt;/em&gt;. The first time I talked to him I asked my usual question about reading code and he gave the standard answer&amp;#x2014;that it was important and we should do it more. But he too failed to name any code he had read recently other than code he was obliged to: reviewing co-workers&amp;#x2019; code at Google where he was on sabbatical and grading student code at MIT. Later I asked him about this disconnect:&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Seibel:&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;#x2019;m still curious about this split between what people say and what they actually do. Everyone says, &amp;#x201C;People should read code&amp;#x201D; but few people seem to actually do it. I&amp;#x2019;d be surprised if I interviewed a novelist and asked them what the last novel they had read was, and they said, &amp;#x201C;Oh, I haven&amp;#x2019;t really read a novel since I was in grad school.&amp;#x201D; Writers actually read other writers but it doesn&amp;#x2019;t seem that programmers really do, even though we say we should.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abelson:&lt;/em&gt; Yeah. You&amp;#x2019;re right. But remember, a lot of times you crud up a program to make it finally work and do all of the things that you need it to do, so there&amp;#x2019;s a lot of extraneous stuff around there that isn&amp;#x2019;t the core idea.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Seibel:&lt;/em&gt; So basically you&amp;#x2019;re saying that in the end, most code isn&amp;#x2019;t worth reading?&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abelson:&lt;/em&gt; Or it&amp;#x2019;s built from an initial plan or some kind of pseudocode. A lot of the code in books, they have some very cleaned-up version that doesn&amp;#x2019;t do all the stuff it needs to make it work.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Seibel:&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;#x2019;m thinking of the preface to SICP, where it says, &amp;#x201C;programs must be written for people to read and only incidentally for machines to execute.&amp;#x201D; But it seems the reality you just described is that in fact, most programs are written for machines to execute and only incidentally, if at all, for people to read.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abelson:&lt;/em&gt; Well, I think they start out for people to read, because there&amp;#x2019;s some idea there. You explain stuff. That&amp;#x2019;s a little bit of what we have in the book. There are some fairly significant programs in the book, like the compiler. And that&amp;#x2019;s partly because we think the easiest way to explain what it&amp;#x2019;s doing is to express that in code.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;Yet somehow even this explicit acknowledgement that most real code isn&amp;#x2019;t actually in a form that can be simply read wasn&amp;#x2019;t enough to lead me to abandon the literature seminar model when I got to Etsy. For our first meeting I picked Jeremy Ashkenas&amp;#x2019;s backbone.js because many of the Etsy developers would be familiar with Javascript and because I know Jeremy is particularly interested in writing readable code. I still envisioned something like a literature seminar but I figured that a lot of people wouldn&amp;#x2019;t actually have done the reading in advance (well, maybe not so different from a literature seminar) so I decided to start things off by presenting the code myself before the group discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;As I prepared my presentation, I found myself falling into my usual pattern when trying to really understand a piece of code&amp;#x2014;in order to grok it I have to essentially rewrite it. I&amp;#x2019;ll start by renaming a few things so they make more sense to me and then I&amp;#x2019;ll move things around to suit my ideas about how to organize code. Pretty soon I&amp;#x2019;ll have gotten deep into the abstractions (or lack thereof) of the code and will start making bigger changes to the structure of the code. Once I&amp;#x2019;ve completely rewritten the thing I usually understand it pretty well and can even go back to the original and understand it too. I have always felt kind of bad about this approach to code reading but it's the only thing that's ever worked for me.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;My presentation to the code reading group started with stock backbone.js and then walked through the changes I would make to it to make it, by my lights, more understandable. At one point I asked if people thought we should move on to the group discussion but nobody seemed very interested. Hopefully seeing my refactoring gave people some of the same insights into the underlying structure of the original that I had obtained by doing the refactoring.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;The second meeting of the Etsy code reading group featured Avi Bryant demonstrating how to use the code browsing capabilities of Smalltalk to navigate through some code. In that case, because few of the Etsy engineers had any experience with Smalltalk, we had no expectation that folks would read the code in advance. But the presentation was an awesome chance for folks to get exposed to the power of the Smalltalk development environment and for me to heckle Avi about Smalltalk vs Lisp differences.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          &lt;p&gt;When I got to Twitter I inexplicably still had the literature seminar model in mind even though neither of the two meetings of the Etsy reading group&amp;#x2014;which folks seemed to like pretty well&amp;#x2014;followed that model at all. When I sent out the email inviting Twitter engineers to join a code reading group the response was pretty enthusiastic. The first meeting was, yet again, a presentation of some code, in this case the internals of the Scala implementation of Future that is used throughout Twitter&amp;#x2019;s many services, presented by Marius Eriksen, who wrote most of it.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;It was sometime after that presentation that I finally realized the obvious: code is not literature. We don&amp;#x2019;t read code, we &lt;em&gt;decode&lt;/em&gt; it. We examine it. A piece of code is not literature; it is a specimen. Knuth said something that should have pointed me down this track when I asked him about his own code reading:&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Knuth:&lt;/em&gt; But it&amp;#x2019;s really worth it for what it builds in your brain. So how do I do it? There was a machine called the Bunker Ramo 300 and somebody told me that the Fortran compiler for this machine was really amazingly fast, but nobody had any idea why it worked. I got a copy of the source-code listing for it. I didn&amp;#x2019;t have a manual for the machine, so I wasn&amp;#x2019;t even sure what the machine language was.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;But I took it as an interesting challenge. I could figure out &lt;code&gt;BEGIN&lt;/code&gt; and then I would start to decode. The operation codes had some two-letter mnemonics and so I could start to figure out &amp;#x201C;This probably was a load instruction, this probably was a branch.&amp;#x201D; And I knew it was a Fortran compiler, so at some point it looked at column seven of a card, and that was where it would tell if it was a comment or not.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;After three hours I had figured out a little bit about the machine. Then I found these big, branching tables. So it was a puzzle and I kept just making little charts like I&amp;#x2019;m working at a security agency trying to decode a secret code. But I knew it worked and I knew it was a Fortran compiler&amp;#x2014;it wasn&amp;#x2019;t encrypted in the sense that it was intentionally obscure; it was only in code because I hadn&amp;#x2019;t gotten the manual for the machine.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;Eventually I was able to figure out why this compiler was so fast. Unfortunately it wasn&amp;#x2019;t because the algorithms were brilliant; it was just because they had used unstructured programming and hand optimized the code to the hilt.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;It was just basically the way you solve some kind of an unknown puzzle&amp;#x2014;make tables and charts and get a little more information here and make a hypothesis. In general when I&amp;#x2019;m reading a technical paper, it&amp;#x2019;s the same challenge. I&amp;#x2019;m trying to get into the author&amp;#x2019;s mind, trying to figure out what the concept is. The more you learn to read other people&amp;#x2019;s stuff, the more able you are to invent your own in the future, it seems to me.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;He&amp;#x2019;s not describing reading literature; he&amp;#x2019;s describing a scientific investigation. So now I have a new mode for how people should get together to gain insights from code which I explained to the Twitter code reading group like this:&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;Preparing for the talk I&amp;#x2019;m going to give to the Girls who Code cohort, I started thinking about what to tell them about code reading and code they should read. And once again it struck me that for all the lip service we pay to the idea of reading code, most programmers really don&amp;#x2019;t read that much code, at least not just for the sake of reading it. As a simple proof: name me one piece of code that you&amp;#x2019;ve read and that you can be reasonably sure that most other good programmers will have read or will at least have heard of. Not many, right? Probably none.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;But then it hit me. Code is not literature and we are not readers. Rather, interesting pieces of code are specimens and we are naturalists. So instead of trying to pick out a piece of code and reading it and then discussing it like a bunch of Comp Lit. grad students, I think a better model is for one of us to play the role of a 19th century naturalist returning from a trip to some exotic island to present to the local scientific society a discussion of the crazy beetles they found: &amp;#x201C;Look at the antenna on this monster! They look incredibly ungainly but the male of the species can use these to kill small frogs in whose carcass the females lay their eggs.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;The point of such a presentation is to take a piece of code that the presenter has understood deeply and for them to help the audience understand the core ideas by pointing them out amidst the layers of evolutionary detritus (a.k.a. kluges) that are also part of almost all code. One reasonable approach might be to show the real code and then to show a stripped down reimplementation of just the key bits, kind of like a biologist staining a specimen to make various features easier to discern.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;The ideal presentation should be aimed at an audience of gentleman and lady programmers&amp;#x2014;smart, and generally capable but without, necessarily, any specific knowledge of the domain from which the code comes. Presentations should provide enough context for the audience to to understand what the code is and should explain any details of the implementation language that may be obscure to the average programmer.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;Since I had my epihany we&amp;#x2019;ve had several meetings of the code reading group, now known as the Royal Society of Twitter for Improving Coding Knowledge, along the new lines. We&amp;#x2019;re still learning about the best ways to present code but the model feels very right. Also, I no longer feel bad about my dissection-based approach to reading code.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;The biggest lesson so far is that code is very dense. A half hour presentation is just enough time to present maybe a dozen meaty lines of code and one main idea. It is also almost certainly the case that the presenters, who have to actually really dig down into a piece of code, get more out of it than anybody. But it does seem that a good presentation can at least expose people to the main ideas and maybe give them a head start if they do decide to read the code themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Code is not Literature
</title>
</item>
<item>
<author>
Jim Harper
</author>
<link>
http://www.cato.org/blog/youre-eight-times-more-likely-be-killed-police-officer-terrorist
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-body&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It got a lot of attention this morning when I &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Jim_Harper/status/233951581001875457&quot;&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;#x201C;You&amp;#x2019;re Eight Times More Likely to be Killed by a Police Officer than a Terrorist.&amp;#x201D; It&amp;#x2019;s been quickly retweeted dozens of times, indicating that the idea is interesting to many people. So let&amp;#x2019;s discuss it in more than 140 characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case it needs saying: Police officers are unlike terrorists in almost all respects. Crucially, the goal of the former, in their vastest majority, is to have a stable, peaceful, safe, law-abiding society, which is a goal we all share. The goal of the latter is &amp;#x2026; well, it&amp;#x2019;s complicated. I&amp;#x2019;ve cited my favorite expert on that, Audrey Kurth Cronin, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cato-at-liberty.org/the-third-strategic-actor/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cato-at-liberty.org/terrorism-and-security-systems/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cato-at-liberty.org/reactions-to-al-qaeda-terrorism-have-opened-a-flank/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Needless to say, the goal of terrorists is not that peaceful, safe, stable society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I picked up the statistic from a blog post called: &amp;#x201C;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtonsblog.com/2011/06/fear-of-terror-makes-people-stupid.html&quot;&gt;Fear of Terror Makes People Stupid&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;#x201D; which in turn cites the National Safety Council for this and lots of other numbers reflecting likelihoods of dying from various causes. So dispute the number(s) with them, if you care to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I take it as a given that your mileage may vary. If you dwell in the suburbs or a rural area, and especially if you&amp;#x2019;re wealthy, white, and well-spoken, your likelihood of death from these two sources probably converges somewhat (at very close to zero).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point of the quote is to focus people on sources of mortality society-wide, because this focus can guide public policy efforts at reducing death. (Thus, the number is not a product of the base rate fallacy.) In my opinion, too many people are still transfixed by terrorism despite the collapse of Al Qaeda over the last decade and the quite manageable&amp;#x2014;indeed, the quite well-managed&amp;#x2014;danger that terrorism presents our society today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to indulge your fears and prioritize terrorism, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cato-at-liberty.org/terrorism-hysteria-watch/&quot;&gt;you&amp;#x2019;ll have plenty of help&lt;/a&gt;, and neither this blog post nor any other appeal to reason or statistics is likely to convince you. Among the John Mueller articles I would recommend, though, is &amp;#x201C;&lt;a href=&quot;http://polisci.osu.edu/faculty/jmueller/ABAFIN.PDF&quot;&gt;Witches, Communists, and Terrorists: Evaluating the Risks and Tallying the Costs&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#x201D; (with Mark Stewart).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If one wants to be clinical about what things reduce death to Americans, one should ask why police officers are such a significant source of danger. I have some ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cato&amp;#x2019;s work on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cato.org/drug-war&quot;&gt;War on Drugs&lt;/a&gt; shows how it produces danger to the public and law enforcement both, not to mention loss of privacy and civil liberties, disrespect for law enforcement, disregard of the rule of law, and so on. Is the sum total of mortality and morbidity reduced or increased by the War on Drugs? I don&amp;#x2019;t know to say. But the War on Drugs certainly increases the danger to innocent people (including law enforcement personnel), where drug legalization would allow harm to naturally concentrate on the people who choose unwisely to use drugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cato.org/publications/white-paper/overkill-rise-paramilitary-police-raids-america&quot;&gt;militarization of law enforcement&lt;/a&gt; probably contributes to the danger. Cato&amp;#x2019;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cato.org/raidmap/&quot;&gt;Botched Paramilitary Police Raids map&lt;/a&gt; illustrates the problem of over-aggressive policing. Cato alum &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/radley-balko/&quot;&gt;Radley Balko&lt;/a&gt; now documents these issues at the &lt;em&gt;Huffington Post&lt;/em&gt;. Try out his &amp;#x201C;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theagitator.com/2012/01/16/take-the-quiz/&quot;&gt;Cop or Soldier?&amp;#x201D; quiz&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some bad apples in the police officer barrel. Given the power that law enforcement personnel have&amp;#x2014;up to and including the power to kill&amp;#x2014;I&amp;#x2019;m not satisfied that standards of professionalism are up to snuff. You can follow the Cato Institute&amp;#x2019;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.policemisconduct.net/&quot;&gt;National Police Misconduct Reporting Project&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter at &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/NPMRP&quot;&gt;@NPMRP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the provocative statistic cited above got your attention, that&amp;#x2019;s good. If it adds a little more to your efforts at producing a safe, stable, peaceful, and free society, all the better.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
You’re Eight Times More Likely to be Killed by a Police Officer than a Terrorist
</title>
</item>
<item>
<link>
http://www.mattcutts.com/blog/guest-blogging/
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Okay, I&amp;#x2019;m calling it: if you&amp;#x2019;re using guest blogging as a way to gain links in 2014, you should probably stop. Why? Because over time it&amp;#x2019;s become a more and more spammy practice, and if you&amp;#x2019;re doing a lot of guest blogging then you&amp;#x2019;re hanging out with really bad company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the day, guest blogging used to be a respectable thing, much like getting a coveted, respected author to write the introduction of your book. It&amp;#x2019;s not that way any more. Here&amp;#x2019;s an example unsolicited, spam email that I recently received:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
My name is XXXXXXX XXXXXXXX and I work as a content marketer for a high end digital marketing agency in [a city halfway around the world]. I have been promoting high quality content in select niches for our clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are always on the lookout for professional, high class sites to further promote our clients and when I came across your blog I was very impressed with the fan following that you have established.I [sic] would love to speak to you regarding the possibility of posting some guest articles on your blog. Should you be open to the idea, &lt;strong&gt;we can consider making suitable contribution&lt;/strong&gt;, befitting to high standard of services that your blog offers to larger audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my part, I assure you a high quality article that is-&lt;br&gt;
- 100% original&lt;br&gt;
- Well written&lt;br&gt;
- Relevant to your audience and&lt;br&gt;
- Exclusive to you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can also explore including internal links to related articles across your site to help keep your readers engaged with other content on your blog.&lt;br&gt;
All I ask in return is a &lt;strong&gt;dofollow link or two in the article body&lt;/strong&gt; that will be relevant to your audience and the article. We understand that you will want to approve the article, and I can assure you that we work with a team of highly talented writers, so we can guarantee that the article would be insightful and professionally written. We aim to write content that will benefit your loyal readers. We are also happy to write on any topic, you suggest for us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you ignore the bad spacing and read the parts that I bolded, someone sent me a spam email offering money to get links that pass PageRank. That&amp;#x2019;s a clear violation of Google&amp;#x2019;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/35769?hl=en&quot;&gt;quality guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. Moreover, we&amp;#x2019;ve been seeing more and more reports of &amp;#x201C;guest blogging&amp;#x201D; that are really &amp;#x201C;paying for PageRank&amp;#x201D; or worse, &amp;#x201C;we&amp;#x2019;ll insert some spammy links on your blog without you realizing it.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, this is why we can&amp;#x2019;t have nice things in the SEO space: a trend starts out as authentic. Then more and more people pile on until only the barest trace of legitimate behavior remains. We&amp;#x2019;ve reached the point in the downward spiral where people are hawking &amp;#x201C;guest post outsourcing&amp;#x201D; and writing articles about &amp;#x201C;how to automate guest blogging.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So stick a fork in it: guest blogging is done; it&amp;#x2019;s just gotten too spammy. In general I wouldn&amp;#x2019;t recommend accepting a guest blog post unless you are willing to vouch for someone personally or know them well. Likewise, I wouldn&amp;#x2019;t recommend relying on guest posting, guest blogging sites, or guest blogging SEO as a linkbuilding strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For historical reference, I&amp;#x2019;ll list a few videos and links to trace the decline of guest articles. Even back in 2012, I tried to draw a distinction between high-quality guest posts vs. spammier guest blogs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/IMxC3wQZOyc?rel=0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, a lot of people didn&amp;#x2019;t seem to hear me say to steer away from low-quality guest blog posting, so I did a follow-up video to warn folks away from spammy guest articles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/qpbCKWu0I0A?rel=0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In mid-2013, &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/+JohnMueller&quot;&gt;John Mueller&lt;/a&gt; gave spot on advice about &lt;a href=&quot;http://searchengineland.com/google-guest-blogging-for-links-you-better-nofollow-those-links-166218&quot;&gt;nofollowing links in guest blog posts&lt;/a&gt;. I think by mid-2013, a ton of people saw the clear trend towards guest blogging being overused by a bunch of low-quality, spammy sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then a few months ago, I took a question about how to be a guest blogger without it looking like paying for links (even the question is a clue that guest blog posting has been getting spammier and spammier). I tried to find a sliver of daylight to talk about high-quality guest blog posts, but if you read the transcript you&amp;#x2019;ll notice that I ended up spending most of the time talking about low-quality/spam guest posting and guest articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/OGieiNe6RL4?rel=0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then in this video that we posted last month, even the question itself predicted that Google would take stronger action and asked about &amp;#x201C;guest blogging as spam&amp;#x201D;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/qozPhALuQQw?rel=0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there you have it: the decay of a once-authentic way to reach people. Given how spammy it&amp;#x2019;s become, I&amp;#x2019;d expect Google&amp;#x2019;s webspam team to take a pretty dim view of guest blogging going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Added&lt;/strong&gt;: It seems like most people are getting the spirit of what I was trying to say, but I&amp;#x2019;ll add a bit more context. I&amp;#x2019;m not trying to throw the baby out with the bath water. There are still many good reasons to do some guest blogging (exposure, branding, increased reach, community, etc.). Those reasons existed way before Google and they&amp;#x2019;ll continue into the future. And there are absolutely some fantastic, high-quality guest bloggers out there. I changed the title of this post to make it more clear that I&amp;#x2019;m talking about guest blogging for search engine optimization (SEO) purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x2019;m also not talking about multi-author blogs. High-quality multi-author blogs like Boing Boing have been around since the beginning of the web, and they can be compelling, wonderful, and useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just want to highlight that a bunch of low-quality or spam sites have latched on to &amp;#x201C;guest blogging&amp;#x201D; as their link-building strategy, and we see a lot more spammy attempts to do guest blogging. Because of that, I&amp;#x2019;d recommend skepticism (or at least caution) when someone reaches out and offers you a guest blog article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
The decay and fall of guest blogging for SEO
</title>
</item>
<item>
<link>
http://www.vintagemacworld.com/iifx.html
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&amp;#13;         &lt;p&gt;In its day, the IIfx was Apple's flagship computer and a&amp;#13;         well specified machine would have left little change from&amp;#13;         &amp;#xA3;10,000. My new purchase had 20MB RAM, an A4 portrait&amp;#13;         display card, a 256 colour Toby video card and a very noisy&amp;#13;         Fujitsu (non-Apple ROM) hard disk drive running System&amp;#13;         software 7.5.5. All of the blanking plates for the NuBus&amp;#13;         slots had been removed and it is likely that any useful&amp;#13;         cards had been removed as the Mac descended the scrap chain;&amp;#13;         the Open Transport preferences contained a reference to an&amp;#13;         ethernet adapter and the control panel for a Radius display&amp;#13;         card was installed.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;#13;         &amp;#13;         &lt;p&gt;The applications software installed on the system didn't&amp;#13;         look very interesting. All of the files I had deleted were&amp;#13;         MacWrite documents and it appeared that the IIfx had been&amp;#13;         used as a glorified word processor. However Retrospect&amp;#13;         Remote was installed for backups so somebody had been using&amp;#13;         the Mac for serious work previously. The last backup was&amp;#13;         performed on 02-02-1997 but, according to the last modified&amp;#13;         file dates, the system remained in use until March 1999.&amp;#13;         Some power user utilities from CE and More were also&amp;#13;         installed.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;#13;      &lt;/td&gt;&amp;#13;      &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&amp;#13;         &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vintagemacworld.com/IIfx/underside.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.vintagemacworld.com/IIfx/underside_th.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;#13;      &lt;/td&gt;&amp;#13;   &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Douglas Adams's Mac IIfx
</title>
</item>
<item>
<author>
Julie Strietelmeier
</author>
<link>
http://the-gadgeteer.com/2014/01/20/amc-movie-theater-calls-fbi-to-arrest-a-google-glass-user
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://the-gadgeteer.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/google-glass.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-150900&quot; alt=&quot;google-glass&quot; src=&quot;http://the-gadgeteer.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/google-glass-600x394.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A long time Gadgeteer reader contacted me today through Google Hangouts to tell me that he had a story that he thought I&amp;#x2019;d be interested in reading. He then forwarded me a long email with a story from a very good friend of his. It was such a surprising story that I asked if I could have permission to post it here on The Gadgeteer. I ended up communicating with the author of the story and have posted it here for everyone to read&amp;#x2026;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have been using Google Glass for about 2 months now, and about 2 weeks ago I got prescription lenses for the glasses.&amp;#xA0;So in the past two weeks I was wearing Google Glass all the time. There were no stories to write about, until yesterday (1/18/2014).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I went to AMC (Easton Mall, Columbus, OH) to watch a movie with my wife (non- Google Glass user). It is the theater we go to every week, so it has probably been the third time I&amp;#x2019;ve been there wearing Google Glass, and the AMC employees (guy tearing tickets at the entrance, girl at the concession stand) have asked me about Glass in the past and I have told them how awesome Glass is with every occasion.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Because I don&amp;#x2019;t want Glass to distract me during the movie, I turn them off (but since my prescription lenses are on the frame, I still wear them). About an hour into the movie (Jack Ryan: Shadow Recruit), a guy comes near my seat, shoves a badge that had some sort of a shield on it, yanks the Google Glass off my face and says &amp;#x201C;follow me outside immediately&amp;#x201D;. It was quite embarrassing and outside of the theater there were about 5-10 cops and mall cops. Since I didn&amp;#x2019;t catch his name in the dark of the theater, I asked to see his badge again and I asked what was the problem and I asked for my Glass back. The response was &amp;#x201C;you see all these cops you know we are legit, we are with the &amp;#x2018;federal service&amp;#x2019; and you have been caught illegally taping the movie&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I was surprised by this and as I was obviously just having a nice Saturday evening night out with my wife and not taping anything whether legally or illegally, I tried to explain that this is a misunderstanding. I tried to explain that he&amp;#x2019;s holding rather expensive hardware that costed me $1500 for Google Glass and over $600&amp;#xA0;for the prescription glasses. The response was that I was searched and more stuff was taken away from me (specifically my personal phone, my work phone &amp;#x2013; both of which were turned off, and my wallet). After an embarrassing 20-30 minutes outside the movie theater, me and my wife were conducted into two separate rooms in the &amp;#x201C;management&amp;#x201D; office of Easton Mall, where the guy with the badge introduced himself again and showed me a different ID. His partner introduced herself too and&amp;#xA0;showed me a similar looking badge. I was by that time, too flustered to remember their names (as a matter of fact, now, over 30 hours later I am still shaking when recounting the facts).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What followed was over an hour of the &amp;#x201C;feds&amp;#x201D; telling me I am not under arrest, and that this is a &amp;#x201C;voluntary interview&amp;#x201D;, but if I choose not to cooperate bad things may happen to me (is it legal for authorities to threaten people like that?). I kept telling them that Glass has a USB port and not only did I allow them, I actually insist they connect to it and see that there was nothing but personal photos with my wife and my dog on it. I also insisted they look at my phone too and clear things&amp;#xA0;out, but they wanted to talk first. They wanted to know who I am, where I live, where I work, how much I&amp;#x2019;m making, how many computers I have at home, why am I recording the movie, who am I going to give the recording to, why don&amp;#x2019;t I just give up the guy up the chain, &amp;#x2019;cause they are not interested in me. Over and over and over again.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I kept telling them that I wasn&amp;#x2019;t recording anything &amp;#x2013; my Glass was off, they insisted they saw it on. I told them there would be a light coming out the little screen if Glass was on, and I could show them that, but they insisted that I cannot touch my Glass for the fear &amp;#x201C;I will erase the evidence against me that was on Glass&amp;#x201D;. I didn&amp;#x2019;t have the intuition to tell them that Glass gets really warm if it records for more than a few minutes and my glasses were not warm. They wanted&amp;#xA0;to know where I got Glass and how did I came by having it. I told them I applied about 1000 times to get in the explorer program, and eventually I was selected, and I got the Glass from Google. I offered to show them receipt and Google Glass website if they would allow me to access any computer with internet. Of course, that was not an option. Then they wanted to know what does Google ask of me in exchange for Glass, how much is Google paying me, who is my boss and why am I recording the movie.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Eventually, after a long time somebody came with a laptop and an USB cable at which point he told me it was my last chance to come clean. I repeated for the hundredth time there is nothing to come clean about and this is a big misunderstanding so the FBI guy finally connected my Glass to the computer, downloaded all my personal photos and started going though them one by one (although they are dated and it was obvious there was nothing on my Glass that was from the time period&amp;#xA0;they accused me of recording). Then they went through my phone, and 5 minutes later they concluded I had done nothing wrong.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I asked why didn&amp;#x2019;t they just take those five minutes at the beginning of the interrogation and they just left the room. A guy who claimed his name is Bob Hope (he gave me his business card) came in the room, and said he was with the Movie Association and they have problems with piracy at that specific theater and that specific movie. He gave me two free movie passes &amp;#x201C;so I can see the movie again&amp;#x201D;. I asked if they thought my Google Glass was such a big piracy machine, why didn&amp;#x2019;t&amp;#xA0;they ask me not to wear them in the theater? I would have probably sat five or six rows closer to the screen (as I didn&amp;#x2019;t have any other pair of prescription glasses with me) and none of this would have happened. All he said was AMC called him, and he called the FBI and &amp;#x201C;here are two more passes for my troubles&amp;#x201D;. I would have been fine with &amp;#x201C;I&amp;#x2019;m sorry this happened, please accept our apologies&amp;#x201D;. Four free passes just infuriated me.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Considering it was 11:27pm when this happened, and the movie started at 7.45, I guess 3 and a half hours of my time and the scare my wife went through (who didn&amp;#x2019;t know what was going on as nobody bothered to tell her) is worth about 30 bucks in the eyes of the Movie Association and the federal militia (sorry, I cannot think of other derogatory words). I think I should sue them for this, but I don&amp;#x2019;t have the time or the energy to deal with &amp;#x201C;who is my boss &amp;#x2013; they don&amp;#x2019;t want me, they want the big guy&amp;#x201D; again, so I just spilled the beans on this forum, for other to learn from my experience.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I guess until people get more familiar with Google Glass and understand what they are, one should not wear them to the movies. I wish they would have said something before I went to the movies, but it may be my mistake for assuming that if I went and watched movies two times wearing Glass with no incident the third time there won&amp;#x2019;t be any incident either. As for the federal agents and their level of comprehension&amp;#x2026; I guess if they deal with petty criminals every day, everybody starts looking like a petty criminal. Again, I wish they would have listened when I told them how to verify I did nothing illegal, or at least apologize afterwards, but hey&amp;#x2026; this is the free country everybody praises. Somewhere else might be even worse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Crazy huh? His story read like something out of the Jack Ryan movie that he and his wife had gone to see. Are there any other Google Glass users out there that have been treated badly just for your wearable tech? If not, are you reconsidering wearing a pair to the next movie you attend?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
AMC movie theater calls FBI to arrest a Google Glass user
</title>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
