<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version='2.0'>
<channel>
<generator>
clj-rss
</generator>
<link>
https://news.ycombinator.com
</link>
<title>
myread
</title>
<description>
myread
</description>
<item>
<link>
http://www.pbrt.org/
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;td width=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;style5&quot;&gt;From movies to video games, computer-rendered images are pervasive today. Physically Based 
              Rendering introduces the concepts and theory of photorealistic rendering hand in hand with the 
              source code for a sophisticated renderer. By coupling the discussion of rendering algorithms with 
              their implementations, Matt Pharr and Greg Humphreys are able to reveal many of the details and 
              subtleties of these algorithms. But this book goes further; it also describes the design strategies 
              involved with building real systems&amp;#x2014;there is much more to writing a good renderer than stringing 
              together a set of fast algorithms. For example, techniques for high-quality antialiasing must be 
              considered from the start, as they have implications throughout the system. The rendering system 
              described in this book is itself highly readable, written in a style called literate programming that 
              mixes text describing the system with the code that implements it. Literate programming gives a 
              gentle introduction to working with programs of this size. This lucid pairing of text and code offers 
              the most complete and in-depth book available for understanding, designing, and building 
              physically realistic rendering systems.
              
              &lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p class=&quot;style5&quot;&gt;For a preview, you can download both Chapter 7, &quot;Sampling and Reconstruction&quot;, from the first 
              edition of the book as well as Chapter 4, &quot;Primitives and Intersection Acceleration&quot; from the 
              forthcoming second edition. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
&quot;Physically Based Rendering&quot;, a book on computer-generated images, has won an Oscar for technical achievment, the first time it's ever been given to a book.
</title>
</item>
<item>
<link>
http://needwant.com/p/im-moving-san-francisco-st-louis/
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;post__body&quot;&gt;
	  	&lt;p&gt;I love San Francisco. I moved here from the UK about 4 years ago to start my last company, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DailyBooth&quot;&gt;DailyBooth&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#x2019;s a wonderful city filled with interesting people doing amazing things. &amp;#xA0;It&amp;#x2019;s the city I grew up lusting over and when I moved here I wasn&amp;#x2019;t disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#x2019;re doing a startup and planning on raising money there&amp;#x2019;s probably no better place in the world to do it. However&amp;#x2026;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;If you&amp;#x2019;re trying to bootstrap, being based in San Francisco is &lt;strong&gt;awful&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x2019;s no secret that rent in San Francisco is starting to get a little crazy. After living here for a while you start to lose context. Let me give you some.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The average price of a 1 bedroom apartment in San Francisco is now $2,800 a month.&lt;/strong&gt; This is for a pretty standard, unexciting, ~700 SQFT space. That&amp;#x2019;s $33,600 per year. The average yearly income in 2012 was $44,321. I&amp;#x2019;ve been here for about 4 years. 4 *&amp;#xA0;$33,600 = $134,400.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Enter St Louis.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average rental price for a 1 bedroom apartment in St Louis is $720. 3.8x cheaper than San Francisco. Moving to St Louis is going to almost&amp;#xA0;quadruple my company&amp;#x2019;s runway. You can&amp;#xA0;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trulia.com/property/3138286329-1601-Washington-Ave-Saint-Louis-MO-63103#photo-2&quot;&gt;buy&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/em&gt;a really nice 1 bedroom apartment in downtown St Louis for less than renting in San Francisco for 4 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cheap cities are startup friendly&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The leading cause of startup death is running out of money. Moving to a cheap city and doubling (or more!) your company&amp;#x2019;s runway will more than likely vastly increase your chances of eventual success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;There&amp;#x2019;s a tech scene here!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, it&amp;#x2019;s not quite on the same level as San Francisco but it&amp;#x2019;s something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;#x2019;s this thing called &lt;a href=&quot;http://archgrants.org&quot;&gt;Arch Grants&lt;/a&gt; which aims to attract entrepreneurs by giving them $50,000 in equity free funding. &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/marshal&quot;&gt;Marshall&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#x2018;s last startup won one of these before being acquired. Applications are currently open for the next 20 grants!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are over 75 startups in our building alone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Something to think about&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#x2019;re an internet company. We don&amp;#x2019;t need to be tied to a specific location. Hiring remote and having a distributed work force is far cheaper than hiring locally and making everyone come into an office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#x2019;re based in San Francisco (or any other big, expensive city) and thinking of bootstrapping a company there &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; other options. I invite you to seriously consider St Louis. You&amp;#x2019;re even welcome to come and work out of our ($275 per month) office for a few days and we&amp;#x2019;ll show you around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;You&amp;#x2019;re not giving up living in a cool city&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;St. Louis isn&amp;#x2019;t &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; ridiculously affordable, there&amp;#x2019;s also a lot to keep you entertained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;align-none&quot; id=&quot;post-239 media-239&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://needwant.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/IMG_4120-e1390325346878.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Need/Want HQ is located in the building on the far right&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;St. Louis is neighborhood-y.&lt;/strong&gt; We&amp;#x2019;ll be living and working downtown (pictured), but St. Louis boasts 78 other neighborhoods, each with their own flair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;align-none&quot; id=&quot;post-225 media-225&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;align-none&quot; id=&quot;post-225 media-225&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;align-none&quot; id=&quot;post-225 media-225&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://needwant.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/FoxTheater-e1390325410137.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;The Fabulous Fox Theatre.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Big money is going into the city. All the time&lt;/b&gt;. In only the past few years, billions of dollars have gone into renewing some of the City&amp;#x2019;s most recognizable institutions. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.peabodyoperahouse.com/about-us/construction&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Peabody Opera House&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://central.slpl.org/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Downtown Central Library&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slam.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;St. Louis Art Museum&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#xA0; &amp;#x2014;&amp;#xA0;up next, even the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cityarchriver.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Arch&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#xA0;itself &amp;#x2014;&amp;#xA0;have all gotten updates and restorations in the past couple of years alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;align-none&quot; id=&quot;post-219 media-219&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;align-none&quot; id=&quot;post-220 media-220&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;align-none&quot; id=&quot;post-231 media-231&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;align-none&quot; id=&quot;post-231 media-231&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://needwant.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Olio.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Olio&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;St. Louis repurposes things well&lt;/b&gt;. The exquisite restaurant and cocktail house&amp;#xA0;&lt;a href=&quot;http://oliostl.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Olio&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#xA0;came out of an old gas station. You can take in your new movie releases on a couch in the&amp;#xA0;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.builtstlouis.net/moolah01.html%5D&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Moolah Theater&lt;/a&gt;, an old Masonic Temple that also has a bowling alley in its basement . World-class climbing can be found at&amp;#xA0;&lt;a href=&quot;http://climbsoill.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Climb So iLL&lt;/a&gt;, which used to be a hospital power plant building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;align-none&quot; id=&quot;post-220 media-220&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://needwant.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Moolah-SoiLL-Split.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Moolah Theater / Climb So ILL&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;align-none&quot; id=&quot;post-220 media-220&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;align-none&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;align-none&quot; id=&quot;post-233 media-233&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://needwant.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/UCBC.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Urban Chestnut &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;align-none&quot; id=&quot;post-233 media-233&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;St. Louis has a great culinary scene.&lt;/strong&gt; After a flourishing of microbreweries like Urban Chestnut, when the city&amp;#x2019;s original beer entrepreneurs got bought out, food trucks caught on, and then coffee roasters started a scene (including one of &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/jack&quot;&gt;@jack&amp;#x2019;s&lt;/a&gt; favorite spots, Sump Coffee).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;align-none&quot; id=&quot;post-232 media-232&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://needwant.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Sump.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Sump Coffee&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;align-none&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;align-none&quot; id=&quot;post-221 media-221&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://needwant.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/CAM-e1390324939393.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;The Contemporary Art Museum&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most attractions are free.&lt;/strong&gt; From spring to fall, weekends are chock-full of free festivals. Plus, its top-ranked Zoo, Science Center, History Museum, and all of the art museums are free to the public. The attractions that aren&amp;#x2019;t free &amp;#x2014; like the world-class Missouri Botanical Garden, the seriously unbeatable City Museum, or even the surprisingly relevant World Chess Hall of Fame &amp;#x2014; are more than worth the cover charge. And you never have to wait in line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;align-none&quot; id=&quot;post-240 media-240&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://needwant.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/MoBot-e1390324625681.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Missouri Botanical Garden&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;align-none&quot; id=&quot;post-223 media-223&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://needwant.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/city-museum.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;City Museum, 4 blocks from our office&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#xA0;Special thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/marshal&quot;&gt;Marshall&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#x2018;s girlfriend, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/tarapham&quot;&gt;Tara Pham&lt;/a&gt; for the St. Louis tips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;align-none&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you found this post interesting you can follow me on twitter &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/jon&quot;&gt;@jon&lt;/a&gt; and Need/Want &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/needwantinc&quot;&gt;@NeedWantInc&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
	  &lt;/section&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Why I'm Moving My Business From San Francisco To St. Louis
</title>
</item>
<item>
<author>
Rachel Williams
</author>
<link>
http://yaledailynews.com/weekend/2014/01/24/we-just-cant-have-you-here/
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content&quot;&gt;
        
  		&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x201C;I&amp;#x2019;m Rachel,&amp;#x201D; I say to the man who is here to evaluate me, extending my hand, trying to put on my best sane face. Problem is, no one ever told me what that looks like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He eyes me for a moment, then takes my hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I run him through the story, trying to emphasize my efforts to be honest and to get help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I say, &amp;#x201C;So as soon as I cut, I texted my FroCo for support.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x201C;But you admit that you willfully harmed yourself?&amp;#x201D; he says, like he&amp;#x2019;s just won something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x201C;Well &amp;#x2026; yes.&amp;#x201D; Because obviously I admit it. I&amp;#x2019;m not a liar. If I were a liar, I would never have gotten myself into this mess. Fuck me for not being a liar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, when I say &amp;#x201C;yes&amp;#x201D; to the &amp;#x2018;I admit cutting myself&amp;#x2019; part, he nods his head and closes his eyes like someone has just given him a bonbon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tell him when I come back to Yale, I will get a therapist on campus and keep working with the one I have at home. I will stop cutting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x201C;Well the question may not be what will you do at Yale, but if you are returning to Yale. It may well be safer for you to go home. We&amp;#x2019;re not so concerned about your studies as we are your safety,&amp;#x201D; he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x201C;I&amp;#x2019;m sorry,&amp;#x201D; I say. &amp;#x201C;What makes you think I will be safer away from school, away from my support system?&amp;#x201D; School was my stimulation, my passion and my reason for getting up in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x201C;Well the truth is,&amp;#x201D; he says, &amp;#x201C;we don&amp;#x2019;t necessarily think you&amp;#x2019;ll be safer at home. But we just can&amp;#x2019;t have you here.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* * *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the night of Jan. 27, 2013, I slashed open my right thigh six times with a Swiss Army knife. I then spent four hours thinking about how good it would feel to jump off the fifth floor of Vanderbilt Hall. On Jan. 28, I put on a pretty dress and went to class. Before lunch, my cuts had stained it brown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That night I texted my Freshman Counselor to tell her what had happened, just as I had done all the other times I felt suicidal and had cut myself. When I went to her suite, I showed her the gashes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went to Yale Health Urgent Care, at around 11:00 p.m., where a doctor bandaged my leg. A psychiatrist appeared. I told her that I had experienced suicidal thoughts the night before, but that the cuts had not been a suicide attempt. I told them that I was no longer suicidal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At midnight, I was strapped to a stretcher under the ashen ceiling of an ambulance, on my way to Yale-New Haven Hospital. There I was taken to the locked ward of the ER &amp;#x2014; guarded by officers with guns &amp;#x2014; stripped of all my belongings, including my pants (they had a drawstring), and shunted into a cubicle containing nothing but a bed. I was here for my own good, they told me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For 24 hours I had nothing to do but listen to the rattling gasping sound coming from the person two beds down, and to a schizophrenic person declare, every hour or so, that he had soiled himself. I was asked to recite the presidents of the United States, in reverse order, as part of a psychiatric evaluation. For more than a day I was not permitted to make a phone call. For more than a day no one had any idea where I was &amp;#x2014; not even my parents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a bed opened up in the actual Yale-New Haven Psychiatric Hospital, I was transported, again in an ambulance, and introduced to the place I would spend the next week of my life. Upon arrival, I was taken into a small room with two female staff members, forced to take off my underwear, spread my legs, then hop up and down to make sure nothing was hidden &amp;#x201C;up there.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Freshman Counselor had brought me some extra clothes and a course packet for my travel writing class, so that I would have something to read. The course packet was confiscated. Why? Because I might cut myself with the plastic binding &amp;#x2014; you know &amp;#x2014; the kind you get from Tyco. I might commit suicide with that, they said. &amp;#x201C;You&amp;#x2019;re a cutter,&amp;#x201D; they told me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a week, I was not allowed to set foot outside. I was not allowed to stretch my hamstrings or calves or any other body part. I was not allowed to pace my confines. I was not allowed to drink caffeine. I was not permitted to take ibuprofen for my caffeine withdrawal headache. I did not get to take a shower until my third day. Phone usage was restricted and phone calls were closely monitored. I was threatened, by a nurse, with the possibility of having my wrists and ankles tied to my bed, and witnessed this threat be carried out on others. Whoever built the hospital had termed this ward, &amp;#x201C;Liberty Village.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was little &amp;#x201C;treatment&amp;#x201D; in the hospital. Mostly, we watched television, played Pictionary and Connect Four and sat. I was interviewed by various clinicians a few times a day; I saw my assigned psychiatrist only three times, for half an hour or so, over the course of seven days. This limited treatment was fairly standard for all patients, but it soon became clear that it would have little effect on my situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The milieu counselors, nurses and doctors in Yale-New Haven Psychiatric Hospital have absolutely no input when it comes to deciding who gets to stay at Yale and who is forced to leave. In talking to the nurses, doctors and fellow Yale students I encountered in the hospital, I understood that job to belong to Dr. Eric Millman and to chief of Yale Psychiatry, Dr. Lorraine Siggins &amp;#x2014; two people who work for the University, rather than the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have shared with you my memorable exchange with a senior psychiatrist at Yale Mental Health who came to evaluate me. It was this exchange that led me to keep an extensive and thorough journal during my time in the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Dr. Siggins is the one who makes a ruling: Does Johnny stay at Yale or does he go? And in my talks, a consensus emerged: Dr. Siggins does not always &amp;#x2014; and by some accounts, rarely &amp;#x2014; make contact with the student in question. (A Yale senior who was in the hospital with me was not granted a meeting with Dr. Siggins but was still forced to leave Yale.) Neither the staff members I spoke with nor a fellow Yalie who had prior experience in the hospital knew of any Yale student admitted to the hospital who had been allowed to stay at Yale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My interview left me terrified of the possibility of leaving school. I called my parents, and they promptly put themselves on Dr. Siggins&amp;#x2019; radar, meeting with her twice and securing me a personal interview. All I remember was that my mind was totally blank when I spoke to her, because I was so focused on making her believe that I was &amp;#x201C;okay.&amp;#x201D; This, of course, is totally futile when you&amp;#x2019;re sitting on a cot in a mental hospital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She called me three days later to tell me that I would have to go home. That meant that I was forced to formally withdraw from the college, with no guarantee of return. As soon as her decision came down, I was eligible for release into my parents&amp;#x2019; custody. Upon my release from the hospital (also not a function of my recovery &amp;#x2014; but as a result of my expulsion from the College I was even more depressed when I left than when I was admitted, my Yale ID was confiscated, as was my room key. I was given one evening to pack up my entire life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My college dean told me I was not even allowed to spend the night in my room in Vanderbilt Hall. I fell asleep on the futon in my suite&amp;#x2019;s common room at four a.m., breaking the rules, but exhausted and unable to continue putting my things in boxes, dismantling the reality of my college life. I had a chance to say goodbye to a few friends &amp;#x2014; most of whom I would not hear from during my time away. 18 hours after I walked out of the hospital doors, I was on a plane, headed back to North Carolina in a storm of tears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did what they said was necessary to be a candidate for readmission: therapy, more therapy, two college courses, more therapy. And I healed. Mostly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I filled out the paper application for readmission: the usual demographic crap, a three-page personal statement, a transcript of my summer classes, two letters of recommendation, a profile from a therapist and a check for $50. I flew to New Haven for my three interviews &amp;#x2014; with the dean of my residential college, Dean Pamela George (chair of readmission) and Dr. Siggins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a side note, I might mention that Dr. Siggins was 45 minutes late to my interview. Dean George called me an hour before the scheduled time to cancel, forcing me to interview the following day, two hours before my return flight took off. I answered every question with as much positivity as I could sell. I said: I do not cut, I do not think of killing myself. I am great. Two weeks later, I was readmitted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every morning of my year away from Yale, I woke to the sight of the &amp;#x201C;Yale&amp;#x201D; pennant on my bedroom wall &amp;#x2014; the one they send to accepted freshmen in the big, glorious &amp;#x201C;Welcome to Yale&amp;#x201D; packet. &amp;#x201C;You&amp;#x2019;re in!&amp;#x201D; it says. &amp;#x201C;You&amp;#x2019;re a treasured asset to our University!&amp;#x201D; it says. &amp;#x201C;Come to Bulldog Days and feel the love because we love you and we care about you and we don&amp;#x2019;t want you to go to any other school because you&amp;#x2019;re the shit!&amp;#x201D; it says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking back to that welcome packet, there is a conspicuous omission: *We love you and want you and will provide for you and protect you, as long as you don&amp;#x2019;t get sick.*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* * *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I return to a different Yale, though it is I who have changed. After a year spent focusing solely on my health and well-being, I find myself, though not perfectly balanced, resting closer to my ideal center. And, after a year of watching and analyzing every one of my inner ticks, I see external things that were invisible to me before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see that Yale is a fundamentally unhealthy place in one important way. The problem is, everyone is &amp;#x201C;okay.&amp;#x201D; I have known friends who have suffered the deaths of siblings, who have been victims of sexual assault or who have fought life-threatening illness, all while navigating their sexuality, while taking five-and-a-half credits, while chairing more organizations and running to more meetings than they can keep track of. I have known friends to do all of this and still profess, at every opportunity, to be &amp;#x201C;okay,&amp;#x201D; &amp;#x201C;fine,&amp;#x201D; &amp;#x201C;great.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To say something else, to be &amp;#x2014; in our own minds and in the minds of others &amp;#x2014; something else, is for some reason not acceptable at Yale. None of us are completely okay. But the pressure to conform to being perfectly functional and happy is a burden that we should neither want nor bear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where does it come from? For most students at Yale, I think the pressure is subconscious, upheld through day-to-day conversation: My classes are amazing. My extracurriculars are dope. My internship this summer is baller. Life is awesome. Are you awesome? No one wants to deviate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I think the source is not, in fact, the students. Those of us who have admitted, at some point or another, that we are legitimately not okay, have learned that there are real and devastating consequences of telling the truth. Because Yale does not want people who are not okay. Yale does not want people who are struggling, who are fighting. Yale, out of concern for its own image, wants them to leave. And Yale makes them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this, I refuse to be okay.&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
“We Just Can’t Have You Here”
</title>
</item>
<item>
<link>
http://bropages.org
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;install&quot; class=&quot;well&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;# install bro now&lt;br&gt;$ gem install bropages&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
	bro pages are a highly readable supplement to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Man_page&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;man pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
	bro pages show concise, common-case examples for Unix commands
	&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;h2&gt;example&lt;/h2&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
	 If you type...
	&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;pre&gt;$ bro curl&lt;/pre&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;...then you get&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;status&quot;&gt;3 entries for curl&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;span class=&quot;important&quot;&gt;curl http://bropages.org&lt;/span&gt;

        &lt;span class=&quot;thanks&quot;&gt;bro thanks&lt;/span&gt;      to upvote (2)
        &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;bro ...no&lt;/span&gt;       to downvote (0)

...............................................


&lt;span class=&quot;important&quot;&gt;curl -o myfile.html http://bropages.org&lt;/span&gt;

        &lt;span class=&quot;thanks&quot;&gt;bro thanks 2&lt;/span&gt;      to upvote (2)
        &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;bro ...no 2&lt;/span&gt;       to downvote (0)

...............................................


&lt;span class=&quot;important&quot;&gt;curl --header &quot;X-BeerIsInteresting: 1&quot; www.bropages.org&lt;/span&gt;

        &lt;span class=&quot;thanks&quot;&gt;bro thanks 3&lt;/span&gt;      to upvote (1)
        &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;bro ...no 3&lt;/span&gt;       to downvote (0)
&lt;/pre&gt;

	&lt;h2&gt;installing bro&lt;/h2&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		The bro &lt;abbr title=&quot;Command Line Interface&quot;&gt;CLI&lt;/abbr&gt; is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://rubygems.org&quot;&gt;Ruby Gem&lt;/a&gt; and can be installed as follows
	&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p class=&quot;well&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;gem install bropages&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		bro is meant to work out of the box for any machine running Ruby 1.8.3+
	&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;h2&gt;community&lt;/h2&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
	bro sources its entries from the community, &lt;a href=&quot;http://bropages.org&quot;&gt;bropages.org&lt;/a&gt; hosts all the entries&lt;br&gt;
	Entries can be voted up or down, and the best entries are what people see first when they use the bro command line interface
	&lt;br&gt;
	For example, here are the top entries on bropages.org:
	&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;table&quot;&gt;
		&lt;thead&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;th&gt;Command&lt;/th&gt;
				&lt;th&gt;Entry&lt;/th&gt;
				&lt;th&gt;Votes&lt;/th&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;/thead&gt;
		&lt;tbody&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;git log&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td class=&quot;msgbody&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;# The ultimate graph display for your git log
git log --graph --abbrev-commit --decorate --date=relative --format=format:'%C(bold blue)%h%C(reset) - %C(bold green)(%ar)%C(reset) %C(white)%s%C(reset) %C(dim white)- %an%C(reset)%C(bold yellow)%d%C(reset)' --all&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;vote&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;upvote&quot;&gt;4 &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-thumbs-up&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#xA0;&amp;#xA0;&lt;span class=&quot;downvote&quot;&gt;0 &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-thumbs-down&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;curl&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td class=&quot;msgbody&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;# get the contents of a web page
curl http://bropages.org&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;vote&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;upvote&quot;&gt;3 &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-thumbs-up&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#xA0;&amp;#xA0;&lt;span class=&quot;downvote&quot;&gt;0 &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-thumbs-down&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;curl&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td class=&quot;msgbody&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;# download a file and write it to another file called myfile.html
curl -o myfile.html http://bropages.org&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;vote&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;upvote&quot;&gt;2 &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-thumbs-up&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#xA0;&amp;#xA0;&lt;span class=&quot;downvote&quot;&gt;0 &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-thumbs-down&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;find&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td class=&quot;msgbody&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;# Searches through my user's &quot;home&quot; directory recursively for the file &quot;hashClass.java&quot;, throwing out error output along the way.  
# Passes the output to grep for case insensitive search.
find ~/ 2&amp;gt;/dev/null | grep -i &quot;hashclass.java&quot;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;vote&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;upvote&quot;&gt;2 &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-thumbs-up&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#xA0;&amp;#xA0;&lt;span class=&quot;downvote&quot;&gt;0 &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-thumbs-down&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;bro&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td class=&quot;msgbody&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;# lookup an entry for the command 'bro' with bro
bro bro&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;vote&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;upvote&quot;&gt;2 &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-thumbs-up&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#xA0;&amp;#xA0;&lt;span class=&quot;downvote&quot;&gt;0 &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-thumbs-down&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;/tbody&gt;
	&lt;/table&gt;
	&lt;br&gt;
	&lt;br&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://bropages.org/browse&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;btn btn-large btn-inverse&quot;&gt;Browse all&amp;#xA0;&amp;#xA0;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-share&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
&quot;bro&quot; pages. like &quot;man&quot; pages, but with examples only
</title>
</item>
<item>
<author>
PAUL KALANITHI
</author>
<link>
http://www.nytimes.com/2014/01/25/opinion/sunday/how-long-have-i-got-left.html?smid=tw-share&_r=0
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;article id=&quot;story&quot; class=&quot;story theme-main&quot;&gt;

    

    
    

                
    &lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;AS soon as the CT scan was done, I began reviewing the images. The diagnosis was immediate: Masses matting the lungs and deforming the spine. Cancer. In my neurosurgical training, I had reviewed hundreds of scans for fellow doctors to see if surgery offered any hope. I&amp;#x2019;d scribble in the chart &amp;#x201C;Widely metastatic disease &amp;#x2014; no role for surgery,&amp;#x201D; and move on. But this scan was different: It was my own.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;I have sat with countless patients and families to discuss grim prognoses: It&amp;#x2019;s one of the most important jobs physicians have. It&amp;#x2019;s easier when the patient is 94, in the last stages of dementia and has a severe brain bleed. For young people like me &amp;#x2014; I am 36 &amp;#x2014; given a diagnosis of cancer, there aren&amp;#x2019;t many words. My standard pieces include &amp;#x201C;it&amp;#x2019;s a marathon, not a sprint, so get your daily rest&amp;#x201D; and &amp;#x201C;illness can drive a family apart or bring it together &amp;#x2014; be aware of each other&amp;#x2019;s needs and find extra support.&amp;#x201D; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;I learned a few basic rules. Be honest about the prognosis but always leave some room for hope. Be vague but accurate: &amp;#x201C;days to a few weeks,&amp;#x201D; &amp;#x201C;weeks to a few months,&amp;#x201D; &amp;#x201C;months to a few years,&amp;#x201D; &amp;#x201C;a few years to a decade or more.&amp;#x201D; We never cite detailed statistics, and usually advise against Googling survival numbers, assuming the average patient doesn&amp;#x2019;t possess a nuanced understanding of statistics. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media photo embedded has-adjacency layout-large-vertical&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;http://static01.nyt.com/images/2014/01/25/opinion/25kalanithi/25kalanithi-blog427.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;media-viewer-candidate&quot;&gt;
            &lt;meta value=&quot;http://static01.nyt.com/images/2014/01/25/opinion/25kalanithi/25kalanithi-blog427.jpg&quot;&gt;
            &lt;meta value=&quot;434&quot;&gt;
            &lt;meta value=&quot;427&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;People react differently to hearing &amp;#x201C;Procedure X has a 70 percent chance of survival&amp;#x201D; and &amp;#x201C;Procedure Y has a 30 percent chance of death.&amp;#x201D; Phrased that way, people flock to Procedure X, even though the numbers are the same. When a close friend developed pancreatic cancer, I became the medical maven to a group of people who were sophisticated statisticians. I still dissuaded them from looking up the statistics, saying five-year survival curves are at least five years out of date. Somehow I felt that the numbers alone were too dry, or that a physician&amp;#x2019;s daily experience with illness was needed for context. Mostly, I felt that impulse: Keep a measure of hope. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;These survival curves, called Kaplan-Meier curves, are one way we measure progress in cancer treatment, plotting the number of patients surviving over time. For some diseases, the line looks like an airplane gently beginning its descent; for others, like a dive bomber. Physicians think a lot about these curves, their shape, and what they mean. In brain-cancer research, for example, while the numbers for average survival time haven&amp;#x2019;t changed much, there&amp;#x2019;s an increasingly long tail on the curve, indicating a few patients are living for years. The problem is that you can&amp;#x2019;t tell an individual patient where she is on the curve. It&amp;#x2019;s impossible, irresponsible even, to be more precise than you can be accurate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;One would think, then, that when my oncologist sat by my bedside to meet me, I would not immediately demand information on survival statistics. But now that I had traversed the line from doctor to patient, I had the same yearning for the numbers all patients ask for. I hoped she would see me as someone who both understood statistics and the medical reality of illness, that she would give me certainty, the straight dope. I could take it. She flatly refused: &amp;#x201C;No. Absolutely not.&amp;#x201D; She knew very well I could &amp;#x2014; and did &amp;#x2014; look up all the research on the topic. But lung cancer wasn&amp;#x2019;t my specialty, and she was a world expert. At each appointment, a wrestling match began, and she always avoided being pinned down to any sort of number. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;Now, instead of wondering why some patients persist in asking statistics questions, I began to wonder why physicians obfuscate when they have so much knowledge and experience. Initially when I saw my CT scan, I figured I had only a few months to live. The scan looked bad. I looked bad. I&amp;#x2019;d lost 30 pounds, developed excruciating back pain and felt more fatigued every day. My tests revealed severely low protein levels and low blood counts consistent with the body overwhelmed, failing in its basic drive to sustain itself. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;For a few months, I&amp;#x2019;d suspected I had cancer. I had seen a lot of young patients with cancer. So I wasn&amp;#x2019;t taken aback. In fact, there was a certain relief. The next steps were clear: Prepare to die. Cry. Tell my wife that she should remarry, and refinance the mortgage. Write overdue letters to dear friends. Yes, there were lots of things I had meant to do in life, but sometimes this happens: Nothing could be more obvious when your day&amp;#x2019;s work includes treating head trauma and brain cancer. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;But on my first visit with my oncologist, she mentioned my going back to work someday. Wasn&amp;#x2019;t I a ghost? No. But then how long did I have? Silence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;Of course, she could not stop my intense reading. Poring over studies, I kept trying to find the one that would tell me when my number would be up. The large general studies said that between 70 and 80 percent of lung cancer patients would die within two years. They did not allow for much hope. But then again, most of those patients were older and heavy smokers. Where was the study of nonsmoking 36-year-old neurosurgeons? Maybe my youth and health mattered? Or maybe my disease was found so late, had spread so far, and I was already so far gone that I was worse off than those 65-year-old smokers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;Many friends and family members provided anecdotes along the lines of my-friend&amp;#x2019;s-friend&amp;#x2019;s-mom&amp;#x2019;s-friend or my-uncle&amp;#x2019;s-barber&amp;#x2019;s-son&amp;#x2019;s-tennis-partner has this same kind of lung cancer and has been living for 10 years. Initially I wondered if all the stories referred to the same person, connected through the proverbial six degrees. I disregarded them as wishful thinking, baseless delusion. Eventually, though, enough of those stories seeped in through the cracks of my studied realism. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;And then my health began to improve, thanks to a pill that targets a specific genetic mutation tied to my cancer. I began to walk without a cane and to say things like, &amp;#x201C;Well, it&amp;#x2019;s pretty unlikely that I&amp;#x2019;ll be lucky enough to live for a decade, but it&amp;#x2019;s possible.&amp;#x201D; A tiny drop of hope.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;In a way, though, the certainty of death was easier than this uncertain life. Didn&amp;#x2019;t those in purgatory prefer to go to hell, and just be done with it? Was I supposed to be making funeral arrangements? Devoting myself to my wife, my parents, my brothers, my friends, my adorable niece? Writing the book I had always wanted to write? Or was I supposed to go back to negotiating my multiyear job offers? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;The path forward would seem obvious, if only I knew how many months or years I had left. Tell me three months, I&amp;#x2019;d just spend time with family. Tell me one year, I&amp;#x2019;d have a plan (write that book). Give me 10 years, I&amp;#x2019;d get back to treating diseases. The pedestrian truth that you live one day at a time didn&amp;#x2019;t help: What was I supposed to do with that day? My oncologist would say only: &amp;#x201C;I can&amp;#x2019;t tell you a time. You&amp;#x2019;ve got to find what matters most to you.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;I began to realize that coming face to face with my own mortality, in a sense, had changed both nothing and everything. Before my cancer was diagnosed, I knew that someday I would die, but I didn&amp;#x2019;t know when. After the diagnosis, I knew that someday I would die, but I didn&amp;#x2019;t know when. But now I knew it acutely. The problem wasn&amp;#x2019;t really a scientific one. The fact of death is unsettling. Yet there is no other way to live. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;The reason doctors don&amp;#x2019;t give patients specific prognoses is not merely because they cannot. Certainly, if a patient&amp;#x2019;s expectations are way out of the bounds of probability &amp;#x2014; someone expecting to live to 130, or someone thinking his benign skin spots are signs of impending death &amp;#x2014; doctors are entrusted to bring that person&amp;#x2019;s expectations into the realm of reasonable possibility. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;But the range of what is reasonably possible is just so wide. Based on today&amp;#x2019;s therapies, I might die within two years, or I might make it to 10. If you add in the uncertainty based on new therapies available in two or three years, that range may be completely different. Faced with mortality, scientific knowledge can provide only an ounce of certainty: Yes, you will die. But one wants a full pound of certainty, and that is not on offer. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;What patients seek is not scientific knowledge doctors hide, but existential authenticity each must find on her own. Getting too deep into statistics is like trying to quench a thirst with salty water. The angst of facing mortality has no remedy in probability. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;I remember the moment when my overwhelming uneasiness yielded. Seven words from Samuel Beckett, a writer I&amp;#x2019;ve not even read that well, learned long ago as an undergraduate, began to repeat in my head, and the seemingly impassable sea of uncertainty parted: &amp;#x201C;I can&amp;#x2019;t go on. I&amp;#x2019;ll go on.&amp;#x201D; I took a step forward, repeating the phrase over and over: &amp;#x201C;I can&amp;#x2019;t go on. I&amp;#x2019;ll go on.&amp;#x201D; And then, at some point, I was through. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot;&gt;I am now almost exactly eight months from my diagnosis. My strength has recovered substantially. In treatment, the cancer is retreating. I have gradually returned to work. I&amp;#x2019;m knocking the dust off scientific manuscripts. I&amp;#x2019;m writing more, seeing more, feeling more. Every morning at 5:30, as the alarm clock goes off, and my dead body awakes, my wife asleep next to me, I think again to myself: &amp;#x201C;I can&amp;#x2019;t go on.&amp;#x201D; And a minute later, I am in my scrubs, heading to the operating room, alive: &amp;#x201C;I&amp;#x2019;ll go on.&amp;#x201D; &lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;footer class=&quot;story-footer story-content&quot;&gt;
        
    &lt;/footer&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
How Long Have I Got Left?
</title>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
