<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version='2.0'>
<channel>
<generator>
clj-rss
</generator>
<link>
https://news.ycombinator.com
</link>
<title>
myread
</title>
<description>
myread
</description>
<item>
<link>
http://www.matasano.com/matasano-square-microcontroller-ctf/
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;primary-content&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Announcing The Matasano/Square CTF&lt;/h2&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;We've teamed up with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.squareup.com&quot;&gt;Square&lt;/a&gt; to run a joint Capture The Flag contest.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;h2&gt;What is it?&lt;/h2&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Your target is a small embedded device; a microcontroller running compiled C code.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;You get access to the device, disassembly of its code, and a low-level debugger and assembler. We &quot;run&quot; the devices, you interact with them via a vanilla web interface.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;At each level, you'll get a simple input that, owing to some C software bug, can be used to own the target. You'll use the debugger to reverse the target, find the input, and then deliver it to a &quot;production&quot; instance to beat the level.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;You'll face a series of revisions of the target, starting from &quot;comically broken&quot; and proceeding vendor-fix by vendor-fix through basic memory corruption, stack overflows, randomization, memory protection schemes, allocator vulnerabilities, and DRM-style software protection.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;All this happens on an architecture you've probably used, but likely never have written any code for. Have you ever reverse-engineered a program from its assembly code to understand what it's doing? That'll happen too.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;We're keeping a leaderboard, by completion time, CPU cycles, and input size. Part of the fun of a challenge like this is to see how others are doing in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;If you've done a lot of exploit development, you won't have much trouble. &lt;em&gt;But we hope the real fun is reserved for the people who haven't&lt;/em&gt;: you'll get to play with concepts that, in the real world, involve tedious toolchain installs and comprehensive knowledge of the memory layouts of gigantic browser library codebases. You won't need any of that here: we're looking forward to seeing people who have never written a line of assembly beating people who've been doing this for years.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;h2&gt;How do I start?&lt;/h2&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://microcorruption.com&quot;&gt;microcorruption.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      
      
    &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Announcing The Matasano/Square CTF
</title>
</item>
<item>
<author>
Also on The Switch, Amazon is a hornet's nest of malware
</author>
<link>
http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/the-switch/wp/2014/01/16/yale-students-made-a-better-version-of-its-course-catalog-then-yale-shut-it-down/
</link>
<description>
&lt;article id=&quot;post-14189&quot; class=&quot;post-14189 post type-post status-publish format-standard hentry category-uncategorized&quot; score=&quot;51.25&quot;&gt;
		&lt;header class=&quot;entry-header&quot;&gt;
			&lt;/header&gt;
		
		&lt;div id=&quot;post-content&quot; class=&quot;cf entry-content&quot; score=&quot;32.5&quot;&gt;
		&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_14196&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-14196&quot; alt=&quot;(CourseTable.com)&quot; src=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/the-switch/files/2014/01/coursetable.jpg&quot; width=&quot;711&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;The page students inside Yale saw when attempting to access a student creating online class planning service earlier this week. (CourseTable.com)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A pair of Yale students and brothers, Peter Xu and Harry Yu, built a site that let students plan out their schedules while comparing class evaluations and teacher ratings for the past three semesters. Thousands of Yale students used it, apparently finding it a better resource than similar sites run by the university. But this week, as the &quot;shopping period&quot; where students are able to try out classes and finalize their schedules began, Yale not only blocked the Web site from campus networks, labeling it &quot;malicious,&quot; but forced the brothers to take it down or face disciplinary action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We found that it was really hard to find and compare courses when we first arrived at Yale,&quot; said Yu,&quot;and given the amount of freedom that Yale gives students to take courses, we found it really frustrating.&quot; So they created their own personal tool to help them use average class and professor evaluations to make informed decisions about their course selections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The information they used was already available to students through internal systems. But there was no centralized database that allowed students to perform comparisons at a glance. So they started collecting information from internal resources and programmed an interface that would compile everything in one place. As it evolved, they thought that other students might be interested in their system as well. So they launched it as &quot;Yale Bluebook+&quot; -- a riff on an officially sanctioned course planning tool. And they were right: According to their data, 2,094 students have used the site, with 1,871 students creating worksheets last semester. That's a significant chunk of Yale's roughly 5,000-person undergraduate student body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As first reported by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://yaledailynews.com/blog/2014/01/14/yale-shuts-down-yale-bluebook/&quot;&gt;Yale Daily News&lt;/a&gt;, representatives of the registrar's office contacted Yu and Xu last week asking how they had obtained their data, with whose permission, and where it was hosted. Officials also expressed concerns that the site was making course evaluation information available to individuals not authorized to view the information. While the site required Yale credentials to log in, it did not have a way to sort between undergrad students and other members of the academic community. In later correspondence, the administration cited concerns about the prominence of evaluation information and unauthorized use of the words &quot;Yale,&quot; &quot;Bluebook,&quot; and the Yale logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a meeting Friday, the brothers say they were told they needed to shut down the site due to these issues. &quot;They seemed to be panicking a little bit about it,&quot; Xu said in an interview. But the brothers countered with proposals aimed at addressing the university's concerns and they rushed to implement changes over the weekend -- including changing the name to CourseTable and adjusting how they displayed rating data. &quot;We thought we could work out all of these issues,&quot; says Xu, &quot;up until Sunday night.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, without further warning, Yale blocked the page from university networks -- effectively cutting off students who intended to use their service to guide their shopping period. Xu and Yu said they scrambled to e-mail out saved worksheets to students and tried to get in contact with the administration to talk through the situation further. In response, they received a written notice that they would be referred to the Executive Committee for disciplinary action if the site was not taken down by 5 p.m. Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So they took down the site. &quot;We're disappointed, but we're afraid of compromising our degree,&quot; said Yu. Both students expressed their continued affection for the institution, but they also saw its actions as contradicting the values like a &quot;drive to promote innovation&quot; and &quot;academic freedom&quot; that they believe are central to their education at Yale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The brothers were especially surprised that the university was unwilling to cooperate with them because the administration's existing course selection software — which Yu and Xu's product was meant to improve — was &lt;a href=&quot;http://yaledailynews.com/blog/2012/08/01/university-acquires-yale-bluebook/&quot;&gt;itself a student-created product&lt;/a&gt;, eventually bought out by the university. In fact, the brothers say, the original Yale Bluebook used some of the same methods to scrape its data, and they worked with a member of the app's team to help create the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But their conversations with the administration and the content of the sites led them to believe the sticking point was the way they displayed course evaluations, which was different from Yale Bluebook because it averaged the ratings and made them easily comparable. &quot;The registrar said that originally when Yale faculty agreed to put that information online, they didn't want it to be displayed that prominently,&quot; said Yu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The brothers don't find that a very compelling reason to limit the way the information could be displayed. &quot;First, we don't think that helps professors that much,&quot;said Xu, saying that the ratings for most classes were positive. &quot;And second, we think it hurts students by limiting their ability to understand information about the classes they want to take.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the administration appears to disagree: A response sent by the Yale IT department to students who filed tickets about the blocking of the site specifically cited the its use of ratings as among the reasons the site was blocked, saying &quot;the design of the site focused on a few ratings never intended to be used for this purpose.&quot; It added, &quot;Yale takes advising and course selection seriously and has given students digital resources to help them design their schedules, such as syllabi, course descriptions, and thoughtful narrative responses written by students.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yale declined Washington Post interview requests for this story, but did share a short statement about the situation from Yale College Dean Mary Miller. The statement did not directly address their blocking of the website or the threat of disciplinary action, or the site's use of course ratings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Yale's policy on free expression and free speech entitles no one to appropriate a Yale resource and use it as their own,&quot; the statement read. It further stated its main priority at this time was supporting its own resources, &quot;not others created independently and without the university's cooperation or permission,&quot; and that &quot;all the information on the website remains remains available to students on the Yale site.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the blocking of the Web site and the forced takedown, the brothers say they have received &quot;radio silence&quot; in response to attempts to meet in person with the dean's or the registrar's office -- a situation they find frustrating, but not particularly surprising. &quot;They want this to blow over,&quot; argued Yu. &quot;In another few weeks, students will be enrolled in classes and it won't be a be a big deal anymore.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But they still believe &quot;Yale as a whole remains a great place for technology. &quot; And they say they've received a lot of support in conversations with faculty and members of the administration outside of the dean's and registrar's office. Plus their &lt;a href=&quot;http://petition.yaleplus.com/&quot;&gt;online petition&lt;/a&gt; asking the university to allow the site has attracted over 500 signatures. &quot;We think that Yale as a whole does not try to stifle innovation,&quot; they explain. &quot;Rather, the overly cautious dean's and registrar's office has just really mishandled this specific case.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related -- &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/national/16-photos-that-make-you-appreciate-america/2013/04/04/7c1f91f6-9ca6-11e2-a941-a19bce7af755_gallery.html#photo=1&quot;&gt;GALLERY: They were teachers before they celebrities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/national/16-photos-that-make-you-appreciate-america/2013/04/04/7c1f91f6-9ca6-11e2-a941-a19bce7af755_gallery.html#photo=1&quot;&gt;GALLERY: 19 photos that make you appreciate America&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;relative gallery-container&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/national/16-photos-that-make-you-appreciate-america/2013/04/04/7c1f91f6-9ca6-11e2-a941-a19bce7af755_gallery.html#photo=1&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://img.washingtonpost.com/rf/image_606w/2010-2019/WashingtonPost/2013/08/29/Interactivity/Images/tumblr_mr61gfp9uj1r81c8do1_1280.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



	&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;entry-footer&quot; score=&quot;0.0&quot;&gt;
		
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
		
&lt;/article&gt;

</description>
<title>
Yale students made a better version of its course catalog. Yale shut it down
</title>
</item>
<item>
<link>
http://blog.rdio.com/us/2014/01/keep-the-music-playing-rdio-is-now-free-on-the-web.html
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-body&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;asset-img-link&quot; href=&quot;http://blog.rdio.com/.a/6a014e87574ac9970d01a3fbf4b69a970b-pi&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a014e87574ac9970d01a3fbf4b69a970b image-full img-responsive&quot; alt=&quot;Blog-image-20140108-jj&quot; title=&quot;Blog-image-20140108-jj&quot; src=&quot;http://blog.rdio.com/.a/6a014e87574ac9970d01a3fbf4b69a970b-800wi&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you love something, set it free.  Well, we couldn't agree more.  So starting today &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rdio.com/&quot;&gt;Rdio&lt;/a&gt; is free in the U.S. on the web. That means you can listen to 20 million songs plus all the albums, playlists, and stations you love anywhere there&amp;#x2019;s a computer. Absolutely free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of this update, we&amp;#x2019;ve added in-stream messaging to Rdio on the web. These new ads are short and sweet. Free listeners will hear a mix of new feature announcements, messages from partner brands, notifications about exclusive content, and other helpful tips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our ad-free option, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rdio.com/settings/subscription/&quot;&gt;Rdio Unlimited,&lt;/a&gt; will still be available for $9.99 a month for mobile and web access. If you&amp;#x2019;re already an Rdio Unlimited subscriber, your listening experience will stay exactly the same. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And don&amp;#x2019;t forget that Stations are always free on your phone. So now you can hear music you love, whether you&amp;#x2019;re walking around town or listening through your computer, without paying a thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To celebrate our new found freedom, we figured there is no better mode of expression than music.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rdio.com/people/RdioOnRdio/playlists/7878164/I%27m_Free/&quot;&gt;Turn up these songs&lt;/a&gt; and let freedom reign:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;New to Rdio? Start listening &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rdio.com/&quot;&gt;for free&lt;/a&gt; right now.   Want the most of your Rdio experience? Upgrade to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rdio.com/settings/subscription/&quot;&gt;Rdio Unlimited&lt;/a&gt; for mobile on-demand features and ad-free listening.&lt;/p&gt;

                &lt;/div&gt;

                
                
                
                    
                    &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Rdio is Now Free on the Web
</title>
</item>
<item>
<author>
Joshua Hunt
</author>
<link>
http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/elements/2014/01/the-ipod-of-prison-sony-radio.html
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div class=&quot;entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;article&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;prison-580.jpg&quot; src=&quot;http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/elements/prison-580.jpg&quot; width=&quot;580&quot; class=&quot;mt-image-center&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In early 2005, Josh Demmitt arrived at a federal prison camp, in Sheridan, Oregon, to serve a thirty-month sentence for starting a fire outside an animal-testing facility at Brigham Young University. The nineteen-year-old received a warm welcome from his fellow inmates, who greeted him with coffee and cigarettes, advice on procuring vegan meals, and a pocket AM/FM radio. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The radio provided hours of welcome distraction for Demmitt, who had come from Sheridan&amp;#x2019;s adjoining detention center, where, he says, he spent weeks without a radio while confined to a small cell for at least twenty-three hours a day. The radio was unlike any Demmitt had seen outside prison, with a transparent plastic body that revealed the landscape within: a single AA battery rested at the bottom of its circuit board, while its antenna&amp;#x2014;one and three quarter inches of copper wire coiled around a small ferrite bar&amp;#x2014;peeked through a white Sony logo, just above the AM/FM dial. &lt;/p&gt;
 


 &lt;div id=&quot;entry-more&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The pocket analog radio, known by the bland model number SRF-39FP, is a Sony &amp;#x201C;ultralight&amp;#x201D; model manufactured for prisons. Its clear housing is meant to prevent inmates from using it to smuggle contraband, and, at under thirty dollars, it is the most affordable Sony radio on the prison market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That market consists of commissaries, which were established by the Department of Justice in 1930 to provide prisoners with items not supplied by their institutions; by offering a selection of shampoos and soaps, they shifted personal hygiene costs to inmates, while distractions like playing cards eased tensions among the nation&amp;#x2019;s growing prison population. More than half a million inmates each week shop at commissaries stocked by the Keefe Group, a privately held company that sells items to the Federal Bureau of Prisons, and twelve out of fourteen privately managed state departments of corrections. A sample commissary order form lists items like an I.B.M. typewriter ribbon, hair dye, RC Cola, Sensodyne toothpaste, chili-garlic sauce, Koss CL-20 headphones, and a &amp;#x201C;Sony Radio.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commissaries often carry other, bargain-brand radios, but according to former inmates and employees of the Bureau of Prisons and the Keefe Group, who spoke on the condition of anonymity, America&amp;#x2019;s federal prisoners are most likely to own a Sony. Melissa Dolan, a Sony spokesperson, confirmed in an e-mail that selling portable radios in American prisons has long been a &amp;#x201C;stable business&amp;#x201D; that represents &amp;#x201C;sizable&amp;#x201D; sales for the company. Of the models available, the SRF-39FP remains an undisputed classic, still found on commissary lists an impressive fifteen years after its initial release, making it nearly as common behind prison walls as Apple&amp;#x2019;s iPod once was outside of them, despite competition from newer devices like digital radios and MP3 players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But sheer availability doesn&amp;#x2019;t explain its ubiquity. The SRF-39FP is the gold standard among prison radios in part because it runs on a single AA battery, and offers forty hours of listening time&amp;#x2014;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/ipodclassic/features.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;longer than an iPod Classic&lt;/a&gt;. Digital models can require twice as many batteries, like the Sony SRF-M35FP, which runs on two AAAs. Federal inmates are particularly attuned to battery life because they are allowed to spend just three hundred and twenty dollars each month on commissary goods; more cash spent on batteries means less for snacks, stationery, clothing, and toiletries. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The importance of radio battery life in prison communities cannot be overstated; the devices are relied on for more than listening to music, hearing about local news and weather, and watching television (TV sets in common areas often use transmitters to broadcast sound on a dedicated frequency). &lt;a href=&quot;http://mcs.sagepub.com/content/29/2/179.full.pdf+html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A study&lt;/a&gt; conducted at San Vittore prison in Milan, Italy, found that &amp;#x201C;in a place where privacy is constantly denied, radio becomes a vital tool for building and maintaining one&amp;#x2019;s private self.&amp;#x201D; Some inmates even had a term for using their radio to create a bubble of personal space: &amp;#x201C;I headphone myself,&amp;#x201D; one said. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also a bit of prison culture itself at work in the story of the SRF-39FP. Radios like the one that was loaned to Demmitt are usually left behind by inmates who have re&amp;#xEB;ntered the free world. Some prisoners believe that it is bad luck for radios to leave prison with their owners, while others believe that taking them simply violates the &amp;#x201C;convict code,&amp;#x201D; according to former inmates like Demmitt and Steven Grayson, author of &amp;#x201C;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bureauofprisons.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Unauthorized Federal Prison Manual.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#x201D; Whether radios are abandoned as a matter of solidarity, convenience, or good karma, they pass from inmate to inmate, serving one sentence after another. The durable, analog SRF-39FPs have been changing hands in this manner for a decade and a half, which adds up to a lot of radios in circulation. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This practice helps explain the relative rarity of the SRF-39FP outside prisons. A unit in good condition can fetch up to double or triple its retail value among enthusiasts and collectors like Gary DeBock, a co-founder of the Ultralight Radio Group. According to DeBock, the outside supply depends upon stock siphoned from the California prison system and sold on auction sites like eBay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DeBock is a member of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dxing.info/introduction.dx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;#x201C;DXing&amp;#x201D; community&lt;/a&gt;, whose hobbyists attempt to pick up distant radio or television signals, including those from amateur or pirate radio stations. (&amp;#x201C;DX&amp;#x201D; is shorthand for &amp;#x201C;distant stations.&amp;#x201D;) DeBock&amp;#x2019;s fascination with the SRF-39FP began when he realized that it could receive AM signals from places as distant as Japan and Korea at his home in Puyallup, Washington. &amp;#x201C;Since then, I&amp;#x2019;ve probably had more exposure to the SRF-39FP than anyone else who has managed to stay out of prison,&amp;#x201D; DeBock said. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Others in the online DXing community argue that the SRF-39FP is superior to virtually every other pocket analog radio, praising it for its large tuning thumbwheel, over-all sensitivity and audio quality, and, above all, its reputed indestructibility. Electronics and radio collectors also marvel at features that are normally associated with professional equipment rather than consumer goods: in particular, an exceptional single-integrated-circuit receiver that insures reception in remote locations&amp;#x2014;or deep within heavy prison walls. In fact, the SRF-39FP was one of the first radios to use the breakthrough CXA1129N integrated-circuit chip, considered by DeBock to be the primary innovation among Sony pocket radios; it helped make the SRF-39FP the smallest and most sophisticated in a line of pocket radios that had launched two decades earlier, in the late nineteen-seventies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent years, Sony has opted to shift its prison-radio lineup away from analog, focussing instead on digital models like the SRF-M35FP. Last year, the Bureau of Prisons decided that it was time to further upgrade prison tech. Following a successful test at the same West Virginia federal prison camp where Martha Stewart spent five months for lying about a stock sale, prison officials began selling MP3 players that allow inmates to download songs at terminals in prison commissaries. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Bureau of Prisons spokesperson said that the MP3 program wasn&amp;#x2019;t expected to make money in its early years. Price is one reason: the MP3 player sold in federal prisons costs roughly three times as much as an SRF-39FP, and downloads can cost up to a dollar and fifty-five cents per song. Limited song selection is another reason; the Bureau of Prisons prohibits songs deemed explicit or likely to incite the inmate population. (JPay, a company that provides services to inmates, boasts that, &lt;a href=&quot;http://jpay.com/pmusic.aspx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;with its catalogue of ten million songs&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;#x201C;no other music service in corrections offers as many tracks for download.&amp;#x201D;) However, despite modest expectations for the technology upgrade, the Bureau of Prisons spokesperson Ed Ross said that more than fifty per cent of federal inmates have already bought MP3 players. It seems inevitable that the MP3 player will soon completely eclipse radios like the SRF-39FP in American prisons, just as they did outside, but for now both devices are woven into prison life. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Josh Demmitt left his Oregon prison camp in May, 2007, two and a half years after he had arrived. While his radio didn&amp;#x2019;t come back with him to suburban Utah, within a matter of weeks he bought his first iPod.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/viajoshhunt&quot;&gt;Joshua Hunt&lt;/a&gt; is a freelance journalist who has reported on business, technology, and sports in Japan for the New York Times.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Illustration by Matthew Hollister.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;/article&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

 &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
The iPod of Prison
</title>
</item>
<item>
<author>
Zachary M. Seward, David Yanofsky, Zachary M. Seward and David Yanofsky
</author>
<link>
http://qz.com/167993/frere-jones-is-suing-hoefler-for-his-half-of-the-worlds-preeminent-digital-type-foundry/
</link>
<description>
&lt;div class=&quot;item-body&quot; score=&quot;32.5&quot;&gt;
		&lt;div score=&quot;30.0&quot;&gt;
			
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.typography.com/&quot;&gt;Hoefler &amp;amp; Frere-Jones&lt;/a&gt;, the preeminent digital type foundry, has broken out into civil war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type designer Tobias Frere-Jones claims he has been cheated out of his half of the company by his business partner, Jonathan Hoefler. In a blistering lawsuit filed today in New York City, Frere-Jones says he was duped into transferring ownership of several fonts, including the world-famous &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.typography.com/fonts/whitney/overview/&quot;&gt;Whitney&lt;/a&gt;, to Hoefler &amp;amp; Frere-Jones (HFJ) on the understanding that he would own 50% of the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In the most profound treachery and sustained exploitation of friendship, trust and confidence, Hoefler accepted all of the benefits provided by Frere-Jones while repeatedly promising Frere-Jones that he would give him the agreed equity, only to refuse to do so when finally demanded,” the suit claims. Here’s the full complaint:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hoefler couldn’t immediately be reached for comment. Messages left at the offices of HFJ weren’t immediately returned. (See below for their statement.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frere-Jones joined the company that would come to be called HFJ in 1999. The suit portrays Frere-Jones as the firm’s design genius, and Hoefler as the business and marketing man. In public, the pair have generally been regarded as equals. But the contract that made it so, according to the lawsuit, was never written down and signed. Frere-Jones claims he had an oral contract with Hoefler that entitles him to half the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dispute came to a head last year. ”Stop it. I’m working on it. Stop harassing me,” Hoefler allegedly wrote to Frere-Jones last summer. The suit claims, “On October 21, 2013, for the first time, Hoefler explicitly reneged on his personal agreement to transfer 50% of HTF to Frere-Jones.” (HTF refers to the Hoefler Type Foundry, the company’s original name.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frere-Jones’s lawyer, Fredric Newman, a senior partner at Hoguet Newman Regal &amp;amp; Kenney, said in a phone interview, ”The two partners tried to resolve it, but couldn’t, and so Mr. Frere-Jones had no choice but to sue to enforce his rights.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The firm is perhaps the most important type designer of the 21st century. Its fonts have graced the branding of billion-dollar companies, and the covers of glossy magazines. Movie-trailer warning labels in the United States are set in Gotham, an HFJ typeface that was also famously used by Barack Obama’s 2008 presidential campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;qz-inline-image aligncenter&quot; score=&quot;16.25&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;http://qzprod.files.wordpress.com/2014/01/gotham.png?w=640&amp;amp;h=499&quot; class=&quot;size-medium_10&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Gotham&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
			&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Gotham&lt;/span&gt;
			&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Hoefler &amp;amp; Frere-Jones&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;p&gt;HFJ’s typefaces have won admiration from designers by taking advantage of the limitless environment of digital design. Where most typefaces only had two weights and two styles in one width, HFJ became known for creating typefaces with several weights and several styles in several widths that included advanced features like alternate characters, and support for multiple alphabets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;qz-inline-image aligncenter&quot; score=&quot;16.25&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;http://qzprod.files.wordpress.com/2014/01/screen-shot-2014-01-16-at-6-51-41-pm.png?w=640&amp;amp;h=412&quot; class=&quot;size-medium_10&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Whitney&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
			&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Whitney&lt;/span&gt;
			&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Hoefler &amp;amp; Frere-Jones&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;update&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update (Jan. 17, 2:45pm ET): &lt;/strong&gt;HFJ &lt;a href=&quot;http://typography.com/press/20140117&quot;&gt;released a statement&lt;/a&gt;, set in the firm’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.typography.com/fonts/mercury-text/overview/&quot;&gt;Mercury&lt;/a&gt; typeface, denying Frere-Jones’s claims and saying the company will henceforth be known as Hoefler &amp;amp; Co.:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week, designer Tobias Frere-Jones, a longtime employee of The Hoefler Type Foundry, Inc. (d/b/a “Hoefler &amp;amp; Frere-Jones”), decided to leave the company. With Tobias’s departure, the company founded by Jonathan Hoefler in 1989 will become known as Hoefler &amp;amp; Co.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following his departure, Tobias filed a claim against company founder Jonathan Hoefler. Its allegations are not the facts, and they profoundly misrepresent Tobias’s relationship with both the company and Jonathan. Whether as The Hoefler Type Foundry, Hoefler &amp;amp; Frere-Jones, or Hoefler &amp;amp; Co., our company has always been a great place for designers, which is why it’s always been and will continue to be a great place for design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It goes without saying that all of us are disappointed by Tobias’s actions. The company will vigorously defend itself against these allegations, which are false and without legal merit. In the meantime, we’re all hard at work, continuing to create the kinds of typefaces that designers have come to expect from us for more than 25 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;


		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
</description>
<title>
Frere-Jones is suing Hoefler for half of preeminent digital type foundry
</title>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
