<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version='2.0'>
<channel>
<generator>
clj-rss
</generator>
<link>
https://news.ycombinator.com
</link>
<title>
myread
</title>
<description>
myread
</description>
<item>
<author>
The Doctor
</author>
<link>
http://blog.chewxy.com/2014/01/20/why-does-a-good-kettle-cost-90
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;Yesterday morning I woke up to a house without electricity &amp;#x2013; that meant I woke up in a puddle of sweat because the fan was no longer turned on. It turned out that my housemate, while making coffee, had tripped the mains of the house. The kettle had caused the trip. It was no longer safe to use the kettle and so I had to buy a new kettle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure id=&quot;attachment_1790&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.chewxy.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/IMG_3320S.jpg?114f79&quot; alt=&quot;My Dead Kettle&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-1790&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption id=&quot;figcaption_attachment_1790&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;The Dead Kettle&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I had coincidentally been considering buying a new kettle to replace the old one, which I have used since 2007.  I was also kinda tired of sticking a thermometer in the water to figure out the temperature of the water before I brew my coffee or tea. However, I never actually had a good reason to do so. The kettle we had was absolutely serviceable, and there wasn&amp;#x2019;t a good reason to change it. Now I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, I took a break from writing &lt;a href=&quot;https://leanpub.com/jsinterviewquestions?utm_source=kettlearticle&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_term=book&amp;amp;utm_content=book&amp;amp;utm_campaign=product&quot; title=&quot;Javascript Interview Questions&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;my book on Javascript interview questions&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://leanpub.com/underhandedjavascript?utm_source=kettlearticle&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_term=book&amp;amp;utm_content=book&amp;amp;utm_campaign=product&quot; title=&quot;Underhanded Javascript&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;alternate title: Underhanded Javascript&lt;/a&gt;) and hopped online to find the best variable temperature control kettles I can find. Being the coffee and tea snob that I am, I perused a number of forums, looking for the best recommendations for such a kettle. I narrowed my choices down to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001DYERBK/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B001DYERBK&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=antwzumuniv-20&quot;&gt;Breville BKE820XL&lt;/a&gt;($149), the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003KYSLNQ/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B003KYSLNQ&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=antwzumuniv-20&quot;&gt;Cuisinart CPK-17&lt;/a&gt;($115), or the Sunbeam KE9450($100). The main reason why I shortlisted them was because they had temperature control. There was also another brand that was mentioned &amp;#x2013; Shark, or Belle, or Da Vinci &amp;#x2013; basically Chinese knockoffs of the Cuisinart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one thing I noticed about these is that they all cost more than $90, which is way more than what I&amp;#x2019;m willing to pay for a kettle. My old kettle had cost me something like $10 from K-Mart. I wasn&amp;#x2019;t very willing to part with so much money for a kettle. So I decided to look for a cheaper version &amp;#x2013; I was willing to forgo the temperature control &amp;#x2013; afterall, I had been using a manual thermometer for years and it didn&amp;#x2019;t affect my making tea or coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My housemate had also mentioned earlier that she would not prefer a plastic kettle and would prefer something metal. And so I went to look for normal electrical kettles. To my frustration &amp;#x2013; all the basic kettles cost roughly the same price: $39. The branded ones cost slightly more, and the non-branded ones cost slightly less. Why in the world would it cost so much? A kettle is not something difficult to build. The most difficult part is the grounding of it &amp;#x2013; which metal kettles are in sore need off, lest they give you an electric shock. But it&amp;#x2019;s really not that difficult to build a kettle, nor does it cost that much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to Build a Kettle With Temperature Control&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x2019;m a big fan of conceptual thinking. I&amp;#x2019;ve once &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.chewxy.com/2013/07/03/do-not-expect-breakthroughs/&quot; title=&quot;Do Not Expect Breakthroughs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;complained&lt;/a&gt; about some of my acquaintences&amp;#x2019; inability to even conceptually build something, what more actually building something. In &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0201657880/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0201657880&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=antwzumuniv-20&quot;&gt;Programming Pearls&lt;/a&gt;, this was referred to as the skill to do back-of-the-envelope-calculation. I think it&amp;#x2019;s a very good skill to have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I began to conceptually build a kettle with temperature controls. I chose a top-down approach to building this in my mind. First, I built a mental model of what is needed in a basic kettle: a heating element, a receptacle to store liquid while it boils, some sort of automatic off switch &amp;#x2013; probably heat powered &amp;#x2013; to turn the switch off once it hits boiling point. Then I think about what extra stuff are needed to build the same kettle, except with temperature control. Temperature control indicates that a) a reading of the temperature of the water is required; b) a switch that could understand the reading of the water temperature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This implied only one thing: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PID_controller&quot; title=&quot;PID controller&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a PID&lt;/a&gt;, and a relay of some sort. I know what PIDs cost &amp;#x2013; I own a couple of PID controllers and have built one from scratch. Because of the cost, that also meant that the kettle that I currently have (and that is broken), cannot possibly be digitally controlled &amp;#x2013; it&amp;#x2019;d cost too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dismantling the kettle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So out of curiosity, I began to dismantle my kettle. A kettle is an extremely simple electrical appliance, really. A heating coil heats up water. When it is hot enough, it stops. And I was right &amp;#x2013; it was ridiculously simple. It simply consisted of a switch, a power source and a heating element:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.chewxy.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/IMG_3334S.jpg?114f79&quot; alt=&quot;Power source, switch and heating element&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-1794&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had removed the switch to remove the heating element from the jug. The image above shows a reconstruction of how the power supply connects to the heating element. Inset is the power supply connected to the switch. The red wires are to a LED which tells you that the heating element is turned on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I was still puzzled by how the kettle would automatically turn off when the water boiled. And so I looked carefully at the details of everything in the kettle. Suddenly it hit me. I was looking at it all along, and it was staring back at me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.chewxy.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/IMG_3324S.jpg?114f79&quot; alt=&quot;The back of the heating element, exposing the bimetallic strip&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-1796&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK, paredolia asides, the metal strip in the middle actually plays a very important part in the analog automatic control. I had actually seen one of those before when I was very young. It&amp;#x2019;s actually a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bimetallic_strip&quot; title=&quot;Bimetallic strip&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bimetallic strip&lt;/a&gt; that curls outwards when heated. It&amp;#x2019;s basically 2 pieces of metal that is pressed into one strip. Because the different metals have different expansion rates when heated, heating a bimetallic strip would cause it to bend one way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To prove that, I took a blowtorch to it and it curled outwards exactly as I thought it would. When it cooled down, it became a flat strip again. The metal strip curved outwards. It must trigger something. Looking at the back of the power source, I found what it triggered &amp;#x2013; a spring loaded switch. Here&amp;#x2019;s how the back of the power supply looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.chewxy.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/IMG_3325S.jpg?114f79&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.chewxy.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/IMG_3325S.jpg?114f79&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3325S&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-1797&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way the kettle is constructed, the heating element and the power source are pressed together when the blue switch is pressed down to turn on the kettle. The switch is basically a see-saw. When it&amp;#x2019;s pressed down, the lever will latch on at the top (the silver coloured piece in the picture above), pressing the power source towards the heating element. The copper piece in the picture above comes into contact with the metal base plate of the heating element, and the circuit is complete. The heating element heats up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the bimetallic strip gets heated up, it curls outwards, pressing on the trigger. The trigger, when pressed, pushes the lever outwards, causing the latch to unlatch. Once the latch is undone, the power source is no longer pressing onto the base plate of the heating element. The circuit is broken, and the water stops heating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a certain elegance to these analogue systems that one must be able to appreciate. Using a bimetallic strip to trigger a mechanical trigger is simply quite a brilliantly elegant way of solving a problem. There is no reason to build an expensive kettle with digital controls if perfectly cheap and simple analogue solutions like these exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How Much Does A Basic Kettle Cost&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once one knows how something works, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.chewxy.com/2012/09/24/magic-lost/&quot; title=&quot;Magic, Lost&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the magic is lost&lt;/a&gt;. Very quickly I began tabulating how much it would cost to build and market a kettle. My answer came to a little over $7. Even with the fanciest metal designs, I estimate it&amp;#x2019;d cost no more than $12 to make and market a basic kettle with no bells and whistles. Even with the most generous of all estimates &amp;#x2013; which is to say extremely expensive industrial designers were hired to craft the shape of the bottle (let&amp;#x2019;s assume we&amp;#x2019;re talking about something like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.casabugatti.com/design-appliances/kettle-X1?id=14-VERACR&quot; title=&quot;Bugatti Vera&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bugatti Vera&lt;/a&gt;.), and that the manufacturer uses the most expensive possible manufacturing tools, the price over a mass amount of units (say 100,000 units) would not cost more than $16.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why did the rest of the basic kettles cost $39? Given the almost-same price from all the brands, they all have to function on the same principle essentially. They&amp;#x2019;d also have to have pretty much the same fixed and variable costs. If we assume we see the market in action, then that would mean I was wrong. It didn&amp;#x2019;t cost $16 to manufacture and market those kettles. The problem is, there exist on the market, homebrand kettles that cost $10 or so. If both homebrand and branded kettles use a similar principle, then it would be cause to wonder why the basic kettles of the bigger brands all cost $39.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless of course, those $39 kettles use a digital solution to stop the water from boiling. But that is just rather silly, given that an analogue solution works better. I do not see how a digital solution is actually a superior solution. It&amp;#x2019;s rather like saying replacing your car&amp;#x2019;s control panel with a touch screen is a better idea &amp;#x2013; oh wait. Tesla actually thought &lt;a href=&quot;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/a/a3/Tesla_Model_S_digital_panels.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Tesla Model S digital panel&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; was a good idea. It isn&amp;#x2019;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that a digital control solution is not going to be much superior (and in fact, like the Tesla example, could actually be inferior) &amp;#x2013; water has ONE boiling temperature &amp;#x2013; 100 Celcius, why would a basic kettle cost $39 and up? Yes, I mean, people could be paying for the design (because a red kettle is so going to boil water faster than a white kettle), but really, there is no basis in reality to pay for such an expensive kettle. Especially so if the basic kettle is digitally driven. It&amp;#x2019;s just a waste of time and energy of the designers, trying to cramp so much electronics into a small space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, rather, basic kettles from bigger brands cost $39 as a form of price differentiation. Consumers who can afford to pay more, or do not know better, would pay more for the same basic product. Anything extra is mostly cosmetic and has no say on the functionality (or if it does, like for example, if the shape or material of a kettle would help it retain heat better, it doesn&amp;#x2019;t add much marginal utility).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to Build a Kettle With Temperature Control &amp;#x2013; pt2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to why I actually want a kettle with temperature control. Unlike a basic kettle, I understand why a more advanced kettle with variable temperatures would cost so much more. As previously mentioned, having temperature control means requiring something to read the temperature of the water &amp;#x2013; a temperature probe (I own a couple of PT100 probes myself), and a PID controller. Those things are not cheap, even if one buys them in bulk. A basic PID would set one back about $30 (and that was the best bulk price I could get). With PID controllers also come costs of hiring electronic designers, and micro-controller programmers. Also, a relay is required to turn on and off the kettle, instead of mechanical solutions like the one above. Furthermore, these electronics have to be heatproofed. A kettle is a very hot thing, and the microcontrollers in the kettle must not fail under heated circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these little things add up. But it&amp;#x2019;s actually useful. Instead of hiring electronic designers, programmers, and using electronics for basic functionality, the main use is for precision boiling. And that&amp;#x2019;s a good use. This is one of the main reasons why I am looking at variable temperature kettles (okay, I admit, it&amp;#x2019;d make my life a lot easier too, if I didn&amp;#x2019;t have to stand and take the temperature of the water every time I make my coffee or tea).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason is I don&amp;#x2019;t feel ripped off paying for a variable temperature kettle. Knowing how a basic analogue kettle works and especially knowing how much it would cost to build one, I would feel terrible if I had to spend $40 on a kettle that works exactly the same way in principle. And yes, before you ask, the ones I saw, they DO work on the same exact principles. How do I know this? The switch in those kettles are mechanical. A digital kettle wouldn&amp;#x2019;t have a mechanical switch (you can design one that has, but I don&amp;#x2019;t see the point).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#x2019;s a rough bill of materials/services and estimates I came out with, assuming a unit cost over 100,000 units in a production run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Estimated Cost&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Manufacture of kettle body (metal, because plastic is so pedestrian)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Industrial design of kettle body (assuming 3 high calibre ($100k p/a) industrial designer)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PID Controller + other electronics&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Heating element&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Electronics engineer (assuming 3 electronics engineer and 2 test technicians)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Various manufacturing fixed cost (safety tests, product tests, etc)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Marketing, stocking, etc fees&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It comes close to $45. And these are on quite generous assumptions. I have no doubt that given the scale of these big branded companies, they would have more economies of scale and scope to reduce these costs even further. Of couse, this being a mental estimate, it could go very wrong. It could be the companies don&amp;#x2019;t manufacture 100,000 units per run. That would change things quite a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means a markup of double. But the main reason why I would rather go for a $90 kettle instead of a $39 kettle is because the $90 kettle does a lot more. There is quite a bit more function per dollar than the $39 one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;But &amp;#x2026;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, then there&amp;#x2019;s the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0083I7THI/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0083I7THI&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=antwzumuniv-20&quot;&gt;Hamilton Beach programmable kettle&lt;/a&gt;, which comes pretty close to the estimated cost price of building a variable temperature kettle I had estimated. I had estimated it costs about $45 to build and market a digital kettle with basic PID functions. I was willing to accept advanced kettles cost about $90 because PID tuning is a variable quality, and I&amp;#x2019;d be willing to accept that companies like Bonavita or Breville actually spend more time and money into tuning these little details. I don&amp;#x2019;t know how Hamilton Beach did it, and I&amp;#x2019;m exceedingly curious as to how. The people at Steepster &lt;a href=&quot;http://steepster.com/discuss/5108-variable-temp-kettle-opinions&quot; title=&quot;Steepster discussion on the Hamilton Beach kettle&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;don&amp;#x2019;t think too highly of it&lt;/a&gt; though, so there&amp;#x2019;s some clues there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for which kettle I bought, the house is currently kettle-less while I figure out which one to buy. I&amp;#x2019;m leaning heavily on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003KYSLNQ/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B003KYSLNQ&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=antwzumuniv-20&quot;&gt;Cuisinart CPK-17&lt;/a&gt;. I am also quite partial to just buying a water warmer like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000MAFJRM/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B000MAFJRM&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=antwzumuniv-20&quot;&gt;Zojirushi&lt;/a&gt;, mainly because my mum uses one and I grew up with one, but who knows, I might just go buy another $10 kettle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TR;DR: &lt;/strong&gt;I seem to have given a lot of thought to buying a kettle (this article is 2250 words long). I come to the conclusion that expensive basic kettles are the same as cheap basic kettles, except for price differentiation. The increase in marginal utility from purchasing a expensive kettle is not big enough compared to buying a baseline cheap kettle to warrant it. It&amp;#x2019;d be better to buy a temperature control kettle, as then the increase in marginal utility would be enough to warrant puchasing it. What do you think?&lt;/p&gt;

					
					
			&lt;/div&gt;
			
			
			&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Why Does A Good Kettle Cost $90+?
</title>
</item>
<item>
<link>
http://www.latimes.com/nation/nationnow/la-na-nn-officemax-mail-20140119,0,6457094.story#axzz2qubhydAY
</link>
<description>

</description>
<title>
Dad gets OfficeMax mail addressed 'Daughter Killed in Car Crash'
</title>
</item>
<item>
<link>
http://www.thedrinkingrecord.com/2014/01/19/romanian-billionaire-saves-openbsd/
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content&quot;&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;The following link: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.osnews.com/story/27519/_OpenBSD_will_shut_down_if_we_do_not_have_the_funding_http://&quot;&gt;http://www.osnews.com/story/27519/_OpenBSD_will_shut_down_if_we_do_not_have_the_funding_&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was dropped in the IRC Channel &lt;a href=&quot;http://log.bitcoin-assets.com/?date=19-01-2014#449580&quot;&gt;#bitcoin-assets&lt;/a&gt; and within hours an announcement was made:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://log.bitcoin-assets.com/?date=20-01-2014#449869&quot;&gt;mircea_popescu: and it pleases me to announce openbsd got itself sponsored.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that not only did this announcing happen on IRC, the important fact finding happened there as well, from the channel #openbsd:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;Jan 19 22:14:04 &amp;lt;mircea_popescu&amp;gt;	soo, who has the authority to make a deal so I can cover the 20k shortfall 
Jan 19 22:16:24 &amp;lt;woopstar&amp;gt;	mircea_popescu: you need to contact Theo
Jan 19 22:16:32 &amp;lt;mircea_popescu&amp;gt;	how would i go about that ?
Jan 19 22:18:27 &amp;lt;woopstar&amp;gt;	mircea_popescu: i believe his email is [redacted because email addresses don't belong in plaintext]
Jan 19 22:20:32 &amp;lt;mircea_popescu&amp;gt;	woopstar ty.
Jan 19 22:20:49 &amp;lt;woopstar&amp;gt;	mircea_popescu: anytime. Would be fantastic, if you can set up a deal with Theo&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This episode just goes to show that IRC even in the 2010's continues to be one of the most expressive, influential, and effective communications mediums on the Internet. It also shows for Open Source projects seeking sponsorships to continue their operations that the traditional channels by which they hope the Microsofts, Apples, and Oracles of the world that happily vacuum up their code may not be the there in their time of need, but if they are truly doing something that is both useful and interesting chances are someone out there might have the money and intelligence to appreciate your project enough to buy it at least another year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I for one am happy that for at least another year the Vaxen will have an OS to run.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;

	
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Romanian saves OpenBSD
</title>
</item>
<item>
<author>
James Clear
</author>
<link>
http://www.entrepreneur.com/article/230333
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;article&quot; class=&quot;nlopt&quot;&gt;

						&lt;div class=&quot;articleimg&quot;&gt;
				&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.entrepreneur.com/dbimages/article/h1/forget-setting-goals-focus-this-instead.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Forget Setting Goals. Focus on This Instead.&quot; width=&quot;300&quot;&gt;
							
									&lt;p class=&quot;courtesy&quot;&gt;Image credit: Shutterstock&lt;/p&gt;			
							&lt;/div&gt;
			    
		    
		
		&lt;p&gt;We all have things that we want to achieve in our lives -- getting into the better shape, building a successful business, raising a wonderful family, writing a best-selling book, winning a championship, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for most of us, the path to those things starts by setting a specific and actionable goal. At least, this is how I approached my life until recently. I would set goals for classes I took, for weights that I wanted to lift in the gym, and for clients I wanted in my business.&lt;/p&gt;


			


			
		&lt;p&gt;What I'm starting to realize, however, is that when it comes to actually getting things done and making progress in the areas that are important to you, there is a much better way to do things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all comes down to the difference between goals and systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Difference Between Goals and Systems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What's the difference between goals and systems?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you're a coach, &lt;/strong&gt;your goal is to win a championship. Your system is what your team does at practice each day.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you're a writer, &lt;/strong&gt;your goal is to write a book. Your system is the writing schedule that you follow each week.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you're a runner,&lt;/strong&gt; your goal is to run a marathon. Your system is your training schedule for the month.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you're an entrepreneur,&lt;/strong&gt; your goal is to build a million dollar business. Your system is your sales and marketing process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now for the really interesting question:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you completely ignored your goals and focused only on your system, would you still get results?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.entrepreneur.com/article/230153&quot;&gt;How You Can Form Good Habits and Stick to Them&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you were a basketball coach and you ignored your goal to win a championship and focused only on what your team does at practice each day, would you still get results?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think you would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example, I just added up the total word count for the articles I've written this year. (You can see them all &lt;a href=&quot;http://jamesclear.com/archives&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.) In the last 12 months, I've written over 115,000 words. The typical book is about 50,000 to 60,000 words, so I have basically written two books this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this is such a surprise because I never set a goal for my writing. I didn't measure my progress in relation to some benchmark. I never set a word count goal for any particular article. I never said, &quot;I want to write two books this year.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I did focus on was writing one article every Monday and Thursday. And after sticking to that schedule for 11 months, the result was 115,000 words. I focused on my system and the process of doing the work. In the end, I enjoyed the same (or perhaps better) results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let's talk about three more reasons why you should focus on systems instead of goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Goals reduce your current happiness.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you're working toward a goal, you are essentially saying, &quot;I'm not good enough yet, but I will be when I reach my goal.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with this mindset is that you're teaching yourself to always put happiness and success off until the next milestone is achieved. &quot;Once I reach my goal, then I'll be happy. Once I achieve my goal, then I'll be successful.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SOLUTION: Commit to a process, not a goal.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choosing a goal puts a huge burden on your shoulders. Can you imagine if I had made it my goal to write two books this year? Just writing that sentence stresses me out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we do this to ourselves all the time. We place unnecessary stress on ourselves to lose weight or to succeed in business or to write a best-selling novel. Instead, you can keep things simple and reduce stress by focusing on the daily process and sticking to your schedule, rather than worrying about the big, life-changing goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you focus on the practice instead of the performance, you can enjoy the present moment and improve at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Goals are strangely at odds with long-term progress.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might think your goal will keep you motivated over the long-term, but that's not always true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider someone training for a half-marathon. Many people will work hard for months, but as soon as they finish the race, they stop training. Their goal was to finish the half-marathon and now that they have completed it, that goal is no longer there to motivate them. When all of your hard work is focused on a particular goal, what is left to push you forward after you achieve it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can create a type of &quot;yo-yo effect&quot; where people go back and forth from working on a goal to not working on one. This type of cycle makes it difficult to build upon your progress for the long-term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SOLUTION: Release the need for immediate results.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was training at the gym last week and I was doing my second-to-last set of clean and jerks. When I hit that rep, I felt a small twinge in my leg. It wasn't painful or an injury, just a sign of fatigue near the end of my workout. For a minute or two, I thought about doing my final set. Then, I reminded myself that I plan to do this for the rest of my life and decided to call it a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.entrepreneur.com/article/230240&quot;&gt;8 Steps to Having Wildly Productive Mornings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a situation like the one above, a goal-based mentality will tell you to finish the workout and reach your goal. After all, if you set a goal and you don't reach it, then you feel like a failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But with a systems-based mentality, I had no trouble moving on. Systems-based thinking is never about hitting a particular number, it's about sticking to the process and not missing workouts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I know that if I never miss a workout, then I will lift bigger weights in the long-run. And that's why systems are more valuable than goals. Goals are about the short-term result. Systems are about the long-term process. In the end, process always wins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Goals suggest that you can control things that you have no control over.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can't predict the future. (I know, shocking.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But every time we set a goal, we try to do it. We try to plan out where we will be and when we will make it there. We try to predict how quickly we can make progress, even though we have no idea what circumstances or situations will arise along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SOLUTION: Build feedback loops.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each Friday, I spend 15 minutes filling out a small spreadsheet with the most critical metrics for my business. For example, in one column I calculate the conversion rate (the percentage of website visitors that join &lt;a href=&quot;http://jamesclear.com/newsletter&quot;&gt;my free email newsletter&lt;/a&gt; each week). I rarely think about this number, but checking that column each week provides a feedback loop that tells me if I'm doing things right. When that number drops, I know that I need to send high quality traffic to my site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feedback loops are important for building good systems because they allow you to keep track of many different pieces without feeling the pressure to predict what is going to happen with everything. Forget about predicting the future and build a system that can signal when you need to make adjustments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fall In Love With Systems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of this is to say that goals are useless. However, I've found that goals are good for &lt;em&gt;planning &lt;/em&gt;your progress and systems are good for actually &lt;em&gt;making &lt;/em&gt;progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, I think I'm going to officially declare 2014 the &quot;Year of the Sloth&quot; so that everyone will be forced to slow down and make consistent, methodical progress rather than chasing sexy goals for a few weeks and then flaming out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goals can provide direction and even push you forward in the short-term, but eventually a well-designed system will always win. Having a system is what matters. Committing to the process is what makes the difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;http://jamesclear.com/goals-systems&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;version of this article&lt;/a&gt; was first published on JamesClear.com.&lt;/p&gt;           
	
	
	
		&lt;p class=&quot;h12&quot;&gt;The author is an Entrepreneur contributor. The opinions expressed are those of the writer.&lt;/p&gt;
			
		
		
	
		
    	

    	
			
	
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Forget Setting Goals. Focus on Systems Instead
</title>
</item>
<item>
<author>
About
</author>
<link>
http://xkcd.com/1319/
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;middleContainer&quot; class=&quot;box&quot;&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;ctitle&quot;&gt;Automation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;comic&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/automation.png&quot; title=&quot;'Automating' comes from the roots 'auto-' meaning 'self-', and 'mating', meaning 'screwing'.&quot; alt=&quot;Automation&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;br&gt;
Permanent link to this comic: http://xkcd.com/1319/&lt;br&gt;
Image URL (for hotlinking/embedding): http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/automation.png

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


</description>
<title>
xkcd: Automation
</title>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
