<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version='2.0'>
<channel>
<generator>
clj-rss
</generator>
<link>
https://news.ycombinator.com
</link>
<title>
myread
</title>
<description>
myread
</description>
<item>
<author>
Terence Eden
</author>
<link>
http://shkspr.mobi/blog/2014/01/another-google-privacy-flaw/
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-bodycopy cf&quot;&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&quot;http://mymisanthropicmusings.org.uk/&quot;&gt;wife&lt;/a&gt; likes to set reminders for herself in Google Calendar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://shkspr.mobi/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Email-Pay-Rise-fs8.png&quot; alt=&quot;Email Pay Rise-fs8&quot; width=&quot;512&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-9532&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Recently, she added a note to her &lt;em&gt;personal&lt;/em&gt; Google Calendar reading &quot;&lt;span&gt;Email &lt;a class=&quot;__cf_email__&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cloudflare.com/email-protection&quot;&gt;[email&amp;#xA0;protected]&lt;/a&gt; to discuss pay rise&lt;/span&gt;&quot; and set the date for a few months from now.  She'd had a discussion with her boss, Alice, and they'd agreed to talk about salary later in the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few moments later, Alice sent her a &quot;Meeting Accepted&quot; email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What... The...?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although pretty embarrassing, it could have been a lot worse.  It could have been &quot;&lt;span&gt;Email &lt;a class=&quot;__cf_email__&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cloudflare.com/email-protection&quot;&gt;[email&amp;#xA0;protected]&lt;/a&gt; with excuse why we can't see her&lt;/span&gt;&quot; or perhaps &quot;&lt;span&gt;Email &lt;a class=&quot;__cf_email__&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cloudflare.com/email-protection&quot;&gt;[email&amp;#xA0;protected]&lt;/a&gt; with divorce details&lt;/span&gt;&quot; or even &quot;&lt;span&gt;Email &lt;a class=&quot;__cf_email__&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cloudflare.com/email-protection&quot;&gt;[email&amp;#xA0;protected]&lt;/a&gt; to demand red stapler back&lt;/span&gt;&quot; or... well, you get the picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, my wife doesn't have a Google+ profile, so there was no information leak other than her email address (which wasn't &quot;huggle.wuggle.2012&quot; or anything daft like that!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've tried several times to recreate this behaviour.  Here's what we discovered:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you use Google Calendar on the web and put a Gmail address in the subject line, that user &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; have the event added to the calendar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They will &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; receive an email notification - although they will get a &quot;meeting reminder&quot; pop-up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating an event on an Android phone does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; trigger a meeting request.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some&lt;/em&gt; non-Gmail addresses will also see the meeting in their calendar - but others will not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you &lt;em&gt;delete&lt;/em&gt; a calendar item, the &quot;Cancellation&quot; notification is emailed &lt;strong&gt;regardless&lt;/strong&gt; of whether the user received the original invite.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://shkspr.mobi/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/Delete-fs8.png&quot; alt=&quot;Delete-fs8&quot; width=&quot;654&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-9611&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
We were unable to determine which &lt;strong&gt;non&lt;/strong&gt;-Gmail addresses would receive the item in their calendar. Some which were hosted with Google didn't receive the pseudo-invitation.  Some accounts hosted on Microsoft Exchange got the invite while others on seemingly similar systems didn't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a video showing it in action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embed-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/ZqjYb6eiMWE?version=3&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that when a user fills in the pop-up, Google Calendar asks for confirmation to send a meeting invite. When using the full interface, &lt;strong&gt;no warning whatsoever&lt;/strong&gt; is given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Impact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google has tried to be clever here.  It has failed.  Just because I am talking &lt;em&gt;about&lt;/em&gt; someone, it doesn't mean I am talking &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; someone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two main risks here - the user could expose her private Gmail account and associated Google+ data, and she could also reveal her private thoughts and feelings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google really needs to work harder at &lt;a href=&quot;http://storify.com/joliss/what-happens-when-our-software-has-broken-privacy&quot;&gt;protecting the privacy of its users&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Disclosure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This privacy issue was formally disclosed to Google on 6th January 2014.&lt;br&gt;
On 22nd January, they responded by saying they &lt;em&gt;didn't&lt;/em&gt; consider it a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We reviewed your report. After careful consideration by our security team, we feel that the issue has minimal impact on the security of our users. Let us know if you believe that this determination may be incorrect. If you'd submitted your report as part of our reward program, this means it doesn't qualify for reward or credit. Thanks for your help!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As much as I'm disappointed not to be getting a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.co.uk/about/appsecurity/reward-program/&quot;&gt;$10,000 bug bounty&lt;/a&gt;, I'm more upset that Google repeatedly finds itself &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zdnet.com/google-outed-me-7000025416/&quot;&gt;failing to keep its users' private information private&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;ins datetime=&quot;2014-01-23T13:54:42+00:00&quot;&gt;Update&lt;/ins&gt;: according to a comment on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=7107597&quot;&gt;HackerNews discussion&lt;/a&gt; - problems like this have been &lt;a href=&quot;http://lee-phillips.org/gcaldisaster/&quot;&gt;reported to Google as far back as 2010&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-10187660-9531-52e2047ab378f&quot;&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;likes-widget-placeholder post-likes-widget-placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;sd-link-color&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-flattr-button&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;FlattrButton&quot; href=&quot;http://shkspr.mobi/blog/2014/01/another-google-privacy-flaw/&quot; title=&quot; Another Google Privacy Flaw - Calendar Unexpectedly Leaks Private Information (Disclosed)&quot; rev=&quot;flattr;uid:edent42;language:en_GB;category:text;tags:bugs,gmail,google,privacy,blog;popout:0;button:compact;&quot;&gt;My wife likes to set reminders for herself in Google Calendar. Recently, she added a note to her personal Google Calendar reading &quot;Email &lt;span class=&quot;__cf_email__&quot;&gt;[email&amp;#xA0;protected]&lt;/span&gt; to discuss pay rise&quot; and set...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				
			&lt;/div&gt;

			
			


		&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Google Calendar Unexpectedly Leaks Private Information
</title>
</item>
<item>
<link>
http://bzg.fr/emacs-strip-tease.html
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;org-src-container&quot;&gt;

&lt;pre class=&quot;src src-emacs-lisp&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;;; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;A small minor mode to use a big fringe&lt;/span&gt;
(&lt;span&gt;defvar&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;bzg-big-fringe-mode&lt;/span&gt; nil)
(&lt;span&gt;define-minor-mode&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;bzg-big-fringe-mode&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;&quot;Minor mode to hide the mode-line in the current buffer.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;:init-value&lt;/span&gt; nil
  &lt;span&gt;:global&lt;/span&gt; t
  &lt;span&gt;:variable&lt;/span&gt; bzg-big-fringe-mode
  &lt;span&gt;:group&lt;/span&gt; 'editing-basics
  (&lt;span&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; (not bzg-big-fringe-mode)
      (set-fringe-style nil)
    (set-fringe-mode
     (/ (- (frame-pixel-width)
           (* 100 (frame-char-width)))
        2))))

&lt;span&gt;;; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Now activate this global minor mode&lt;/span&gt;
(bzg-big-fringe-mode 1)

&lt;span&gt;;; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Use a minimal cursor&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;;; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(setq cursor-type 'hbar)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span&gt;;; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Get rid of the indicators in the fringe&lt;/span&gt;
(mapcar (&lt;span&gt;lambda&lt;/span&gt;(fb) (set-fringe-bitmap-face fb 'org-hide))
        fringe-bitmaps)
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://bzg.fr/u/emacs-big-fringe.png&quot; alt=&quot;emacs-big-fringe.png&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Oh, but you don't want the grey fringe?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;org-src-container&quot;&gt;

&lt;pre class=&quot;src src-emacs-lisp&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;;; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Set the color of the fringe&lt;/span&gt;
(custom-set-faces
 '(fringe ((t (&lt;span&gt;:background&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&quot;white&quot;&lt;/span&gt;)))))
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://bzg.fr/u/emacs-big-white-fringe.png&quot; alt=&quot;emacs-big-white-fringe.png&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Emacs, naked
</title>
</item>
<item>
<author>
Greg Anderson, January 23, 2014, Leave a Comment
</author>
<link>
http://arcticstartup.com/2014/01/23/linda-liukas-programming-book-for-children-has-huge-first-day-on-kickstarter
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;article id=&quot;post&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    
    &lt;span class=&quot;byline&quot;&gt;
    By Greg Anderson, January 23, 2014,
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://arcticstartup.com/2014/01/23/linda-liukas-programming-book-for-children-has-huge-first-day-on-kickstarter#comments&quot;&gt;Leave a Comment&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://wp.arcticstartup.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Screen-Shot-2014-01-23-at-15.32.08-e1390484018248.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Screen Shot 2014-01-23 at 15.32.08&quot; width=&quot;580&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-46559&quot;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;It's been amazing so far,&quot; says Linda Liukas of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/lindaliukas/hello-ruby&quot;&gt;new programming book for children, Hello Ruby&lt;/a&gt;, which was put on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/lindaliukas/hello-ruby&quot;&gt;Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt; this morning. &quot;In 3.5 hours it reached its [$10,000] goal. Let's see what happens next.&quot; 
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;The topic of coding education isn't new to her - on top of her early involvement in the Aalto entrepreneurship society, Liukas is a cofounder in &lt;a href=&quot;http://railsgirls.org&quot;&gt;Railsgirls&lt;/a&gt;, a global non-profit that has taught programming to tens of thousands of women in over 160 cities. Additionally she was one of the early &lt;a href=&quot;http://codeacademy.com&quot;&gt;Codeacademy&lt;/a&gt; employees where she worked as a community manager. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liukas tells us that the Hello Ruby project got its roots three years ago when Railsgirls got started and they needed some illustrations for the web and their events. &quot;I found when I had problems thinking about garbage collection, for example, I would draw Ruby. And then last September I decided I need to be a little more systematic and someone said, 'oh, you should do a Kickstarter.'&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At time of publishing, the book has now raised $16,283 with 29 days left to go. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://wp.arcticstartup.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/9796daaa34b2501bbcf10a4e9c44e5e0_large.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;9796daaa34b2501bbcf10a4e9c44e5e0_large&quot; width=&quot;576&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-46563&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hello Ruby book will be a 32 page hardcover that covers the traditional story of friendship, being different, and technology. Rather than an artsy how-to, the book will tell the story of Ruby, a small girl who visits castles and solves problems with wise penguins. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;We instinctively thick in narrative,&quot; says Liukas. &quot;Instead of just giving kids iPad applications that react once, I think theres longer term value in this style.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally the bundle will come with a workbook for parents to sit down with their kids and think about solving problems with general programming concepts like loops, lists conditionals, sequences, and variables. Rather than punishing kids for forgetting that semicolon, the book and workbook is more focused on getting kids thinking about solving problems and teaching basic programming concepts so that later they can apply them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She promises on the Kickstarter that Hello Ruby will be shipped by August, but Liukas tells us that she recognizes everyone wants the book sooner than that. This is her first dive into the publishing world, so she promises to keep backers updated with how her progress is going. As you can see in the video below, she's kind a of a delightful person, so you might as well throw in the minimum $5 commitment just to hear how the publishing progress goes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the big initial response, Liukas tells us she might put up some milestone rewards for her backers. And perhaps later an iPad app later wouldn't be out of the question, but right now she's focused in Ruby's hardcover world. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/lindaliukas/hello-ruby&quot;&gt;find the project on Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;




  




  &lt;div id=&quot;topics&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;TOPICS&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://arcticstartup.com/tag/book&quot;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://arcticstartup.com/tag/children&quot;&gt;children&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://arcticstartup.com/tag/hello-ruby&quot;&gt;hello ruby&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://arcticstartup.com/tag/kickstarter&quot;&gt;kickstarter&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://arcticstartup.com/tag/programming&quot;&gt;programming&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  



  

        
        


        &lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Linda Liukas' Programming book for Children has Huge First Day on Kickstarter
</title>
</item>
<item>
<link>
http://venturebeat.com/2014/01/23/startup-developing-hivaids-vaccine-is-2nd-nonprofit-accepted-into-y-combinator/
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;A vaccine for HIV/AIDS has been the holy grail of the medical community for decades, and these guys may have found it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.immunityproject.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Immunity Project&lt;/a&gt; is developing a free HIV/AIDS vaccine through a radical new approach that involves data analysis and machine learning. &lt;a href=&quot;http://ycombinator.com/np.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;It is one of seven nonprofits in elite accelerator program Y Combinator&amp;#x2019;s latest batch.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#xA0;YC &lt;a href=&quot;http://venturebeat.com/2013/07/25/watsi-raises-first-ever-philanthropic-seed-round-from-silicon-valley-investors/&quot; title=&quot;Watsi raises first-ever &amp;#x2018;philanthropic seed round&amp;#x2019; from Silicon Valley&amp;#xA0;investors&quot;&gt;accepted its first nonprofit Watsi last year.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pledge.immunityproject.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Immunity Project also launched a crowdfunding campaign using Crowdhoster&lt;/a&gt; today with the goal of raising $482,000. This money will help Immunity fund its final experiment using human blood before it begins the first phase of clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x201C;This is the ultimate application of informatics to medicine,&amp;#x201D; cofounder and CEO Dr. Reid Rubsamen said in an interview. &amp;#x201C;So much vaccine design since 1953 has been based on neutralizing antibodies, but that legacy approach doesn&amp;#x2019;t work for HIV. The virus is too smart and can mutate so quickly. We are doing something very different.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When cells are infected by HIV, they send pieces of HIV protein, or &amp;#x201C;flags,&amp;#x201D; to their surface for the immune system to identify and attack. However there are hundreds of signals coming from cells, and most people&amp;#x2019;s bodies don&amp;#x2019;t have the ability to pick out the HIV cells from all the other noise, except for a small group of people known as &amp;#x201C;controllers.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One out of every 300 people living with HIV is a &amp;#x201C;controller,&amp;#x201D; meaning they carry low levels of the virus in a dormant state that never turns into AIDS. Their &amp;#x201C;immunity&amp;#x201D; to the virus is due to a unique targeting capability in their immune system that enables it to neutralize HIV&amp;#xA0;molecules by hitting them in weak spots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immunity&amp;#x2019;s algorithm sorts through the enormous amount of combinations of HIV genome and human immune system genetic data to figure out how controllers are able to keep HIV dormant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x201C;All the information from the immune system and the HIV genome generates this really, really big dataset,&amp;#x201D; Rubsamen said. &amp;#x201C;We use machine learning to understand what is happening with this dataset and reverse engineer this biological process. Hitting that tiny target is the output of a giant computer science effort.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of the vaccine is basically to turn everyone into a controller by training the immune system to attack the right targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The algorithm Immunity uses was written by Dr. David Heckerman and his colleagues at Microsoft e-Science Research. It is actually based on similar principles to spam filtering software because both spam and HIV &amp;#x201C;spread rapidly, mutate relentlessly, and have multitude of variations.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x201C;Dr. Heckerman designed algorithms to find the part on HIV that absolutely cannot mutate &amp;#x2014; the place where if it changes, the virus stops functioning,&amp;#x201D; Immunity said on its site. &amp;#x201C;In both cases, researches are using machine learning to create statistical ways of dealing with large data sets in order to find the needle in the haystack.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rubsamen said this is the first vaccine in history developed in this matter and is viewed as a rogue project by the immunology community. That said, early tests on mice have shown &amp;#x201C;overwhelmingly positive results.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rubsamen and Heckerman are both medical doctors and computer scientists. The two went to Stanford Medical School together and have known each other for decades. Rubsamen previously founded &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aradigm.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Aradigm&lt;/a&gt;, a public pharmaceutical company that develops inhalation drug products. He has more than 60 patents for drug delivery technologies and said he is leveraging this expertise to create a nasal spray, rather than an injectable vaccine, which will make it easier to administer in the developing world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amfar.org/about-hiv-and-aids/facts-and-stats/statistics--worldwide/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Over 35 million people are currently living with HIV/AIDS&lt;/a&gt;, and 6,300 new people are infected everyday. Over 4,000 people die a day from AIDS, and nearly 36 million people&amp;#xA0; have died of HIV-related causes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amfar.org/about-hiv-and-aids/facts-and-stats/statistics--worldwide/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;70 percent of all people living with HIV live in sub-Saharan Africa.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rubsamen said that, unlike retrovrial treatments, Immunity wouldn&amp;#x2019;t require a lifetime of medication &amp;#x2014; you could take the vaccine and be done. It also has potential to act preventatively. Plus Immunity plans to make the vaccine free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However there are still years of work, experimenting, clinical trials, and federal approvals to get through and millions of dollars to be raised. The vaccine has not officially entered Phase 1 yet and hopes to begin clinical trials in December 2014. The third and final phase of clinical trials, and widespread vaccination efforts, wouldn&amp;#x2019;t happen before 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it works, this will be a huge victory in the fight against HIV/AIDS and a watershed moment in immunology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Immunity Project is a partnership between biotech firm Flow Pharma and digital agency SparkArt.&amp;#xA0;Rubsamen is the CEO of Flow Pharma, and cofounder Naveen Jain is the cofounder of SparkArt. Microsoft Research contributed $1 million to the project in 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;post-boilerplate boilerplate-after&quot;&gt;

VentureBeat is&amp;#xA0;creating an index of the&amp;#xA0;&lt;a href=&quot;http://venturebeat.com/2013/10/23/the-top-online-health-services-for-consumers/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;top online health services for&amp;#xA0;consumers&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#xA0;Take a look at our initial suggestions and&amp;#xA0;&lt;a href=&quot;http://venturebeat3.polldaddy.com/s/the-top-online-health-tools&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;complete the survey&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#xA0;to help us build a definitive index. We&amp;#x2019;ll publish the official index in the weeks to come, and for those who fill out they survey, we&amp;#x2019;ll send you an expanded report free of charge.

Speak with the analyst who put this survey together to get more in-depth information,&amp;#xA0;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:research@venturebeat.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;inquire within&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;					&lt;/div&gt;

					
				&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
Startup developing HIV/AIDS vaccine is 2nd nonprofit accepted into Y Combinator
</title>
</item>
<item>
<link>
http://ibuildings.nl/blog/2013/03/4-http-security-headers-you-should-always-be-using
</link>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
	  

  
         &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://ibuildings.nl/sites/default/files/blog/298px-Internet1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What started as a dream for a worldwide library of sorts, has transformed into not only a global repository of knowledge but also the most popular and widely deployed Application Platform: the World Wide Web.&lt;br&gt;
	The poster child for Agile, it was not developed as a whole by a single entity, but rather grew as servers and clients expanded it's capabilities. Standards grew along with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While growing a solution works very well for discovering what works and what doesn't, it hardly leads to a consistent and easy to apply programming model. This is especially true for security: where ideally&amp;#xA0;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secure_by_default&quot; title=&quot;Secure by default (Security Principle) on Wikipedia&quot;&gt;the simplest thing that works is also the most secure&lt;/a&gt;, it is far too easy to introduce vulnerabilities like&amp;#xA0;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cross-site_scripting&quot;&gt;XSS&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;#xA0;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cross-site_request_forgery&quot;&gt;CSRF&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#xA0;or&amp;#xA0;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clickjacking&quot;&gt;Clickjacking&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because HTTP is an extensible protocol browsers have pioneered some useful headers to prevent or increase the difficulty of exploiting these vulnerabilities.&amp;#xA0;&lt;strong&gt;Knowing what they are and when to apply them can help you increase the security of your system&lt;/strong&gt;. &amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;
	1. Content-Security-Policy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
	What's so good about it?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How would you like to be largely&amp;#xA0;&lt;strong&gt;invulnerable to XSS&lt;/strong&gt;? No matter if someone managed to trick your server into writing &amp;lt;script&amp;gt;alert(1);&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;, &lt;strong&gt;have the browser straight up refuse it&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's the promise of Content-Security-Policy.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding the Content-Security-Policy header with the appropriate value allows you to restrict the&amp;#xA0;&lt;strong&gt;origin&lt;/strong&gt; of the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;script-src&lt;/strong&gt;:&amp;#xA0;JavaScript code (biggest reason to use this header)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;connect-src&lt;/strong&gt;:&amp;#xA0;XMLHttpRequest, WebSockets, and EventSource.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;font-src&lt;/strong&gt;:&amp;#xA0;fonts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;frame-src&lt;/strong&gt;:&amp;#xA0;frame ulrs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;img-src&lt;/strong&gt;: images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;media-src&lt;/strong&gt;:&amp;#xA0;audio &amp;amp; video&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;object-src&lt;/strong&gt;:&amp;#xA0;Flash (and other plugins)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;style-src&lt;/strong&gt;:&amp;#xA0;CSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;So specifying the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
Content-Security-Policy: script-src 'self' https://apis.google.com&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Means that script files may only come from the current domain or from apis.google.com (the Google JavaScript CDN).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another helpful feature is that you can automatically enable &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.html5rocks.com/en/tutorials/security/sandboxed-iframes/&quot;&gt;sandbox mode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for all iframes on your site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you want to test the waters, you can use use the '&lt;strong&gt;Content-Security-Policy-Report-Only&lt;/strong&gt;' header to do a dry run of your policy and have the browser post the results to a URL of your choosing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is definitely worth the time to read the&amp;#xA0;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.html5rocks.com/en/tutorials/security/content-security-policy/&quot;&gt;excellent HTML5Rocks introduction&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
	What's the catch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately Internet Explorer (IE) only supports the sandbox mode, and with a 'X-' prefix no less. Also Android support is pretty new (4.4).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course it can't protect against all XSS, if you generate your JavaScript dynamically (a bad idea, but not uncommon in practice) someone may still trick your server into generating bad JS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, including it does no harm and will protect users on Chrome, Firefox and iOS.&lt;br&gt;
	&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
	Where does it work?&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;
	Where do I learn more about it?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.html5rocks.com/en/tutorials/security/content-security-policy/&quot;&gt;HTML5Rocks has an awesome introduction&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#xA0;Other than that, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.w3.org/TR/CSP/&quot;&gt;W3C spec&lt;/a&gt; is quite readable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;
	2. X-Frame-Options&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
	What's so good about it?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stop Clickjacking with one simple header:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
X-Frame-Options: DENY&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This will cause browsers to refuse requests for framing in that page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supplying the value '&lt;strong&gt;SAMEORIGIN&lt;/strong&gt;' will allow framing only from the same origin and '&lt;strong&gt;ALLOW FROM &lt;a href=&quot;http://url-here.example.com&quot;&gt;http://url-here.example.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;' will allow you to specify an origin (unsupported by IE).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
	What's the catch?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This header will be deprecated and it's functionality will be moved to Content-Security-Policy 1.1 (which does not have the same level of support yet).&lt;br&gt;
	But until that has wider support, there is no reason not to use this header.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
	Where does it work?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;
				IE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;
				Firefox&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;
				Chrome&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;
				iOS Safari&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;
				Android Browser&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;
				8+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
				3.6.9+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
				4.1.249+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
				?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
				?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;(data from &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/HTTP/X-Frame-Options&quot;&gt;Mozilla Developer Network&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
	Where do I learn more about it?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much more to learn, but if you want some more information you can check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/HTTP/X-Frame-Options&quot;&gt;Mozilla Developer Network article on the topic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also&amp;#xA0;Coding Horror has an old (2009) but good article on Clickjacking / framing: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2009/06/we-done-been-framed.html&quot;&gt;We done been framed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;
	3. X-Content-Type-Options&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
	What's so good about it?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Unrestricted_File_Upload&quot;&gt;Letting your users upload files is inherently dangerous&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, serving up files uploaded by users is even more dangerous and difficult to get right. &amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn't made any easier by browsers second-guessing the Content-Type of what you're serving by doing &lt;a href=&quot;http://mimesniff.spec.whatwg.org/#introduction&quot;&gt;Mime Sniffing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The X-Content-Type-Options allows you to, in effect, say to browsers that yes, you know what you're doing, the Content-Type is correct with it's only allowed value:&amp;#xA0;'&lt;strong&gt;nosniff&lt;/strong&gt;'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/blog/1482-heads-up-nosniff-header-support-coming-to-chrome-and-firefox&quot;&gt;GitHub uses it&lt;/a&gt;, you can too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
	What's the catch?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only works for IE and Chrome, though depending on your audience that could be 65% of your visitors that you're protecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
	Where does it work?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;
				IE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;
				Firefox&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;
				Chrome&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;
				iOS Safari&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;
				Android Browser&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;
				8+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
				- (&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=471020&quot;&gt;bug 471020&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
				1+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
				-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
				-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
	Where do I learn more about it?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FOX IT has an excellent article on MIME sniffing:&amp;#xA0;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.fox-it.com/2012/05/08/mime-sniffing-feature-or-vulnerability/&quot;&gt;MIME Sniffing: feature or vulnerability?&lt;/a&gt; and the IT Security Stackexchange has a dedicated question on this topic:&amp;#xA0;&lt;a href=&quot;http://security.stackexchange.com/questions/12896/does-x-content-type-options-really-prevent-content-sniffing-attacks&quot;&gt;Does X-Content-Type-Options really prevent content sniffing attacks?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;
	4. Strict-Transport-Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
	What's so good about it?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My online banking system uses HTTPS, providing authenticity (that yes, I really am connecting to my bank) and transport security (anybody snooping in would only see the encrypted traffic).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there is a problem with it...&lt;br&gt;
	When I type &quot;onlinebanking.example.com&quot; into the address bar of my browser, &lt;strong&gt;it will connect to plain old HTTP by default&lt;/strong&gt;. It's only if the server then redirects the user to HTTPS (which is a&amp;#xA0;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/4365294/is-redirecting-http-to-https-a-bad-idea&quot;&gt;bad idea in theory, but a good one in practice&lt;/a&gt;) that I get my secure connection. Unfortunately &lt;strong&gt;this redirecting gives an attacker a window to play man-in-the-middle&lt;/strong&gt;. To solve this the Strict-Transport-Security header was added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The HTTP Strict-Transport-Security (HSTS) header instructs the browser to (for a given time)&amp;#xA0;&lt;strong&gt;only use https&lt;/strong&gt;. If for instance, you go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://hsts.example.com&quot;&gt;https://hsts.example.com&lt;/a&gt; and (among others) it returns the following header:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
Strict-Transport-Security: max-age=31536000; includeSubDomains&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then even typing in &lt;strong&gt;http&lt;/strong&gt;://hsts.example.com will make the browser connect to &lt;strong&gt;https&lt;/strong&gt;://hsts.example.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will do this for as long as the HSTS header is valid, which in the case of the example is 1 year&amp;#xA0;&lt;strong&gt;since the last response that sent the HSTS header&lt;/strong&gt;. So if I visit the site once on January 1st 2013, it will be valid until January 1st 2014. But if I visit again on December 31st 2013 it will not only still be valid, it will reset the validity to be valid until December 31st 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
	&lt;span&gt;What's the catch?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It only works on Chrome and Firefox for now. Your Internet Explorer users are still vulnerable. Never the less, it's worth implementing as &lt;strong&gt;it's an official IETF standard&lt;/strong&gt; and the next IE should implement it real soon now...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also &lt;strong&gt;you don't want to implement this unless you're using HTTPS&lt;/strong&gt;, but why wouldn't you be using HTTPS? Remember that HTTPS not only guarantees that your content (and the users content) will be encrypted and therefore uninterceptable, it also provides authenticity. Promising your users that yes, this content really came from you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why you should always use HTTPS is &lt;a href=&quot;http://mashable.com/2011/05/31/https-web-security/&quot;&gt;a different discussion&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#xA0;and as evindenced by the fact that both that blog post and this one are not on HTTPS, still an uphill battle. But &lt;strong&gt;if you're using HTTPS you should probably use HSTS too&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
	Where does it work?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
	Where do I learn more about it?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mozilla Developer Network has a good article on it:&amp;#xA0;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Security/HTTP_Strict_Transport_Security&quot;&gt;HTTP Strict Transport Security&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;
	If you're doing Symfony2 or Drupal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For &lt;strong&gt;Symfony2&lt;/strong&gt; take a look at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nelmio/NelmioSecurityBundle/blob/master/README.md&quot;&gt;NelmioSecurityBundle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#xA0;and for &lt;strong&gt;Drupal&lt;/strong&gt; check out the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://drupal.org/project/seckit&quot;&gt;Security Kit module&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#xA0;which allow you to specify all the aforementioned headers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;
	Hall of Shame: X-Requested-With&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default jQuery sends the X-Requested-With header. It was thought that the mere presence of this header could be used as a way to defeat Cross-Site Request Forgery. Surely no request with this header and a users session could be initiated by a third party as in a browser only XMLHttpRequest is allowed to set custom headers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately as &lt;a href=&quot;http://jasoncodes.com/posts/rails-csrf-vulnerability&quot;&gt;the Ruby On Rails Ruby framework&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.djangoproject.com/weblog/2011/feb/08/security/&quot;&gt;the Django Python framework&lt;/a&gt; soon found out, &lt;strong&gt;while this is a good measure for defence in depth, it can not be fully relied on in the face of other third party plugins like Java or Adobe Flash&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Using the HTTP headers discussed above allows you to &lt;strong&gt;quickly and easily protect your users from XSS, Clickjacking, Mime sniffing vulnerabilities and Man-In-The-Middle attacks&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you aren't using these headers yet, now might be a good time to introduce them to your application or webserver configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep your users safe out there.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    

	&lt;/div&gt;
	
	
	
			
	&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<title>
4 HTTP Security headers you should always be using
</title>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
